< E13 C6 K6 S8 >

1 Thou art love and Thou art light, Lord,

In the Son as life Thou art;

Love expressing, light illum'ning,

Thou dost life to us impart.

Thou art love! Thou art light!

In the Son as life Thou art;

Love expressing, light illum'ning

Thou dost life to us impart.

2 Love bespeaks Thy very being,

What Thou dost is shown by light;

Love is inward, light is outward,

Love accompanies the light.

3 Love by grace is manifested,

And the light by truth is shown;

By Thy love we may enjoy Thee;

By Thy light Thou, Lord, art known.

4 Thru Thy love, which led to Calvary,

We receive the life of God;

Light our understanding opens,

That we may apply the blood.

5 Thru Thy love, as life Thou enter'st

Fellowship with Thee to give;

Thru Thy light we take Thy cleansing

And in fellowship may live.

6 By the light and blood which cleanses,

The anointing we shall know;

Then the life of love Thine essence,

More and more in us will flow.

7 By Thy love we are Thy children,

Abba Father calling Thee;

Light disperses all our darkness,

Till, like Him, Thy Son, we see.

O what grace! O what truth!

Love is seen and light is shown!

We would praise Thee never ceasing,

Thou by love and light art known!

< E15 C10 K10 S9 >

1 O God, Thou art transcendent,

The Holy One Thou art!

None other is Thine equal,

Incomp'rable Thou art!

The holiest of the holy

The universe may call!

Thy power and Thy nature

Do far exceed it all!

2 Distinct, unique, and holy,

Not only right and pure;

Not only without defect,

But with perfection more;

For nothing can approach Thee,

Nor e'er Thine equal be;

If aught Thy place hath taken,

'Tis insult unto Thee.

3 The excellent excelling,

The fairest of the fair,

Yet differing from the finest,

For none with Thee compare.

From all the righteous different,

For Thine is absolute;

None beauteous with Thee vying,

For Thine excels repute.

4 Thy holiness transcendent

Thou hast for us prepared,

And this distinctive nature

We have already shared.

We share in Thy transcendence,

Since we Thy nature own;

Thy holy life we follow

Till unto fulness grown.

5 We give Thee praise and worship

For all Thy holiness,

For Thy transcendent nature,

Thine utter peerlessness.

We praise Thee that Thy nature -

Unique, distinct - we share;

This separating nature

Is ours now and fore'er.

< E20 C18 K18 S13 >

1 God our Father, we adore Thee,

For the sake of righteousness;

Thou in Christ hast justified us,

Who our conscience can depress?

Thou art righteous, and art faithful,

On Thy righteousness we stand;

No unrighteousness is in Thee,

None can turn Thy righteous hand.

2 Thou hast laid our sins on Jesus,

By Thy justice He was killed;

All Thy holy law's requirements

For Thy justice He fulfilled.

Recompense from Him receiving,

Thou art fully satisfied;

How couldst Thou, O God most righteous,

Claim it once more from our side?

3 Father God, Thou hast accepted

Jesus as our Substitute;

Judged the Just One for the unjust,

Couldst Thou change Thy attitude?

As a proof of perfect justice,

At Thine own right hand He sits;

He, as Thy full satisfaction,

Righteously Thy need befits.

4 Father, through the blood of Jesus

We possess Thy righteousness;

By Thy righteousness protected,

None can shake our steadfastness.

Righteousness of Thine Thou mad'st us,

None can ever us condemn;

We'll forever testify this

In the new Jerusalem.

< E21 C16 K16 S14 >

1 We praise Thee for Thy righteousness;

Thy justice, Father, we confess,

And fully testify.

Thou art the judge of all mankind,

In Thee injustice none can find,

Nor wrong to Thee apply.

2 O holy Father, righteous One,

Thy righteousness upholds Thy throne,

'Tis a foundation sure.

'Tis through this righteousness of Thine

That reigns in Christ the grace divine,

And peace we thus secure.

3 Thy righteousness has caused Thy Son

To die for us that we be won,

Redemption thus was bought;

Thy righteousness has justified

When Christ's redemption was applied,

Salvation thus was wrought.

4 That Thou might show Thy righteousness,

With Thy forgiveness Thou didst bless

Men in the ancient age;

For Thee Thy righteousness to show,

Remission Thou dost now bestow

On sinners in this age.

5 All people Thou wilt judge one day,

Thy righteousness to all display

By Christ, Thy Son, our Lord;

Yet fast we'll stand, for none can move,

Thy righteousness we'll ever prove,

With grace Thou wilt afford.

6 With justice is Thy kingdom filled,

And peace upon it Thou dost build

With all in harmony;

In the new heaven and new earth

Thy righteousness will be their worth,

As promised, God, by Thee.

< E26 C22 K22 S18 >

1 God, we praise Thee for Thy mercy,

'Tis so great and so profound!

In our weakness and our failures;

With its greatness it abounds.

We adore Thee! We adore Thee!

With such mercy we've been crowned!

2 How we marvel at this mercy

So far-reaching and so vast!

It has reached us, e'en the sinners,

And will ever hold us fast.

From this mercy, from this mercy,

What can cause us to be cast?

3 For Thy mercy we are grateful,

'Tis so rich, so plenteous!

Thru Thy mercy in redemption,

Thou hast richly favored us.

If without this, if without this,

How could we be favored thus?

4 Oh, Thy mercy, so inspiring!

Gentle, tender, dear and sweet!

With Thy patience and Thy kindness,

Us in all our need it meets.

It we treasure, it we treasure,

Nothing can with it compete.

5 Father, we enjoy Thy mercy,

Ever fresh and ever new;

Every morning shed upon us,

It refreshes as the dew.

How we taste it! How we taste it!

Giving Thee the praises due.

6 We can never cease to praise Thee,

As Thy mercy e'er endures;

All Thy grace and all Thy favor,

Ever for us it secures.

Trusting in it, trusting in it,

Thy sure mercy us assures.

< E32 C30 K30 S22 >

1 We bow and worship, Father, here

And marvel at Thy wondrous love.

O what is man that Thou shouldst deign

To him such boundless grace to prove!

2 We praise Thee for Thy heart's intent

That man Thy likeness should Possess,

That with Thy life and nature filled

Thine image he should manifest.

3 Man in Thine image Thou didst make,

To him authority didst give;

Thyself presenting as his life,

That by Thy riches he might live.

4 To enter man Thou dost desire,

With him to mingle thru Thy grace,

That man may be transformed and built

To be Thy worthy dwelling place.

5 Tho' man did fall, Thou didst not leave

Thy heart's intent, but Thou didst move;

Redeeming man to bring him back,

Thou didst Thy love and wisdom prove.

6 In Christ Thou didst Thyself reveal,

Who died and rose, redemption wrought;

In Spirit Thou hast entered man

And to him life and grace hast brought.

7 My spirit is Thy holiest place,

Thy throne of grace is founded there;

Thou wouldst that we in spirit come

To burn the incense thru our prayer.

8 Such grace is like a river full

Which from the throne of grace doth come;

It floweth thru, transforming us,

And builds us up to be Thy home.

9 Receiving of Thy matchless grace,

We marvel at Thy gift so free;

With grateful hearts for Thy great love,

In spirit now we worship Thee.

< E45 C38 K38 S- >

1 Abba, Father! We adore Thee,

Humbly now our homage pay;

'Tis Thy children's bliss to know Thee,

None but children "Abba" say.

This high honor we inherit,

Thy free gift through Jesus' blood;

God the Spirit, with our spirit,

Witnesseth we're sons of God.

2 Thine own purpose gave us being'

When in Christ, in that vast plan,

Thou in Christ didst choose Thy people

E'en before the world began.

Oh, what love Thou, Father, bore us!

Oh, how precious in Thy sight!

When to Thine own Son Thou gav'st us,

To Thy Son, Thy soul's delight.

3 Though our nature's fall in Adam

Shut us wholly out from God,

Thine eternal counsel brought us

Nearer still, through Jesus' blood;

For in Him we found redemption,

Grace and glory in Thy Son;

O the height and depth of mercy!

Christ and His redeemed are one.

4 Hence, through all the changing seasons,

Trouble, sickness, sorrow, woe,

Nothing changeth Thine affections,

Love divine shall bring us through;

Soon shall all Thy blood-bought children

Round the throne their anthems raise,

And, in songs of rich salvation,

Shout to Thine eternal praise.

< E62 C56 K56 S36 >

1 Dear Lord Jesus, we adore Thee,

"Seed of woman" Thou became;

Of the virgin wast begotten,

Called e'en with a human name.

Taking thus the human nature,

Thou as man the serpent trod;

By the Cross his head Thou bruised

And fulfilled the plan of God.

Lord, we see Thy glory,

Shown in human beauty,

Full of splendor, manifested

In humanity.

2 As a man, by incarnation,

Flesh and blood didst Thou partake

To destroy the devil, Satan,

In our stead and for our sake.

With the name of Jesus given

And Emmanuel called too,

Thou becam'st our precious Savior,

Bringing us salvation true.

3 Thou, "Last Adam" wast entitled,

And wast called the "second man",

Head of all the new creation,

Better than the first man.

On this earth in life and conduct

Thou indeed wast Son of man;

Now in heaven with this nature

Thou dost still appear as man.

4 In the time which God appointed

Thou wilt come, dear Lord, again,

With the glory of the Father,

Still appearing as a man.

Even on the throne of judgment

Son of man Thou still wilt be;

And with this, our human nature,

Thou forevermore wilt be.

< E78 C61 K61 S43 >

1 Gracious Lord, Thy name "I AM" is,

Precious name, how rich and full 'tis,

All-inclusive, faithful too 'tis -

All, we need, Thou art!

2 Thou the Son, the Father in Thee,

As the Spirit now indwell me,

That the riches of Thyself we

May experience.

3 Thou the Temple for God's dwelling,

Thou the Father's life e'er telling;

We in Thee with joy excelling

Face to face see Him.

4 Thou the Lamb and Thou the Bridegroom,

For the bride Thou sufferedst sin's doom,

Wounded, crucified in our room;

Thus we find our rest.

5 Thou art wisdom and the way, Lord,

Thou our lives dost plan each day, Lord,

Grace to us Thou dost convey, Lord,

In Thy path to walk.

6 Pure and holy, righteous Thou art,

One with God, well-pleasing His heart,

Thou within to us dost impart

Harmony with God.

7 Thou art life and Thou art light, Lord,

Death hast swallowed, banished night, Lord,

Thou hast quickened, given sight, Lord;

We are now set free.

8 Thou art resurrection power,

Thou the conqu'ror in hell's hour;

Thou dost us with might empower

Over all to reign.

9 Living water, food supply, Lord,

Thou Thyself art, and didst die, Lord,

All our want to satisfy, Lord;

Now we feast on Thee.

10 Thou the Shepherd and Physician,

Thou hast healed our sick condition;

Comfort, guide, protect - Thy mission;

Thou dost care for us.

11 Priest and King Thou art fore'er, Lord;

Into God we're brought, and there, Lord,

Thine authority we share, Lord;

What an honored place!

12 Thou our Hope and our Redemption,

Thou wilt change our old creation,

Make of Thee a duplication,

Thus Thyself express.

13 Thou our Joy, our Peace, our Glory;

Truth, and Grace, the Rock, the Life-tree,

Building, Mountain, Sun, and Shield - we

Ne'er can tell it all.

14 What Thou art - eternal, boundless,

Full and perfect, rich, exhaustless -

Meets our need to utter fullness

And from us o'erflows.

< E94 C84 K84 S- >

1 O Christ, what burdens bow'd Thy head!

Our load was laid on Thee;

Thou stoodest in the sinner's stead,

Didst bear all ill for me.

A victim led; Thy blood was shed;

Now there's no load for me.

2 Death and the curse were in our cup,

O Christ, 'twas full for Thee!

But Thou hast drained the last dark drop -

'Tis empty now for me.

That bitter cup - love drank it up;

Now blessings' draught for me.

3 Jehovah lifted up His rod,

O Christ, it fell on Thee!

Thou wast sore stricken of Thy God;

There's not one stroke for me.

Thy tears, Thy blood, beneath it flowed;

Thy bruising healeth me.

4 The tempest's awful voice was heard,

O Christ, it broke on Thee!

Thy open bosom was my ward,

It braved the storm for me.

Thy form was scarred, Thy visage marred;

Now cloudless peace for me.

5 Jehovah bade His sword awake,

O Christ, it woke 'gainst Thee!

Thy blood the flaming blade must slake;

Thy heart its sheath must be -

All for my sake, my peace to make;

Now sleeps that sword for me.

6 For me, Lord Jesus, Thou hast died,

And I have died in Thee;

Thou'rt ris'n: my bands are all untied,

And now Thou liv'st in me.

When purified, made white, and tried,

Thy glory then for me!

< E110 C92 K92 S- >

1 O solemn hour! O hour alone,

In solitary night,

When God the Father's only Son,

As Man, for sinners lost, undone,

Expires - amazing sight!

The Lord of glory crucified!

The Lord of Life has bled and died!

2 O mystery of mysteries!

Of life and death the tree!

Center of two eternities,

Which look with rapt, adoring eyes,

Onward, and back to Thee!

O cross of Christ, where all His pain

And death is our eternal gain.

3 O how our inmost hearts do move,

While gazing on that cross!

The death of the incarnate Love!

What shame, what grief, what joy we prove,

That He should die for us!

Our hearts were broken by that cry,

"Eli, lama sabachthani!"

4 Worthy of death, O Lord, we were;

That vengeance was our due;

In grace Thou, spotless Lamb, didst bear

Thyself our sins, and guilt, and fear;

Justice our Surety slew.

With Thee, our Surety, we have died;

With Thee, we there were crucified.

5 Quickened with Thee with life divine,

Raised with Thee from the dead;

Thine Own, now human and divine,

Shall with Thee in Thy glories shine,

The Church's living Head!

We, who were worthy but to die,

Now with Thee, "Abba Father," cry.

< E114 C- K- S- >

1 Hail, Thou once despised Jesus!

Hail, Thou still rejected King!

Thou didst suffer to release us,

Thou didst free salvation bring;

Through Thy death and resurrection,

Bearer of our sin and shame!

We enjoy divine protection,

Life and glory through Thy name.

2 Paschal Lamb, by God appointed,

All our sins on Thee were laid;

By our Father's love anointed,

Thou redemption's price hast paid.

All who trust Thee are forgiven

Through the virtue of Thy blood;

Opened are the things of heaven,

Grace shines forth to man from God.

3 Savior, hail! Enthroned in glory,

Where for us Thou dost abide;

We, by faith, do now adore Thee,

Seated at Thy Father's side.

There, for us Thou now art pleading,

There Thou dost our sorrows share,

Ever for us interceding,

Till in glory we appear.

4 Worship, honor, praise, and blessing,

Thou art worthy to receive;

Loudest praises, without ceasing,

Meet it is for us to give.

In that day Thy saints will meet Thee,

Welcome Thee with grateful song;

Joyful hearts will ever greet Thee,

Source of joy to all the throng!

< E130 C112 K112 S- >

1 See the Conqu'ror mount in triumph,

See the King in royal state

Riding on the clouds His chariot

To His;heav'nly palace gate;

Hark! The choirs of angel voices

Joyful hallelujahs sing,

And the portals high are lifted

To receive, to receive, to receive their

heav'nly King.

2 Who is this that comes in glory,

With the trump of jubilee?

Lord of battles, God of armies,

He has gained the victory;

He who on the cross did suffer,

He who from the grave arose,

He has vanquished sin and Satan,

He by death, He by death, He by

death has spoiled His foes.

3 While He lifts His hands in blessing

He is parted from His friends;

While their eager eyes behold Him,

He upon the clouds ascends;

He who walked with God and pleased Him,

Preaching truth and doom to come,

He, our Enoch, is translated

To His home, to His home,

to His everlasting home.

4 Now our heavenly Aaron enters,

With His blood, within the veil;

Joshua now is come to Canaan,

And the kings before Him quail;

Now He plants the tribes of Israel

In their promised resting-place;

Now our great Elijah offers

Of His grace, of His grace,

double portion of His grace.

5 He has raised our human nature

On the clouds to God's right hand;

There we sit in heav'nly places,

There with Him in glory stand. Jesus reigns,

adored by angels;

Man with God is on the throne;

Mighty Lord, in Thine ascension

We by faith, we by faith, we by

faith behold our own.

< E142 C- K- S72 >

1 Crown Him with many crowns,

The Lamb upon His throne;

Hark! How the heav'nly anthem drowns

All music but its own!

Awake, my soul, and sing

Of Him who died for thee,

And hail Him as thy matchless King

Through all eternity.

2 Crown Him the Virgin's Son,

The God Incarnate born,

Whose arm those crimson trophies won

Which now His brow adorn:

Fruit of the mystic Tree,

As of that Tree the Stem;

The Root whence flows Thy mercy free,

The Babe of Bethlehem.

3 Crown Him the Lord of Love:

Behold His hands and side;

Rich wounds yet visible above

In beauty glorified:

No angel in the sky

Can fully bear that sight,

But downward bends his burning eye

At mysteries so bright.

4 Crown Him the Lord of peace,

Whose power a scepter sways

From pole to pole, that wars may cease,

And all be prayer and praise.

His reign shall know no end,

And round His pierced feet

Fair flowers of glory now extend

Their fragrance ever sweet.

5 Crown Him the Lord of years,

The Potentate of time,

Creator of the rolling spheres,

Ineffably sublime.

All hail, Redeemer, hail!

For Thou hast died for me;

Thy praise shall never, never fail

Throughout eternity.

< E154 C134 K134 S77 >

1 It passeth knowledge, that dear love of Thine,

My Savior, Jesus; yet this soul of mine

Would of Thy love in all its breadth and length,

Its height and depth, its everlasting strength,

Know more and more.

2 It passeth telling, that dear love of Thine,

My Savior, Jesus; yet these lips of mine

Would fain proclaim to sinners, far and near,

A love which can remove all guilty fear,

And love beget.

3 It passeth praises, that dear love of Thine,

My Savior Jesus; yet this heart of mine

Would sing that love, so full, so rich, so free,

Which brings a rebel sinner, such as me,

Nigh unto God.

4 But though I cannot sing, or tell, to know

The fullness of Thy love, while here below,

My empty vessel I may freely bring;

O Thou, who art of love the living spring,

My vessel fill.

5 I am an empty vessel - not one thought

Or look of love to Thee I've ever brought;

Yet I may come, and come again to Thee,

With this the empty sinner's only plea,

Thou lovest me.

6 Oh, fill me, Jesus, Savior, with Thy love!

Lead, lead me to the living fount above;

Thither may I, in simple faith draw nigh,

And never to another fountain fly,

But unto Thee.

7 Lord Jesus, when Thee face to face I see,

When on Thy lofty throne I sit with Thee,

Then of Thy love, in all its breadth and length,

Its height and depth, its everlasting strength,

My soul shall sing.

< E158 C131 K131 S- >

1 Lord, Thy love has sought and found us

Wand'ring in this desert wide;

Thou hast thrown Thine arms around us,

For us suffered, bled, and died.

Sing, my soul! He loved thee,

Jesus gave Himself for me.

2 Hark! What sounds of bitter weeping

From yon lonesome garden sweep;

'Tis the Lord His vigil keeping,

While His followers sink in sleep.

Ah, my soul, He loved thee,

Yes, He gave Himself for me.

3 He is speaking to His Father,

Tasting deep that bitter cup,

Yet He takes it, willing rather

For our sakes to drink it up.

Oh, what love! He loved me!

Gave Himself, my soul, for thee.

4 Then that closing scene of anguish:

All God's waves and billows roll

Over Him, there left to languish

On the cross, to save my soul.

Matchless love! How vast, how free,

Jesus gave Himself for me.

5 Hark again! His cries are waking

Echoes on dark Calvary's hill;

God, my God, art Thou forsaking

Him who always did Thy will?

Ah, my soul! It was for thee,

Yes! He gave Himself for me.

6 Lord, we joy, Thy toils are ended,

Glad Thy suff'ring time is o'er;

To Thy Father's throne ascended,

There Thou liv'st, to die no more.

Yes, my soul, He lives for thee,

He who gave Himself for me.

7 Lord, we worship and adore Thee

For Thy rich, Thy matchless grace;

Perfect soon in joy before Thee,

We shall see Thee face to face.

Yet e'en now our song shall be,

Jesus gave Himself for me.

< E187 C152 K152 S- >

1 O Lord, how rich Thou art to us,

Thy love reveals the measure!

The boundless riches of Thyself,

In spirit here we treasure.

2 Thou art the Word, e'en God Himself,

With God in the beginning;

Incarnate in the flesh with us,

And God to us defining.

3 Thou art the tabernacle true,

In Thee we see God's glory;

For God Thou art the temple too,

In Thee is God's full story.

4 Thou art the only Son of God,

The Father e'er declaring,

That we may have the life divine,

God's very nature sharing.

5 Thou art the Son of Man like us,

And truly share our nature,

That we may be the sons of God

And grow to Thy full stature.

6 Thou art the Christ, the Lord of all,

By God Thou art anointed;

The One who is the All in all,

For God and us appointed.

7 Thou art the Savior crucified,

Whence issued blood and water,

That we might be redeemed to God,

And life divine may enter.

8 Thou now art Jesus glorified,

From whom descends the Spirit;

The all-inclusive Spirit comes

To us with all Thy merit.

9 Thou art the very light of life

That shineth in the darkness;

The light divine that shines with God

Within our hearts in fulness.

10 Thou art the very life divine,

Which all our spirits quickens;

The life which brings us out of death

And all our being strengthens.

11 Lord, Thou art God's reality,

The truth that meets God's pleasure;

The truth that brings Thyself to us,

That we may know Thy measure.

12 Thou also art the way of life,

Which unto glory leads us;

The way of Thy reality,

Which into vict'ry speeds us.

13 Thou art the resurrection too,

All death Thy life doth swallow;

'Tis by Thy resurrection pow'r,

We bear the cross and follow.

14 Thou art the spotless Lamb of God,

Who died for our redemption;

Thou art the Spirit-giver too,

For our regeneration.

15 Thou art the serpent made of brass,

Who saveth us from evil;

Thou on the tree wast lifted up,

To crush for us the devil.

16 Thou art the Shepherd and the door,

For us to leave the sheepfold,

By Thee we have full liberty

And share the pasture freehold.

17 Thy washing keeps us always clean,

In function like the laver;

Thus we are kept in fellowship,

Partaking of Thy favor.

18 Thou art the heav'nly riven rock,

With living water flowing;

We drink of this refreshing stream,

Thy quenching power knowing.

19 Thou art the heav'nly well, in Thee

Is living water ever;

We drink of Thine eternal life,

And thirst no more forever.

20 Thou art the heav'nly bread of life,

Thy food divine doth flourish;

With all Thy riches bountiful

Our spirits Thou dost nourish.

21 Thou even art our breath of life

Thyself we breathe in spirit,

By Thee we live, in Thee we walk,

Thy riches we inherit.

22 Thou art the grain of wheat divine,

That died and rose with glory,

To bring forth us as many grains

To form Thy glorious Body.

23 Thou art the true and heav'nly vine,

And we in Thee are branches;

In Thee abiding, Thou in us,

We share in all Thy riches.

24 Thou art the Bridegroom from above

To take the Bride, Thy Body;

That we may be with Thee as one,

In life and love and glory.

25 Thou art the ladder Jacob saw,

By Thee the heav'n is open;

In Thee we are the house of God,

And earth is joined to heaven.

26 O Lord, Thou art the great "I AM,"

Who all our need doth furnish;

Enjoying Thee as all in all,

God's purpose we accomplish.

< E188 C164 K164 S86 >

22 Dear Lord, Thou art the Son of God,

His absolute expression;

In Thee God speaks to us today,

Thou art His definition.

The impress of God's substance true,

Effulgence of His glory,

Thou even art our God Himself,

In Thee is His full story.

3 By Thee was made, the universe,

Subsisting by Thy merit;

The heir God hath appointed Thee,

That all Thou may inherit.

4 Since Thou hast purged our sins by death,

In heaven Thou art seated,

Till all Thy foes will be subdued

And all God's will completed.

5 A better name than angels have,

From God Thou didst inherit;

As Son of God to us as life,

Thou now art in the Spirit.

6 Thy kingdom is of righteousness,

Thy throne will stand forever;

God hath in love anointed Thee,

And Thou shalt wax old never.

Thou also art a man indeed,

With all our human nature;

By grace Thou tastedst death for us

That we may have Thy stature.

8 With glory and with honor crowned,

All things to Thee are subject,

As Captain of salvation, full,

Thou art thru sufferings perfect.

By death the devil Thou hast spoiled,

And from death's bondage freed us;

Thou sanctifiest us in life

And dost to glory speed us.

10 To us, Thy brethren, Thou art here,

The Father's Name declaring;

Within the Church Thou singest hymns,

God's praises with us sharing.

Superior Thou to Moses, Lord,

As to the house the builder;

Thou, our Apostle sent from God,

Art worthy of more splendor.

12 Thou art our real Joshua,

By Thee the rest we enter;

Our full salvation is of Thee,

Our faith on Thee doth center.

13 Thou art the heav'nly rest -to us,

Now dwelling in our spirit,

For us to enter as the land

And all Thy good inherit.

Superior Thou to Aaron too -

Thyself, the offering given,

Thou enteredst, as our Great High Priest,

The holiest place in heaven.

15 Thou art our true Melchisedec,

With endless life in power,

To minister the "bread and wine,"

In every needful hour.

16 Thou art the better sacrifice,

Thru the eternal Spirit,

Once offered unto God for us,

That we may gain Thy merit.

A better covenant was made

With Thy dear blood in heaven;

By Thee this sure new testament

To Thy redeemed was given.

18 Thou, art its Maker adequate,

For Thou dost have the merit;

Thou art its Giver competent

That we may all inherit;

19 Its qualified Executor,

By life of resurrection;

Its potent Mediator too,

Fulfilling God's election.

20 Lord, Thou art now within the veil,

As our unique Forerunner,

That by Thy life, without the camp,

We'll in the race be runners.

Thou art the Finisher of faith,

As well its Author perfect;

By faith and love we follow Thee,

And e'er to Thee are subject.

Unequaled is Thy worth, dear Lord,

And all Thou art we treasure;

Thou art so perfect and complete,

Beyond all human measure.

< E189 C163 K163 S87 >

1 Thou art the Son beloved,

The image of our God;

Thou art the saints' dear portion,

Imparted thru Thy blood.

Among all God's creation

Thou art the firstborn One;

By Thee all was created,

All for Thyself to own.

2 Thou art before all creatures,

In Thee all things consist;

Of all Thou art the center,

By Thee all things subsist.

Thou art the sole beginning,

The Firstborn from the dead;

And for the Church, Thy Body,

Thou art the glorious Head.

3 Because it pleased the Father,

All fulness dwells in Thee,

That Thou might have the first place

In all we ever see.

All things Thou reconciledst

To God by Thy shed blood,

To thus present us holy

And blameless unto God.

4 In Thee God's fulness dwelleth,

Thou art God's mystery;

The treasures of all wisdom

And knowledge are in Thee.

Thou art the hope of glory,

In us Thou dost abide;

In Thee we are perfected

And God is satisfied.

5 All things are but a shadow

Which unto us reveal

Thyself, in whom we're rooted,

The only One that's real.

Enjoying all Thy riches,

Thy fulness we will be;

We'll hold Thee, as Thy Body,

And grow with God in Thee.

6 With Thee in God we're hidden,

Thou art in us our life;

Thy peace in us presiding,

We rest from all our strife.

In the new man, Thy Body,

Thou art the all in all;

Our all-inclusive Savior,

Thyself we'll ever call.

< E193 C161 K161 S- >

1 Dear Lord, Thou art so much to us

Thou art our all in all;

What Thou art fully meets our needs,

Though they be great or small.

Our hearts appreciate what Thou art,

Our spirits worship Thee;

Our grateful praise to Thee we give

As we Thy riches see.

2 Thou art the Prophet raised by God,

With pow'r for God to speak;

Like Moses, Thou God's plan hast shown,

That we God's will may seek.

Thou art like Jonah sent by God,

To enter death and live,

That by this sign of death and life,

We may in Thee believe.

3 Thou art the Prophet raised from men,

To speak with pow'r and light;

Thou, like Elisha, filled with love,

Thy miracles in might.

Thou, like Isaiah, full of grace,

God's Christ dost e'er reveal,

That we may share this Christ of all

As life both rich and real.

4 Thou art the Priest from us to God,

The holy Priest for us,

Like Aaron called of God from men,

For us Thou servest thus.

In love Thou bearest us to God,

The great High Priest to serve;

With love Thou intercedest there

And dost with strength preserve.

5 Thou art the Priest from God to us,

The royal Priest of God;

Like Salem's King, Melchisedec,

The minister of God.

With bread and wine Thou cam'st from God

To us in time of need;

Thou cam'st with God that we in Him

Might fully share indeed.

6 Thou art the King as David was,

And God's desire dost seek;

The battle fought, the foe subdued,

God's heart Thou dost bespeak.

Thou art empowered on the throne,

Not with a human rod,

But with authority divine

To reign for us and God.

7 Thou art the King like Solomon,

Whose rule with peace was filled;

With wisdom Thou dost reign in pow'r

And Thou God's house dost build.

As King unseen Thou reignest now

Among Thy saints with love;

One day, when Thou shalt reign with us,

Thou wilt Thy kingship prove.

8 As King and Priest and Prophet too,

How precious, Lord, art Thou;

Thy worth to God, Thy worth to us,

We all with love avow.

O how we treasure what Thou art,

Our hearts are drawn by Thee;

To Thee we'll give our thanks and praise

Throughout eternity.

< E194 C160 K160 S- >

1 Thou art God's testimony, Lord,

Much better than the law;

The law in letter was engraved,

In it Thy type men saw.

A definition was the law,

God's picture to provide;

But Thou art God's reality,

In Thee doth God abide.

2 The ark of testimony too

Was but a type of Thee;

In it the law of God was placed,

But God in Thee we see.

The ark, in type, was made of wood

And. overlaid with gold;

It typifies Thee as a man,

Who God in full doth hold.

3 Thou art the tabernacle too,

God's holy dwelling place;

Incarnate in the flesh Thou art,

And full of truth and grace.

God's glory we behold in Thee,

Thou art the Word divine;

Thy words and deeds of love and light

Do God in life define.

4 The temple was a type of Thee;

The house of God Thou art;

God dwells in Thee, Himself to show,

His fulness to impart.

Though Thou by Satan wast destroyed

And numbered with the dead,

In resurrection Thou dost build

A larger one instead.

5 The city shows Thy fulness true,

A figure of Thy Bride,

The increase of Thyself in full,

In whom Thou dost abide.

In Thee is God, the light divine,

The lamp in her art Thou;

With Thee God shines thru her on all,

His glory to avow.

6 The tabernacle and the ark,

The law within them stored,

The temple and the city too,

Are all Thyself, dear Lord.

Thou art the hub, Thou art the rim,

The all in all Thou art!

In Thee we see both God and man,

How precious to our heart!

< E195 C165 K165 S89 >

1 Lord, Thou art all the offerings

Prepared by God for us;

They are so rich in meaning,

So sweet and glorious.

They have fulfilled God's purpose

And met His heart's desire;

They too have satisfied us,

And faced what we require.

2 Thou art the burnt-oblation,

Consumed by holy fire;

To God as a sweet savor,

Fulfilling His desire.

Thou walkedst in God's presence,

And all His will pursued;

Thyself the spotless offering,

For us to God as food.

3 Thou art the meal-oblation,

With "oil" and "frankincense";

'Tis holy, fine, and perfect,

And sweet to every sense.'

Thou art the peace-oblation,

The peace for us to make,

That we with God may share Thee,

As food of Thee partake.

4 Thou art the sin-oblation,

For us Thou sin wast made;

By death for our redemption

The ransom Thou hast paid.

Thou art the trespass-offering,

Thou all our sins didst bear

To satisfy God's justice,

That we His pardon share.

5 Thou art the wave-oblation,

The resurrected One;

O'er Hades, death and darkness,

The vict'ry Thou hast won.

Thou art the heave-oblation,

Thou didst ascend to God;

As such in heav'nly places

Thou art our holy food.

< E196 C155 K155 S- >

1 Lord, the ancient types and symbols

As our all Thyself portrayed;

As was shadowed in those figures,

Real to us Thou now art made.

Contemplating such a picture,

As we on its wonders gaze,

How we marvel at Thy riches

And our song of worship raise.

2 Lord, Thou art our true Passover,

God passed over us thru Thee;

By Thyself and Thy redemption

We with God have harmony.

Thou, the Lamb of God, redeemedst us

With Thyself and with Thy blood;

We apply Thy blood, our ransom,

Eating Thee, our real food.

3 Lord, Thou art the Bread from heaven,

The unleavened Bread of life;

Eating Thee, with Thee we mingle,

Ceasing from our sin and strife.

Lamb and Bread are both Thy figures,

Showing Thou art life to us;

Feasting on Thee at Thy table,

We enjoy Thy riches thus.

4 Lord, Thou art the Heav'nly Manna,

As our daily food supply;

Strengthening and energizing,

All our need to satisfy.

Living Rock Thou also art, Lord,

Cleft for us with life to flow;

Drinking of this living water,

Thirst is quenched, Thy life we know.

5 Lord, Thou art the Land of Canaan -

Elevated, rich and good,

Flowing with both milk and honey

In a glorious plenitude.

By Thy surplus God we worship,

In Thy fellowship we move;

Thus in love we're joined together

And God's building we will prove.

< E199 C151 K151 S- >

1 Thou art the Rock everlasting,

Spiritual Rock cleft for me;

Drinking of Thee as the Spirit,

Thus I become one with Thee.

Thou art the Rock never shaken,

'Tis on this Rock we are built;

Joined unto Thee thru redemption,

Nothing can shake us thru guilt.

Lord, how we treasure Thy value,

All that Thou art is for us;

While here in loving remembrance

We share Thy wealth glorious.

2 Thou art the Stone tried by many,

Precious to God, dear to us,

Thou art so sure and trustworthy,

Thy strength is so marvelous.

Thou art the Stone that is living,

Chosen of God, made our own;

So energetic and pow'rful,

With endless life to us known.

3 Thou art the Stone of Foundation

Laid by our God, safe and sure;

It is by this sure foundation

Safety fore'er we secure.

To us no other foundation

Of any kind man can lay;

Thou art the only foundation

Which we have now and for aye.

4 Lord, for God's spiritual building,

Thou art the Chief Cornerstone;

Both of the Jews and the Gentiles

By Thee are built into one.

Lord, Thou art also the Topstone,

Brought forth in measureless grace;

Thou art our cover and glory,

Moving our hearts in Thy praise.

< E203 C154 K154 S93 >

1 In the bosom of the Father,

Ere the ages had begun,

Thou wast in the Father's glory,

God's unique begotten Son.

When to us the Father gave Thee,

Thou in person wast the same,

All the fulness of the Father

In the Spirit to proclaim.

2 By Thy death and resurrection,

Thou wast made God's firstborn Son;

By Thy life to us imparting,

Was Thy duplication done.

We, in Thee regenerated,

Many sons to God became;

Truly as Thy many brethren,

We are as Thyself the same.

3 Once Thou wast the only grain, Lord,

Falling to the earth to die,

That thru death and resurrection

Thou in life may multiply.

We were brought forth in Thy nature

And the many grains became;

As one loaf we all are blended,

All Thy fulness to proclaim.

4 We're Thy total reproduction,

Thy dear Body and Thy Bride,

Thine expression and Thy fulness,

For Thee ever to abide.

We are Thy continuation,

Thy life-increase and Thy spread,

Thy full growth and Thy rich surplus,

One with Thee, our glorious Head.

+ Lord Thy human shell was broken.

Life and glory Thou released

That thine own incorporation

With thy chosen be increased.

We with Thee incorporated:

Thou in us and we in Thee.

Here we eat the hidden manna,

New Jerusalem to be.

< E221 C178 K178 S97 >

1 Lord, we thank Thee for the table,

With the bread and with the wine;

At this table we enjoy Thee

As the feast of love divine.

We partake the bread, the emblem

Of Thy body giv'n for us;

And we share the wine, the symbol

Of Thy blood Thou shedd'st for us.

Lo, the holy table!

With the sacred symbols;

Its significance in figure

Is unsearchable!

2 By the death of Thy redemption,

That Thy life Thou may impart,

E'en Thyself to us Thou gavest

That we share in all Thou art.

By the bread and wine partaking,

We Thy death display and prove;

Eating, drinking of Thyself, Lord,

We remember Thee with love.

3 By this bread which signifieth

Thy one body mystical,

We commune with all Thy members

In one bond identical.

By this holy cup of blessing,

Cup of wine which now we bless,

Of Thy blood we have communion

With all those who faith possess.

4 Thou art our eternal portion,

Here we take a sweet foretaste;

We are waiting for Thy kingdom,

And Thy coming now we haste.

At Thy coming, in Thy kingdom,

With all saints that overcome,

We anew will feast upon Thee

And Thy loving Bride become.

< E224 C175 K175 S100 >

1 As we're sharing of the cup,

How can we restrain our praise;

For the blood Thou shedd'st for us,

Worth of which none can appraise.

O how precious is Thy blood!

All our problems it resolves;

In Thine efficacious blood

All our care and fear dissolves.

2 It is by this blood of worth

The new testament was made;

For this better covenant,

'Tis a sure foundation laid.

We have been redeemed by God,

Not with silver or with gold,

But, Lord, with Thy precious blood,

Which Thy love doth e'er unfold.

3 For remission of our sins

Thou hast shed Thy cleansing blood,

Which for us has fully met

All the righteous claims of God.

Thou hast washed us from our sins

In Thy pow'rful purging blood;

And our conscience purged by it,

Thus to serve the living God.

4 By Thy separating blood,

We have all been sanctified;

'Tis by Thy preserving blood

Holiness is testified.

By Thy propitiating blood,

We have all been justified;

'Tis by Thy redeeming blood

God is fully satisfied.

5 Thru Thy blood shed on the cross,

We are reconciled to God,

That the way to contact Him

May in peace by us be trod.

By partaking of Thy blood,

We have Thine eternal life;

In Thy blood and life received,

We have rest, free from all strife.

6 Now, in heav'n Thy sprinkled blood

Speaks for us of better things;

Under its defending pow'r

We are kept from Satan's stings.

By Thine overcoming blood,

We defeat the enemy;

Over our accuser thus,

We will have the victory.

7 Of Thy blood, for fellowship,

We commune with all the saints;

Under its full covering,

Our freed spirit never faints.

How can we exhaust, in words,

The account of Thy dear blood;

We will need eternity

To declare its boundless good.

< E227 C181 K181 S102 >

1 Through the bread and cup, Lord Jesus,

We Thy death exhibit here;

What Thy love has done reviewing,

All Thy suff'ring we revere.

Bread and cup in separation,

Show that Thou thru death hast gone;

Grateful now, our spirit worships,

And to Thee we give our song.

Thine the cup of suff'ring,

Mine the cup of blessing;

For Thy love in Thy redemption,

Praise we ever sing!

2 Thou, in love, hast shed Thy blood, Lord,

Bringing us to God in grace,

That from God, no longer severed,

We may ever see His face.

All God's righteousness and glory

Have been fully satisfied;

Thru Thy death's abundant merit

We may now with God abide.

3 By Thy death the veil was riven,

Opened was the holiest place,

All the barriers have been broken;

We approach the throne of grace,

There receiving grace and mercy,

Thus the timely need to meet,

Drinking as of living water,

Tasting God Himself replete.

4 Thou in grace hast so redeemed us,

We the priests may be fore'er

To fulfill that holy office,

All God's sweetness thus to share.

Such a blessing, such a mercy,

From Thy death for us ensue;

We would ever Thee remember

Till with Thee we drink anew.

< E235 C190 K190 S- >

1 Praise Him! praise Him! Jesus, our blessed Redeemer!

Sing, ye saints! His wonderful love proclaim!

Hail Him! hail Him! mightiest angels in glory;

Strength and honor give to His holy name!

Like a shepherd, Jesus will feed His people,

In His arms He carries them all day long;

O ye saints that live in the light of His presence,

Praise Him! praise Him! ever in joyful song!

2 Praise Him! praise Him! Jesus, our blessed Redeemer!

For our sins He suffered and bled and died;

He, our Rock, our Hope of eternal salvation,

Hail Him! hail Him! Jesus, the Crucified;

Loving Savior, meekly enduring sorrow,

Crowned with thorns that cruelly pierced His brow;

Once for us rejected, despised, and forsaken,

Prince of Glory, ever triumphant now.

3 Praise Him! praise Him! Jesus, our blessed Redeemer!

Heavenly portals, loud with hosannahs ring!

Jesus, Savior, reigneth for ever and ever;

Crown Him! crown Him! Prophet and Priest and King!

Death is vanquished! Tell it with joy, ye faithful,

Where is now thy victory, boasting grave?

Jesus lives! No longer thy portals are cheerless;

Jesus lives, the mighty and strong to save.

< E236 C- K- S- >

1 Lamb of God! our souls adore Thee,

While upon Thy face we gaze;

There the Father's love and glory

Shine in all their brightest rays;

Thine Almighty pow'r and wisdom

All creation's works proclaim;

Heav'n and earth alike confess Thee

As the ever great "I AM."

2 Lamb of God! Thy Father's bosom

Ever was Thy dwelling place;

His delight, in Him rejoicing,

One with Him in pow'r and grace;

O what wondrous love and mercy!

Thou didst lay Thy glory by;

And for us didst come from heaven

As the Lamb of God to die.

3 Lamb of God! When we behold Thee

Lowly in the manger laid,

Wand'ring as a homeless stranger

In the world Thy hands had made;

When we see Thee in the garden

In Thine agony of blood,

At Thy grace we are confounded,

Holy, spotless Lamb of God!

4 When we see Thee, as the victim,

Bound to the accursed tree,

For our guilt and folly stricken,

All our judgment borne by Thee,

Lord, we own, with hearts adoring,

Thou hast loved us unto blood;

Glory, glory everlasting

Be to Thee, Thou Lamb of God.

5 Lamb of God, Thou soon in glory

Wilt to this sad earth return;

All Thy foes shall quake before Thee,

All that now despise Thee mourn;

Then Thy saints all gathered to Thee,

With Thee in Thy kingdom reign;

Thine the praise and Thine the glory,

Lamb of God, for sinners slain!

< E244 C200 K200 S114 >

1 The Holy Spirit is today

The Spirit of the life divine,

He quickens us and gives us life,

And makes us fit for God's design.

2 As living water quenching thirst

The stream of life He e'er supplies;

Imparting Christ as life divine,

My hungry heart He satisfies.

3 Enlight'ning with the light of life,

He chases darkness far away;

Imparting Christ as light divine,

He turns for us the night to day.

4 He strengthens with the pow'r of life

To energize our inner man;

Imparting Christ as strength divine,

He moves within us for God's plan.

5 By law of life He liberates,

And frees us from the law of sin;

And with the nature all divine

He regulates us from within.

6 As Spirit of the life divine,

Thru us abundant fruit He bears;

Expressing God-like attributes,

To others Christ in life He shares.

7 The Spirit ever giving life

Transforms me thus with life divine;

Renewing all my inward parts,

In life He makes Christ's image mine.

8 Oh, by Thy Spirit, fill me, Lord,

The Spirit of Thy life divine,

And saturate me thoroughly

Till all my life is filled with Thine.

< E249 C- K- S- >

1 Flow through me, Lord, a weak and earthly vessel,

Cleansed by Thy blood, and quickened at Thy call.

Flow through me, Lord, all utterly abandoned,

To Thy dear service, great, or high, or small.

2 Flow through me, Lord, with overflowing fulness,

Make me to know Thine own deep love for souls.

Work in me, Lord, the faith that moveth mountains,

As power, Almighty power, my being holds.

3 Flow through me, Lord, till sin in all its blackness

To captives bound by Satan is revealed.

Flow through me, Lord, till hearts are stricken, broken,

And in Thy cleansing fountain saved and healed.

4 Flow through me, Lord, till lagging souls are quickened,

Till lives of failure sing the victory song,

Till praise from lips long dumb and silent, open,

And join with rapture earth's glad, cleansed throng.

5 Flow through me, Lord, till waters from Thy fountain

Shall slake the thirst of souls in deserts drear.

Flow through me, Lord, till arid places blossom

With roses fresh and sweet, and wondrous fair.

6 Flow through me, Lord, set all my heart-strings thrilling,

With Thine own love, so matchless, perfect, free.

Flow through me, Lord, till naught in earth or heaven,

Can satisfy my being, Lord, but Thee.

< E271 C220 K220 S130 >

1 Of the Spirit born in spirit,

As the sons of God indeed,

We possess the Holy Spirit,

Dwelling in us for all need.

Yet we still need more of Him, Lord,

That we may be full of Thee;

May Thou fill us with Thy Spirit,

Give us life abundantly.

2 Lord, we know the Spirit in us,

But of life Thy Spirit is,

That the riches of Thy fulness

We may share thru what He is.

Yet we still require Thy Spirit

As the power from on high,

That for all Thy work and service,

We may be equipped thereby.

3 Lord, baptize us with Thy Spirit,

Clothe us with Thy pow'r of might;

With this "mantle" of Thy power,

We may then the battle fight.

May Thy wind now blow upon us,

Giving us the tongues of fire,

That, as witnesses anointed,

We'll fulfill Thy heart's desire.

4 With the power of Thy Spirit,

Still we need the gifts to share,

That as members we may function

And Thy testimony bear.

By Thy Spirit's full outpouring,

Lord, impart the gifts we need,

That the building of Thy Body

With Thy blessing might proceed.

5 For Thy glory and Thy kingdom,

May Thou hear Thy Body's cry!

Now fulfill Thy holy purpose,

All our hunger satisfy.

May we all partake Thy Spirit,

Him apply in many ways;

His infilling, His outpouring,

And His gifts to share always.

< E272 C221 K221 S131 >

1 Christ indeed was born of Spirit

When He came a man to be;

And before His service started,

With the Spirit filled was He.

Yet He still received the baptism

Of the Spirit from on high

When He came to start His service

And was clothed with pow'r thereby.

2 Peter and the Lord's disciples

All were Spirit born and filled,

Breathing in the Holy Spirit

As on them Christ breathed and willed.

Yet they still received the baptism

Of the Spirit from on high

When they were equipped for service,

And were clothed with pow'r thereby.

3 Saul of Tarsus, the Ephesians,

And Samaritans believed;

Thus by Spirit generated,

Of His fulness they received.

Yet they still received the baptism

Of the Spirit from on high

When some laid their hands upon them,

And were clothed with pow'r thereby.

4 We are also born of Spirit

On the day when we believe,

And of Him we now are drinking

As we daily Him receive.

Yet we also must be baptized

With the Spirit from on high,

Thus to be equipped for service,

And be clothed with pow'r thereby.

5 Lord, baptize us with Thy Spirit!

This is what we need today;

Clothe us with Thy heav'nly power,

Bring us under its full sway.

Oh, baptize us in this hour!

This is all our earnest cry;

Now on us repeat Thine answer,

Clothe with power from on high.

< E277 C224 K224 S133 >

1 Christ the Savior hath ascended

To the heavens far above,

Crowned with glory and with honor

By the Father God in love;

He hath made Him Head of all things,

His supremacy to prove.

2 From this Christ to God ascended

Hath the Spirit been outpoured,

Poured upon the Church, His Body,

That His members be empow'red;

Thus the Lord of all in heaven

Thru His Church will be adored.

3 In the flesh by incarnation,

Into man He God hath brought;

By His death and resurrection,

Into God He man hath brought;

God and man together mingled,

In Himself is fully wrought.

4 Now in heaven by ascension

He is seated on the throne;

All the lordship, all the headship,

He Himself doth fully own;

And by pouring out His Spirit,

He as such might be made known.

5 By this outpour, His descension

On the Church was realized;

'Tis by this, that in His Spirit

All the Church He hath baptized;

Thus the baptism of the Spirit

Was forever actualized.

6 Hallelujah, 'tis accomplished,

And accomplished once for all!

Hallelujah, we're included,

All included, great or small!

Praise Him, He hath sent the Spirit

And baptized the Church withal!

< E279 C227 K227 S135 >

1 First the blood, and then the ointment,

Cleansing, then anointing comes;

If we pass not thru Golgotha,

Ne'er to Pentecost we'll come.

If the blood has never cleansed us,

Ne'er the Spirit's pow'r we'll know,

If for Christ we'd truly witness,

Self-life to the Cross must go.

Through the Cross, O Lord, I pray,

Put my soul-life all away;

Make me any price to pay,

Full anointing to receive.

2 Christ, the Rock, must first be smitten,

That the living water flow;

Without death the Spirit's fulness

Ne'er could dwell in man below.

If with Christ we die completely,

Willing thus our all to lose,

He will clothe us with His power

And to win the world will use.

3 First the altar, then the fire,

If no loss, there'll be no gain;

If our all has not been offered,

To the throne we'll ne'er attain.

If to sacrifice we're willing,

All forsaking, God t'obey,

He to us will be committed

And thru us His pow'r display.

4 First we must prepare the vessels

That the Oil they may contain;

Dig the valley full of ditches

That they may be filled with Rain.

First we must go thru the Jordan

Ere anointed from above;

First in death we must be baptized,

Then experience the Dove.

5 When we see the ripened harvest

Of the golden countryside,

We may know that many seeds have

Fallen to the earth and died.

Ere the fruit of life may blossom,

We must surely suffer death;

If with Christ we've not been buried,

We'll not feel the Spirit's breath.

6 Since it must be thus, I pray, Lord,

Help me go the narrow way;

Deal with pride and make me willing

Thus to suffer, Thee t'obey.

I for greater power pray not,

Deeper death is what I need;

All the meaning of the Cross, Lord,

Work in me - for this I plead.

< E296 C234 K234 S141 >

1 And can it be that I should gain

An int'rest in the Savior's blood?

Died He for me, who caused His pain?

For me, who Him to death pursued?

Amazing love! how can it be

That Thou, my God, shouldst die for me?

2 'Tis mystery all! The Immortal dies!

Who can explore His strange design?

In vain the firstborn seraph tries

To sound the depths of love Divine!

'Tis mercy all! let earth adore,

Let angel minds inquire no more.

3 He left His Father's throne above,

So free, so infinite His grace;

Emptied Himself of all but love,

And bled for Adam's helpless race:

'Tis mercy all, immense and free;

For, O my God, it found out me.

4 Long my imprisoned spirit lay

Fast bound in sin and nature's night;

Thine eye diffused a quickening ray,

I woke, the dungeon flamed with light;

My chains fell off, my heart was free,

I rose, went forth, and followed Thee.

5 No condemnation now I dread;

Jesus, and all in Him, is mine!

Alive in Him, my living Head,

And clothed in righteousness Divine,

Bold I approach the eternal throne,

And claim the crown, through Christ my own.

< E304 C- K- S- >

1 How should the Lord keep back His sword from blood?

"The soul that sinneth it shall surely die:"

But ah, can Justice make His counsels good?

Can Law bring in the glory from on high?

Grace must provide a Lamb - a Ransom find;

Redeem by One whom death no more may bind.

2 "One poor wise man" hath cried, O God, to Thee;

His blood is counted precious in Thy sight.

He liveth, and His name shall ever be

Thy praise, Thy glory, Thy supreme delight.

By Jesus' blood - that new and living way -

God's priests shall now within the holiest stay.

3 The blood of bulls and goats for ages failed

To purge the conscience, burdened sore with sins;

Thy precious blood, O Lamb of God, prevailed -

Through Thee, sweet Peace her endless reign begins.

Thy blood hath made redemption e'en for me;

Complete I stand, O risen Christ, in Thee.

4 The precious blood of Christ, it speaketh peace

To guilty sinners, groaning 'neath their load;

To captive spirits it proclaims release,

And Pharaoh's slaves become the "hosts of God."

His flesh is meat - His blood is drink indeed;

He died, He rose, His people's cause to plead.

5 Oh, precious blood! Poured freely forth for me,

My sins are sunk beneath thy crimson tide.

No more before th' Avenger's sword I flee!

Christ is the Refuge-City, where I hide.

My life's dark page, blood-sprinkled, gleameth white;

My name shines forth in heaven in words of light.

< E389 C290 K290 S171 >

1 Lord Jesus, I long in Thy presence to live,

From morning to evening my one world Thou art;

O let not my heart be contented or rest

When loving or seeking what with Thee doth part.

Each moment, each day, throughout suff'ring and pain,

When nought in the world can give comfort or cheer,

When sighing and weeping encompasses me,

Lord, still all my sighing and wipe every tear.

2 Each time when I dream of the goodness of life,

I pray Thee, dear Lord, that Thou in it may be;

O do not allow me to choose by myself,

Nor seek any pleasure that's other than Thee.

Each night when alone in the stillness I lie,

I pray Thee, Lord Jesus, that Thou wilt be near;

Each morning ere dawn comes, while still in my sleep,

Then whispering call me and open my ear.

3 Each time, Lord, when reading in Thy holy Word,

I pray that Thy glory may shine on each line,

That clearly I'll see what a Savior I have

And how great salvation that Thou hast made mine.

When helpless I come, Lord, to kneel at Thy throne,

I pray Thee to hear me and grant me Thy grace;

If thru my shortcomings Thou hear not my prayer,

Withdraw not Thy presence, O hide not Thy face.

4 Each time when of heavenly blessings I think,

O let my heart long to be raptured to Thee;

My only hope here is Thy coming again,

My only joy there, Lord, Thy presence will be.

Lord, teach me each day in Thy presence to live,

From morning to evening my one world Thou art;

O let not my heart be contented or rest

When loving or seeking what with Thee doth part.

< E412 C309 K309 S179 >

1 Lord, reveal Thyself to me,

That the flesh I'll fully know;

May Thy grace so work in me,

That in dust I'll lowly bow.

How I long for victory,

Yet, thru all my life, how weak!

Evil things I cannot leave,

Nor can do the good I seek.

2 Inwardly I want the Lord,

But my conduct hateful is;

Though I would, I cannot change,

O what real bondage 'tis!

By God's law my sin's revealed,

But the law of sin doth bind;

Though I struggle to be free,

No release my soul can find.

3 Many times I fall and rise,

Oft resolve, and often fail;

Craving vict'ry, I retreat,

And my sad defeat bewail.

Truly I am sold to sin

And completely powerless;

There's no good within my flesh,

All is dark and sinfulness.

4 Now I know myself in part,

And confess my helplessness;

All my temperament is odd,

All my life corrupted is.

Subtle self I cannot trust,

Nor to fleshly strength can cling;

All my trust and all my hope

Is in Jesus Christ my King.

5 May the Cross put me to death

That on Christ I may rely;

May His Holy Spirit fill,

That Himself I may apply.

May His death so work in me

Daily deeper than before,

That my self may be destroyed

And His life thru me may pour.

6 O how bitter is my case!

Who this wretched slave can free,

Who deliver from this death,

To a life of victory?

Jesus shed His blood for me,

Christ is now my holiness;

I receive Him as my life

And my portion measureless.

7 Now I'm wholly sanctified,

Selfless, I obey His word;

Nevermore to feel ashamed

When I come before the Lord.

How transcendent is this life!

Praise the Lord, He heard my cry

And has made me wholly free.

< E415 C314 K314 S- >

1 There is a foe whose hidden pow'r

The Christian well my fear,

More subtle far than inbred sin,

And to the heart more dear.

It is the pow'r of selfishness,

It is the willful I,

And ere my Lord can live in me,

My very self must die.

2 There is, like Anak's sons of old,

A race of giants still:

Self-glorying, self-confidence,

Self-seeking and self-will.

Still must these haughty Anakims

By Caleb's sword be slain,

Ere Hebron's heights of heav'nly love,

Our conqu'ring feet can gain.

3 Oh, save me from self-will, dear Lord,

Which claims Thy sacred throne;

Oh! Let my will be lost in Thine,

And let Thy will be done.

Oh, keep me from self-confidence,

And self-sufficiency;

Let me exchange my strength for Thine,

And lean alone on Thee.

4 Oh, save me from self-seeking, Lord,

Let me not be my own;

A living sacrifice I come,

Lord, keep me Thine alone.

From proud vain glory save me, Lord,

From pride of praise and fame;

To Christ be all the honor given,

The glory to His name.

5 Oh, Savior, slay the self in me

By Thy consuming breath;

Show me Thy heart, Thy wounds, Thy shame,

That self be put to death.

When the Shekinah flame came down,

E'en Moses could not stay;

So let Thy glory fill me now,

And self forever slay.

< E423 C321 K321 S- >

1 Thou hidden love of God, whose height,

Whose depth unfathomed no man knows,

I see from far Thy beauteous light,

Inly I sigh for Thy repose;

My heart is pained, nor can it be

At rest, till it finds rest in Thee.

2 Thy secret voice invites me still

The sweetness of Thy yoke to prove;

And fain I would: but though my will

Seems fixed, yet wide my passion rove;

Yet hindrances strew all the way;

I aim at Thee, yet from Thee stray.

3 'Tis mercy all, that Thou hast brought

My mind to seek her peace in Thee;

Yet, while I seek but find Thee not,

No peace my wand'ring soul shall see.

Oh, when shall all my wand'rings end,

And all my steps to Thee-ward tend!

4 Is there a thing beneath the sun

That strives with Thee my heart to share?

Ah! Tear it thence, and reign alone,

The Lord of every motion there.

Then shall my heart from earth be free,

When it has found repose in Thee.

5 Oh, hide this self from me, that I

No more, but Christ in me may live;

My vile affections mortify,

Nor let one darling sin survive.

In all things nothing may I see,

Nothing desire or seek but Thee.

6 O Lord, Thy sovereign aid impart,

To save me from low-thoughted care;

Chase this self-will through all my heart,

Through all its latent mazes there.

Make me Thy duteous child, that I

Ceaseless may Abba, Father, cry.

7 Each moment draw from earth away

My heart which lowly waits Thy call;

Speak to my inmost soul and say.

"I am Thy Love, Thy God, Thy All."

To feel Thy power, to hear Thy voice,

To taste Thy love, be all my choice.

< E437 C333 K333 S186 >

1 Hast thou heard Him, seen Him, known Him?

Is not thine a captured heart?

Chief among ten thousand own Him;

Joyful choose the better part.

Captivated by His beauty,

Worthy tribute haste to bring;

Let His peerless worth constrain thee,

Crown Him now unrivaled King.

2 Idols once they won thee, charmed thee,

Lovely things of time and sense;

Gilded thus does sin disarm thee,

Honeyed lest thou turn thee thence.

3 What has stripped the seeming beauty

From the idols of the earth?

Not a sense of right or duty,

But the sight of peerless worth.

4 Not the crushing of those idols,

With its bitter void and smart;

But the beaming of His beauty,

The unveiling of His heart.

5 Who extinguishes their taper

Till they hail the rising sun?

Who discards the garb of winter

Till the summer has begun?

6 'Tis that look that melted Peter,

'Tis that face that Stephen saw,

'Tis that heart that wept with Mary,

Can alone from idols draw:

7 Draw and win and fill completely,

Till the cup o'erflow the brim;

What have we to do with idols

Who have companied with Him?

< E488 C361 K361 S203 >

1 Lord, Thou hast shown the mystery,

How on the Cross I died with Thee;

I need no other pow'r or way

That I may triumph day by day.

2 That cross of Thine is also mine,

Into my life its light doth shine;

When I believe I'm dead with Thee,

The world has lost it pow'r o'er me.

3 Since I am crucified with Thee,

From sin and self I am set free;

How can I still enjoy the world

Or seek its vanities unfurled?

4 I take my place, dear Lord, with Thee

Upon the cross of Calvary.

Thy life and power then are mine,

Since Thou and I in oneness twine.

5 Since Thou didst come to slay the foe,

His work and power to overthrow,

I too can overcome in Thee

And prove Thy mighty pow'r in me.

6 Yet, for the vict'ry we rely

Upon the death which Thou didst die;

We tread the path which Thou hast trod

Until we reach the goal in God.

7 My death with Thee I now believe

And all its meaning would receive.

Thy death more deeply show to me,

That from my flesh I may be free.

8 I long to win as Thou hast won,

To reign with Thee when Thou dost come.

If we the cross will gladly bear,

Then in Thy glory we will share.

< E489 C370 K370 S- >

1 Oh, Jesus, Lord, when Thou on earth

Accompanied Thy faithful band,

It seemed they knew, but knew Thee not,

Thyself they did not understand.

2 They heard Thy voice, beheld Thy form,

Thy beauteous stature unforgot;

They crowded 'round Thee, met Thy gaze,

But who Thou art, they knew it not.

3 As they of old we too are veiled;

We've known Thee long apparently;

Yet if we say we know, at best

We know Thee not transparently.

4 But as the Spirit now Thou art,

Another Comforter become;

Reveal Thyself within my heart,

Since to Thy temple Thou hast come.

5 With Thy blest Spirit, Lord, fill me,

Fill every corner of my soul;

May Thou inspire my every part,

Oh may Thou touch, renew the whole.

6 The Spirit then revealing make

Thyself more real within my heart,

That ear not hear, nor eye may see

How very real to me Thou art.

7 When Thou in mercy dost reveal

And give Thyself as Spirit thus,

What in the world can be more real,

More true than what Thou art to us?

8 Thy Spirit, Lord, in mine, I pray,

O'erflow my being as a flood,

That every part with glory shine

And everywhere be Thee and God.

9 How close we are in such a life,

In one is blended earth with heav'n;

Thy presence sweetly fills our souls;

Our hearts are to Thy praises giv'n.

< E501 C382 K382 S215 >

1 O glorious Christ, Savior mine,

Thou art truly radiance divine;

God infinite, in eternity,

Yet man in time, finite to be.

Oh! Christ, expression of God, the Great,

Inexhaustible, rich, and sweet!

God mingled with humanity

Lives in me my all to be.

2 The fulness of God dwells in Thee;

Thou dost manifest God's glory;

In flesh Thou hast redemption wrought;

As Spirit, oneness with me sought.

3 All things of the Father are Thine;

All Thou art in Spirit is mine;

The Spirit makes Thee real to me,

That Thou experienced might be.

4 The Spirit of life causes Thee

By Thy Word to transfer to me.

Thy Spirit touched, Thy Word received,

Thy life in me is thus conceived.

5 In spirit while gazing on Thee,

As a glass reflecting Thy glory,

Like to Thyself transformed I'll be,

That Thou might be expressed thru me.

6 In no other way could we be

Sanctified and share Thy vict'ry;

Thus only spiritual we'll be,

And touch the life of glory.

7 Thy Spirit will me saturate,

Every part will God permeate,

Deliv'ring me from the old man,

With all saints building for His plan.

< E510 C388 K388 S232 >

1 I've found the One of peerless worth,

My heart doth sing for joy;

And sing I must, for Christ I have:

Oh, what a Christ have I!

2 My Christ, He is the Lamb of God,

Who full salvation brings;

He is the Sun of Righteousness,

With healing in His wings.

3 My Christ, He is the Tree of Life

With fruit abundant, sweet;

My hunger He doth satisfy;

Of Him I daily eat.

4 My Christ, He is the smitten Rock

Whence living waters burst;

He is the fountain in my heart

Which quenches all my thirst.

5 Christ is my life, my light my way,

My comfort and my health,

My peace, my rest, my joy, my hope,

My glory and my wealth.

6 Christ is my wisdom and my pow'r,

My boast and righteousness,

My vict'ry and redemption sure,

My truth and holiness.

7 Christ is my Savior, Shepherd, Lord,

My Advocate above,

My Counsellor, my Father, God,

My Brother, Friend, and Love.

8 Christ is my Captain and my Guard,

My Teacher and my Guide,

My Bridegroom, Master and my Head;

In me doth He reside.

9 Christ is my Prophet, Priest, and King;

My Prophet full of sight;

My Priest that stands 'twixt me and God,

My King that rules with might.

10 Christ is the Author of my faith,

And its Perfecter too,

My Mediator, Guarantee,

And faithful Witness true.

11 Christ is my everlasting home,

My all-sufficient land;

My fortress, tower, hiding-place,

And my eternal stand.

12 Christ is my sabbath and new moon,

My morning and my day,

My age and my eternity

That ne'er will pass away.

13 Christ is my trust and my desire,

In comeliness replete,

My satisfaction and delight,

Who all my need doth meet.

14 My Christ, the all-inclusive One,

My Christ what shall I call?

He is the first, He is the last,

My Christ is All in all.

15 Since such a treasure I possess,

My heart doth sing for joy;

And I must sing, and sing again;

Oh, what a Christ have I!

< E515 C- K- S- >

1 All is in Christ;

God's dear Son is Lord of all.

Jesus Christ is life's perfection,

Perfect love and perfect light.

Son of God, the true reflection

Of the Father's radiance bright.

All the treasures of God's riches,

All the secrets of His wisdom,

All in Christ are hid away.

Let His name be praised today!

2 All is in Christ;

God's dear Son is Lord of all.

Blessings are imparted to us

By the shameful cross He bore.

By His suffering inglorious

We have peace forevermore.

By the Cross we have forgiveness,

Life eternal, endless mercy.

By God's Son is freely giv'n

Everything in earth and heav'n.

3 All is in Christ;

God's dear Son is Lord of all.

In me there is naught but weakness,

I am worthless, full of sin,

Stricken by its mortal sickness,

Lacking light and hope within.

Now in Christ I find abundant

Victory and strength and power.

Savior, come and live in me,

Come and make me rich in Thee.

4 All is in Christ;

God's dear Son is Lord of all.

Savior, pardon my transgressions,

For my love is still so small;

Though I gave all my possessions,

This would profit scarce at all.

'Tis myself that Thou desirest;

So I give myself, dear Master;

No thing hast Thou kept from me -

Nor will I keep aught from Thee.

5 All is in Christ;

Your whole self present to Him.

Vain your quest for lasting pleasure,

Wealth, success, and worldly fame;

Christ alone must be your treasure,

His resource your only claim.

Come, let Him disperse the famine

Of your arid, waste existence.

Let God's Son, th' Immortal King

Freely give you everything.

< E521 C- K- S- >

1 I thank Thee, Lord, that Thou hast shown,

And I begin to see,

What Thou canst be to all Thine own,

What they may be to Thee;

If only they will yield Thee all,

And trustingly obey Thy call.

2 How wonderful! I never knew

That I might trust Thee so;

That Thou wouldst be so much to me,

In all the way I go,

That every need Thou wouldst supply,

And all my longings satisfy.

3 I take Thee as my keeper now,

And I commit to Thee

My soul, my way, my works, my cause,

In Thy sole charge to be;

And my deposit, Thou, I know

Wilt guard secure from every foe.

4 I take Thee for my peace, O Lord,

My heart to keep and fill,

Thine own great calm, amid earth's storms

Shall keep me always still;

And as Thy kingdom doth increase,

So shall Thine ever-deep'ning peace.

5 I take Thee as my wisdom too,

For wisdom's sum Thou art;

Thou, who dost choose the foolish things,

Set me henceforth apart,

That I may speak and work for Thee

As Thou shalt work and speak in me.

6 I take Thee, Lord, to be my all,

Since all Thou art is mine;

I nothing have, and nothing am;

That nothing, Lord, is Thine.

Thou shalt be everything to me,

In all things my sufficiency.

< E523 C- K- S- >

1 I have come to the Fountain of Life,

A fountain that flows from above;

I have passed from the waters of strife

And come to the Elim of love;

I have drunk of the heavenly well,

In the depths of my being it springs.

No mortal can measure or tell

The gladness the Comforter brings.

Oh, come to the Fountain of Life,

The fountain that never runs dry;

Oh, drink of the boundless supply,

For Christ is the Fountain of Life.

2 I have come to the Fountain of Blood

That for guilt and uncleanness doth flow;

I have washed in its sin-cleansing flood

And my garments are whiter than snow.

I count not my righteousness mine -

'Tis Jesus that lives in my soul.

I partake of His nature divine,

And in Him I am perfectly whole.

3 I have come to the Fountain of Health,

A boundless and endless supply;

'Tis a secret man's wisdom and wealth

Can never discover or buy.

But the secret my Lord hath revealed

In the fountain that flows from His side,

In the stripes by whose pain we are healed,

In Himself as He comes to abide.

4 I have come to the Fountain of Joy;

His joy is the strength of my heart.

My delight is unmixed with alloy,

My sunshine can never depart.

The fig tree may wither and die,

Earth's pleasures and prospects decline;

But my fountains can never be dry -

My portion, my joy is divine.

< E529 C396 K396 S- >

1 How tedious and tasteless the hours

When Jesus no longer I see!

Sweet prospects, sweet birds and sweet flow'rs,

Have all lost their sweetness to me.

The midsummer sun shines but dim,

The fields strive in vain to look gay;

But when I am happy in Him

December's as pleasant as May.

2 His name yields the richest perfume,

And sweeter than music His voice;

His presence disperses my gloom,

And makes all within me rejoice.

I should, were He always thus nigh,

Have nothing to wish or to fear;

No mortal so happy as I;

My summer would last all the year.

3 Content with beholding His face,

My all to His pleasure resigned;

No changes of season or place,

Would make any change in my mind.

While blessed with a sense of His love,

A palace a toy would appear;

And prisons would palaces prove,

If Jesus would dwell with me there.

4 My Lord, if indeed I am Thine,

If Thou art my sun and my song,

Say, why do I languish and pine?

And why are my winters so long?

Oh, drive these dark clouds from the sky,

Thy soul-cheering presence restore;

Or take me to Thee up on high,

Where winter and clouds are no more.

< E556 C408 K408 S260 >

1 Thy name is sweet as ointment poured forth;

Better Thy love than wine, O draw Thou me!

If we the footsteps follow of the flock,

Entered Thy fellowship of love we'll be.

2 He's my Beloved, I am His own love;

He draweth me, pursue I after Him.

Fragrant as myrrh, I'd hide Him in my heart;

Beauteous as henna, I'd be clothed with Him;

3 Bathe in His love, and of His fatness taste,

Lie on His breast, His sweetness there enjoy;

His love the banner, His affection shown

Tenderly soothes my heart to purest joy.

4 Oh, my Beloved's mine, and I am His;

I am a lily and my Shepherd He;

May daybreak come, the shadows flee away,

Him on the mountains as a hart I'd see.

5 Myrrh of the death with Him and frankincense,

The resurrection, permeate my heart;

North wind awake, and let the south wind blow,

Make my heart's garden pleasure to His heart.

6 I'd be to Him a dove that's undefiled,

As a pure lily in His presence be,

His, wholly His, the joy of all His joys,

He wholly mine, the Song of songs to me.

7 Fair as the moon, conformed to Him I'd be,

Clear as the sun, unto His stature grown;

For my Beloved, all to please His heart,

For my Beloved, that His life be shown.

8 Thou art my life, and I Thine image real;

Love in such union is as death most strong,

Ne'er can it be destroyed or e'er replaced

Till Thou on spices mountains come ere long.

< E560 C- K- S- >

1 Come, O Thou Traveler unknown,

Whom still I hold but cannot see;

My company before is gone,

And I am left alone with Thee;

With Thee all night I mean to stay,

And wrestle till the break of day.

2 I need not tell Thee who I am,

My sin and misery declare;

Thyself hast called me by my name,

Look on Thy hands, and read it there;

But who, I ask Thee, who art Thou?

Tell me Thy name, and tell me now.

3 In vain Thou strugglest to get free;

I never will unloose my hold;

Art Thou the Man that died for me?

The secret of Thy love unfold;

Wrestling, I will not let Thee go,

Till I Thy name, Thy nature know.

4 Yield to me now, for I am weak,

But confident in self-despair;

Speak to my heart, in blessings speak,

Be conquered by my instant prayer;

Speak, or Thou never hence shalt move,

And tell me if Thy name be Love.

5 'Tis Love! 'Tis Love! Thou diedst for me;

I hear Thy whisper in my heart;

The morning breaks, the shadows flee:

Pure, universal Love Thou art;

To me, to all Thy mercies move;

Thy nature and Thy name is Love.

6 Lame as I am, I take the prey;

Hell, earth and sin, with ease o'ercome.

I leap for joy, pursue my way,

And, as a bounding hart, I run,

Through all eternity to prove

Thy nature and Thy name is Love.

< E564 C- K- S264 >

1 I have learned the wondrous secret

Of abiding in the Lord;

I have tasted life's pure fountain,

I am drinking of His word;

I have found the strength and sweetness

Of abiding 'neath the blood;

I have lost myself in Jesus,

I am sinking into God.

I'm abiding in the Lord

And confiding in His word;

I am hiding in the bosom of His love.

Yes, abiding in the Lord

And confiding in His word,

I am hiding in the bosom of His love.

2 I am crucified with Jesus,

And He lives and dwells with me;

I have ceased from all my struggling,

'Tis no longer I, but He.

All my will is yielding to Him,

And His Spirit reigns within;

And His precious blood each moment

Keeps me cleansed and free from sin.

3 All my sicknesses I bring Him,

And He bears them all away;

All my fears and griefs I tell Him,

All my cares from day to day,

All my strength I draw from Jesus,

By His breath I live and move;

E'en His very mind He gives me,

And His faith, and life, and love.

4 For my words I take His wisdom,

For my works His Spirit's power;

For my ways His ceaseless presence

Guards and guides me every hour.

Of my heart, He is the portion,

Of my joy the boundless spring;

Savior, Sanctifier, Healer,

Glorious Lord, and coming King.

< E571 C- K633 S- >

1 Thou whose name is called Jesus,

Risen Lord of life and pow'r,

Oh, it is so sweet to trust Thee,

Every day and every hour;

Of Thy wondrous grace I sing,

Savior, Counsellor, and King.

2 Thou canst keep my feet from falling,

Even my poor wayward feet;

Thou who dost present me faultless

In Thee - Righteousness complete;

Jesus, Lord, in knowing Thee,

Oh, what strength and victory.

3 All the sin in me, my Savior,

Thou canst conquer and subdue;

With Thy sanctifying power

Permeate my spirit through;

Let Thy government increase,

Risen, crowned, Prince of Peace.

4 Thou canst keep my upward looking,

Ever upward in Thy face;

Thou canst make me stand, upholden

By the greatness of Thy grace;

Every promise of Thy word

Now I claim from Thee, dear Lord.

5 Oh! what joy to trust Thee, Jesus,

Mighty Victor o'er the grave,

And to learn amid earth's shadows

Thine unceasing power to save!

Only those who prove Thee know

What the grace Thou dost bestow.

6 Make my life a bright outshining

Of Thy life, that all my see

Thine own resurrection power

Mightily put forth in me;

Ever let my heart become

Yet more consciously Thy home.

< E579 C- K- S- >

1 Jesus! I am resting, resting

In the joy of what Thou art;

I am finding out the greatness

Of Thy loving heart.

Thou hast bid me gaze upon Thee,

And Thy beauty fills my soul,

For, by Thy transforming power,

Thou hast made me whole.

Jesus! I am resting, resting

In the joy of what Thou art;

I am finding out the greatness

Of Thy loving heart.

2 Oh, how great Thy loving kindness,

Vaster, broader than the sea;

Oh, how marvelous Thy goodness,

Lavished all on me!

Yes, I rest in Thee, Beloved,

Know what wealth of grace is Thine,

Know Thy certainty of promise,

And have made it mine.

3 Simply trusting Thee, Lord Jesus,

I behold Thee as Thou art,

And Thy love, so pure, so changeless,

Satisfies my heart,

Satisfies its deepest longings,

Meets, supplies its every need,

Compasseth me round with blessings,

Thine is love indeed.

4 Ever lift Thy face upon me,

As I work and wait for Thee;

Resting 'neath Thy smile, Lord Jesus,

Earth's dark shadows flee.

Brightness of my Father's glory,

Sunshine of my Father's face,

Keep me ever trusting, resting,

Fill me with Thy grace.

< E581 C- K- S- >

1 On Thee my heart is resting,

Ah, this is rest indeed:

What else, Almighty Savior,

Can a poor sinner need?

Thy light is all my wisdom,

Thy love is all my stay;

Thy coming back in glory,

Draws nearer every day.

On Thee my heart is resting,

Ah, this is rest indeed:

What else, Almighty Savior,

Can a poor sinner need?

2 My guilt is great, but greater

The mercy Thou dost give;

Thyself, a spotless Off'ring,

Hast died that I should live.

With Thee, my soul unfettered

Has risen from the dust;

Thy blood is all my treasure,

Thy word is all my trust.

3 Through me, Thou gentle Master,

Thy purposes fulfil;

I yield myself forever

To Thy most holy will.

What though I be but weakness?

My strength is not in me;

The poorest of Thy people

Has all things, having Thee.

4 When clouds are darkest round me,

Thou, Lord, art then most near,

My drooping faith to quicken,

My weary soul to cheer.

Safe nestling in Thy bosom,

I gaze upon Thy face;

In vain my foes would drive me

From Thee, my hiding-place.

5 'Tis Thou hast made me happy,

'Tis Thou hast set me free;

To whom shall I give glory

Forever, but to Thee?

Of earthly love and blessing

Should every stream run dry,

Thy grace shall still be with me,

Thy grace, to live and die.

< E589 C434 K434 S269 >

1 God in heaven hath a treasure,

Riches none may count or tell;

Hath a deep eternal pleasure,

Christ the Son, He loveth well.

God hath here on earth a treasure,

None but He its price may know -

Deep, unfathomable pleasure,

Christ revealed in saints below.

2 God in tongues of fire descending,

Chosen vessels thus to fill

With the treasure never ending,

Ever spent - unfailing still.

God's own hand the vessel filling

From the glory far above,

Longing hearts forever stilling

With the riches of His love.

3 Thus though worn, and tried, and tempted,

Glorious calling, saint, is thine;

Let the Lord but find thee emptied,

Living branch in Christ the Vine!

Vessels of the world's despising,

Vessels weak and poor and base,

Bearing wealth God's heart is prizing,

Glory from Christ's blessed face.

4 Oh to be but emptier, lowlier,

Mean, unnoticed - and unknown,

And to God a vessel holier,

Filled with Christ and Christ alone!

Naught of earth to cloud the glory,

Naught of self the light to dim,

Telling forth His wondrous story,

Emptied to be filled with Him.

< E593 C435 K435 S271 >

1 All I have in Adam is but sin and death,

I in Christ inherit life and righteousness;

When in flesh abiding, Adam I express,

But when in the spirit Christ is manifest.

2 When I am in Adam, though I may not sin,

Unto death, a sinner, sentenced I have been;

When in Christ I need not righteously to act,

I'm already righteous, justified in fact.

3 In the flesh I need no effort to express

Marks of Adam's nature and its sinfulness;

In the spirit I need not to strive or strain,

I can live as He is and in spirit reign.

4 Thru my death with Christ, from Adam I am free,

Thru my life with Christ, new life is given me!

Minding not the flesh, old Adam cannot move,

Minding just the spirit, life divine I prove.

5 Minding just the spirit is God's saving way,

Minding just the spirit, Christ we will display;

Minding just the spirit, we can overcome,

Minding just the spirit, we the race may run.

6 Minding just the spirit, we the cross will know,

And His resurrection pow'r thru us will flow;

Minding just the spirit, Christ will live thru me,

And His life within will reach maturity.

7 In the spirit Christ is life and all to me,

Strengthening and blessing all-inclusively;

Living in the spirit, holiness I prove,

And the triune God within my heart doth move.

< E596 C- K- S- >

1 Mine is the earth, the worlds in all their fulness;

Mine, every ocean, river, plain, and hill;

Mine are the stars within the heaven's stillness,

Mine are the clouds that wander at their will.

2 Mine is the spring, when blossoms sweet are blowing,

Wakened from slumb'ring neath the winter snow;

Mine, summer's wealth, with her bright colors glowing;

Mine is the fruit rich autumn doth bestow.

3 Mine, all the things created: praise the Giver!

Fish, and all beasts, the birds upon the wing,

Sun-loving butterflies - now and forever;

Beauty and grace of every living thing.

4 Mine, all things lovely, blessing every hour,

Wealth of creation, over and around;

Mine is the sun, with its life-giving power,

Mine is the music wonderful of sound.

5 Mine are the pillars which cannot be shaken -

Truth in the Word, the Word that cannot fall.

Mine is the wisdom which great thoughts awaken

In a man's soul, that this life is not all.

6 Knowledge as needed, skill in all the doing,

Mine, when kept closely for my Lord above;

Beauty and wisdom, living streams e'er flowing

Fresh from the springs of God, the God of love.

7 Mine are the battles, triumph-shouts e'er ringing -

Joy of the warriors for the truth and right;

Mine are the trophies God's brave ones are bringing,

Heroes of faith and overcoming might.

8 Mine, mercies granted, and each new awaking,

Every experience, and each soul that's won;

Mine, the confessions sinners poor are making,

Yea, I am joined with them, one in God's Son.

9 One Lord in all, and all one in His Spirit,

Heavenly fellowship earth has not known;

Faith sees the riches we shall yet inherit,

Glorious treasure laid up for His own.

10 All in the bounds of earth and sea and heaven,

Creation's wonders and Thy grace are stored:

Praise to Thee, Christ, for all the wealth

Thou'st given!

Poor in myself, but wealthy in the Lord!

< E598 C440 K440 S- >

1 All fair within those children of the light,

Though dark their brows beneath the desert sun;

Mysterious joys, far hidden from all sight,

The King of Glory giveth to each one;

No thought of man has pictured them,

No hand may touch that diadem;

Within God's light His own abide

With hidden glory glorified.

2 To earthly eyes they are as Adam's race -

They wear the earthly form, and scars of pain

On them as on all sinners leave their trace;

Their outward needs are those of other men.

And theirs the forms of earthly life,

Theirs sleeping, waking, want, and strife,

Yet this they have that they despise

What fairest seems to earthly eyes.

3 And inwardly their life is from above,

The Lord's Almighty Word hath quickened them;

Flames kindled from the everlasting Love,

The children of the New Jerusalem;

Their brethren are the saints in light,

And songs of sweetness infinite

They sing with them to God Most High,

A deep and wondrous melody.

4 They walk upon the earth, and dwell in heaven,

Though pow'rless, guard the world with arms unseen;

Deep peace to them in midst of strife is given,

And all they wish they have, though poor and mean.

Storms beat them, but may not destroy,

Fast rooted in eternal joy;

They walk as in the shade of death,

Yet living on in silent faith.

5 When Christ their Life shall be made manifest,

When He shall come with all His pow'r to rule,

Their glory, hidden long, shall be confessed;

Arise and shine! O bright and beautiful!

With Christ ye shall ascend on high,

Victorious in His victory -

The hidden light shall shine afar,

Each saint an everlasting star.

< E602 C443 K443 S284 >

1 O how glorious! O how holy!

God is the eternal life!

Full, unlimited, and pow'rful,

Pure, and merciful, and bright!

In this life are all His riches,

All His nature, love and light.

2 O how loving! O how gracious!

God Himself is life to man!

He in man hath made a spirit

That He might fulfill His plan.

'Tis His heart's delight and longing

E'er to be received by man.

3 O what love and grace unbounded!

God as life to man doth flow!

He no more is hid in secret

But Himself to man doth show,

First in flesh and then as Spirit

That His life all men may know.

4 How approachable! How near us!

God in Christ our life to be!

Christ is God in flesh incarnate,

Manifest for man to see.

Died and risen, now He enters

Into man, his life to be.

5 O what wonder! As the Spirit

God as life to man is shown!

'Tis His other transformation,

He as Spirit thus is know;

Men convicting and inspiring,

He within them makes His home.

6 O how glorious! O how precious!

Thus the triune God to know!

First the Father in the Son came,

Now the Son as Spirit flows.

When in man the Spirit enters

God as life He doth bestow.

7 How mysterious, yet how real!

God Himself now flows in me!

In my heart, with me in oneness,

He has come my life to be.

Hallelujah! Hallelujah!

I will praise unceasingly!

< E606 C445 K445 S- >

1 Oh, how the thought of God attracts

And draws the heart from earth,

And sickens it of passing shows

And dissipating mirth!

2 'Tis not enough to save our souls,

To shun th' eternal fires;

The thought of God will rouse the heart

To more sublime desires.

3 God only is the creature's home,

Though rough and straight the road;

Yet nothing less can satisfy

The love that longs for God.

4 Oh, utter but the Name of God

Down in your heart of hearts,

And see how from the world at once

All tempting light departs.

5 A trusting heart, a yearning eye,

Can win their way above;

If mountains can be moved by faith,

Is there less power in love?

6 How little of that road, my soul!

How little hast thou gone!

Take heart, and let the thought of God

Allure thee further on.

7 The freedom from all willful sin,

The Christian's daily task;

Oh! These are graces far below

What longing love would ask!

8 The perfect way is hard to flesh;

It is not hard to love;

If thou wert sick from want of God,

How swiftly wouldst thou move!

9 Then keep thy conscience sensitive;

No inward token miss:

And go where grace entices thee -

Perfection lies in this.

< E609 C448 K448 S288 >

1 I praise Thee for Thy mystery,

That I may truly contact Thee;

In unapproachable light Thou wast

But now as Spirit nigh to me.

2 The Father, Son, and Spirit, Thou,

The triune God, my life fore'er;

In me Thou art the full supply

That I Thy holy nature share.

3 The triune God the Spirit is,

And comes as breath and wind to me;

'Tis thus I may experience

The Godhead's wondrous mystery.

4 All that the Father is and has

In His beloved Son doth rest,

And all the riches of the Son

Are by the Spirit now possessed.

5 The Spirit doth descend on me

And to my spirit enters in,

That He, the Father in the Son,

My blessed portion be within.

6 The Father is the fountainhead,

The Son expression gives to Him;

The Spirit is His very flow,

As my reality within.

7 The Father in the Son has come

That God to man Himself may show;

The Son as Spirit enters me

That God I inwardly may know.

8 The Father purposed that the Son

Should be the first in everything;

The Son the Father takes as Head

And over all His headship brings.

9 The Spirit perfectly desires

That Christ, the Son, be glorified,

And He reveals Him unto me,

That He be fully testified.

10 Thy final form the Spirit is,

Our worship to receive within;

If I Thy riches would enjoy,

In spirit I must contact Him.

11 If I in spirit worship Thee,

In spirit live, in spirit pray,

The Holy Spirit I will touch

And Thee enjoy in every way.

< E611 C449 K449 S290 >

1 God's glorious substance Spirit is,

His essence, holy and divine;

To contact God and Him enjoy,

His Spirit I must touch with mine.

2 The spirit is the innermost,

The part of man most deep and real;

If he would contact God in life,

'Tis with the spirit he must deal.

3 The worship which the Father seeks

Is in the spirit's strength alone;

His Spirit into man's would come,

That His and man's may thus be one.

4 When Spirit unto spirit calls

The two commingle and are one;

Man's spirit is the Spirit's home,

The Spirit doth man's life become.

5 Man's spirit must God's Spirit touch

If in God's fulness he would live;

'Tis only with the spirit thus

That he to God may worship give.

6 In ministry and fellowship

Man to the spirit we must bring;

All ministry should turn to prayer,

Spirit to spirit answering.

7 In spirit we must pray and serve,

In spirit touch the life divine,

In spirit grow, in spirit build,

That Christ thru us may fully shine.

8 Lord, to the spirit I would turn

And learn to truly contact Thee;

Thy Spirit thus will flow with mine

And overflow eternally.

< E617 C- K- S- >

1 Thou sweet, beloved will of God,

My anchor ground, my fortress hill,

My spirit's silent, fair abode,

In Thee I hide me and am still.

2 O Will, that willest good alone,

Lead Thou the way, Thou guidest best;

A little child, I follow on,

And, trusting, lean upon Thy breast.

3 God's will doth make the bitter sweet,

And all is well when it is done;

Unless His will doth hallow it,

The glory of all joy is gone.

4 Thy beautiful sweet will, my God,

Hold fast in its sublime embrace

My captive will, a gladsome bird,

Prisoned in such a realm of grace.

5 Within this place of certain good

Love evermore expands her wings,

Or nestling in Thy perfect choice,

Abides content with what it brings.

6 Oh, lightest burden, sweetest yoke;

It lifts, it bears my happy soul,

It giveth wings to this poor heart;

My freedom is Thy grand control.

7 Upon God's will I lay me down,

As child upon its mother's breast;

No silken couch, nor softest bed,

Could ever give me such deep rest.

8 Thy wonderful grand will, my God,

With triumph now I make it mine;

And faith shall cry a joyous Yes

To every dear command of Thine.

< E621 C- K- S- >

1 Beneath the cross of Jesus

I fain would take my stand,

The shadow of a might Rock

Within a weary land;

A rest upon the way,

From the burning of the noontide heat,

And the burden of the day.

2 Oh, safe and happy shelter!

Oh, refuge tried and sweet!

Oh, trysting place where heaven's love

And heaven's justice meet.

As to the holy patriarch

That wondrous dream was given,

So is my Savior by the cross

A ladder up to heaven.

3 There lies beneath its shadow,

But on the farther side,

The darkness of an awful grave

That gapes both deep and wide;

And there between us stands the cross,

Two arms outstretched to save,

Like a watchman set to guard the way

From that eternal grave.

4 Upon that cross of Jesus

Mine eyes at times can see

The very dying form of One,

Who suffered there for me;

And from my smitten heart, with tears,

Two wonders I confess,

The wonders of His glorious love,

And my own worthlessness.

5 I take, O cross, thy shadow

For my abiding place;

I ask no other sunshine than

The sunshine of His face;

Content to let the world go by,

To know no gain nor loss,

My sinful self my only shame,

My glory all the cross.

< E624 C459 K459 S- >

1 The heavier the cross, the nearer God;

No cross without, no God within!

The prince of darkness thus is trod,

Amid the world's false glare and din.

Oh, happy he, with all his loss,

Whom God hath set beneath the cross.

2 The heavier the cross, the better saint;

This is the touchstone God applies.

The gardens many would be faint,

Unwet by showers from weeping eyes!

The gold by fire is purified;

The saint is by much trouble tried.

3 The heavier the cross, the stronger faith:

The loaded palm strikes deeper root;

The vine juice sweetly issueth

When men have pressed the clustered fruit;

And courage grows where dangers come,

Like pearls beneath the salty foam.

4 The heavier the cross, the deeper prayer;

The bruised herbs most fragrant are.

If sky and wind were always fair,

The sailor would not watch the star;

And David's Psalms had ne'er been sung

If grief his heart had never wrung.

5 The heavier the cross, the more inspired;

From vales to climb to mountain crest;

The pilgrim, of the desert tired,

Longs for the Canaan of his rest.

The dove has here no rest in sight,

And to the ark she wings her flight.

6 The heavier the cross, the easier to die;

Death is a kinder face to see;

Our life's decay we dare defy,

From life's distress we then are free.

The cross sublimely lifts our faith

To Him who triumphed over death.

7 Thou Crucified! The cross I bear.

The longer, may it dearer be;

And lest I faint while ling'ring here,

Implant Thou such a heart in me

That faith and love may flourish e'er,

Till for the cross the crown I wear.

< E626 C458 K458 S295 >

1 Olives that have known no pressure

No oil can bestow;

If the grapes escape the winepress,

Cheering wine can never flow;

Spikenard only through the crushing,

Fragrance can diffuse.

Shall I then, Lord, shrink from suff'ring

Which Thy love for me would choose?

Each blow I suffer

Is true gain to me.

In the place of what Thou takest

Thou dost give Thyself to me.

2 Do my heartstrings need Thy stretching,

Songs divine to prove?

Do I need for sweetest music

Cruel treatment of Thy love?

Lord, I fear no deprivation

If it draws to Thee;

I would yield in full surrender

All Thy heart of love to see.

3 I'm ashamed, my Lord, for seeking

Self to guard alway;

Though Thy love has done its stripping,

Yet I've been compelled this way.

Lord, according to Thy pleasure

Fully work on me;

Heeding not my human feelings,

Only do what pleases Thee.

4 If Thy mind and mine should differ,

Still pursue Thy way;

If Thy pleasure means my sorrow,

Still my heart shall answer, "Yea!"

'Tis my deep desire to please Thee,

Though I suffer loss;

E'en though Thy delight and glory

Mean that I endure the cross.

5 Oh, I'll praise Thee, e'en if weeping

Mingle with my song.

Thine increasing sweetness calls forth

Grateful praises all day long.

Thou hast made Thyself more precious

Than all else to me:

Thou increase and I decrease, Lord -

This is now my only plea.

< E628 C469 K469 S- >

1 Via Bethlehem we journey,

We whose hearts on God are set;

Babe-like souls of Jesus learning,

While our cheeks with tears are wet;

For the manger and the stable

Are not pleasant to our eyes,

But our feet must follow Jesus,

If our hands would grasp the prize.

2 Via Nazareth! The pathway

Narrows still as on we go,

Years of toil none understanding,

Yet God teaches us to know

That the servant is not greater

Than the Lord, who through long years

Hid Himself from this world's glory,

Follow Him! Count not the tears.

3 Via Galilee, we see Him!

Stones are hurled, and cursed hissed

By the men who gather round Him,

Has He not the pathway missed?

No! Unharmed the Savior passes,

And this rough bit of the way

We must travel, since like Jesus,

Nothing can our purpose stay.

4 Via too, the awful anguish

Of the hours beneath the trees,

Where the host of Satan linger,

Awful hours of anguish these!

Yet we fail not, for God's angels

Minister to us, and say,

"Look, beloved, at the glory,

Conflict is but for a day!"

5 Then the Cross! For via Calvary

Every royal soul must go;

Here we draw the veil, for Jesus

Only can the pathway show;

"If we suffer with Him," listen,

Just a little, little while,

And the memory will have faded

In the glory of His smile!

6 Then the grave, with dear ones weeping,

Knowing that all life has fled;

(Fellow-pilgrims, art thou numbered

With the men the world calls dead?)

Thence we rise, and live with Jesus,

Throned above the world's mad strife,

Gladly forfeiting forever,

All that worldlings count as life.

7 On we press! And yonder gleaming,

Nearer every day, we see

The great walls of that fair city,

God has built for such as we;

And we catch the tender music

Of the choirs that sing of One

Who once died to have us with Him

In His kingdom, on the throne.

8 Just a few more miles, beloved!

And our feet shall ache no more;

No more sin, and no more sorrow,

Hush thee, Jesus went before;

And I hear Him sweetly whispering,

"Faint not, fear not, still press on,

For it may be ere tomorrow,

The long journey will be done."

< E635 C465 K465 S- >

1 Let us contemplate the grape vine,

From its life now let us learn,

How its growth is fraught with suff'ring,

Midst environment so stern;

How unlike the untamed flowers

Growing in the wilderness

In a maze of wild confusion,

Making patterns numberless.

2 But the blossoms of the grape vine

Without glory are and small;

Though they do have some expression,

They are hardly seen withal.

But a day since they have flowered

Into fruit the blooms have grown;

Never may they wave corollas

With luxuriant beauty shown.

3 To a post the vine is fastened;

Thus it cannot freely grow;

When its branches are extended,

To the trellis tied they go.

To the stony soil committed,

Drawing thence its food supply;

It can never choose its own way,

Or from difficulty fly.

4 Oh, how beautiful its verdure,

Which in spring spread o'er the field.

From life's energy and fulness

Growth abundant doth it yield.

Till it's full of tender branches

Twining freely everywhere,

Stretching 'gainst the sky's deep azure

Tasting sweetly of the air.

5 But the master of the vineyard

Not in lenience doth abide,

But with knife and pruning scissors

Then would strip it of its pride.

Caring not the vine is tender,

But with deep, precision stroke

All the pretty, excess branches

From the vine are neatly broke.

6 In this time of loss and ruin,

Dare the vine self-pity show?

Nay, it gives itself more fully

To the one who wounds it so,

To the hand that strips its branches,

Till of beauty destitute,

That its life may not be wasted,

But preserved for bearing fruit.

7 Into hard wood slowly hardens

Every stump of bleeding shoot,

Each remaining branch becoming

Clusters of abundant fruit.

Then, beneath the scorching sunshine,

Leaves are dried and from it drop;

Thus the fruit more richly ripens

Till the harvest of the crop.

8 Bowed beneath its fruitful burden,

Loaded branches are brought low -

Labor of its growth thru suff'ring

Many a purposed, cutting blow.

Now its fruit is fully ripened,

Comforted the vine would be;

But the harvest soon is coming,

And its days of comfort flee.

9 Hands will pick and feet will trample

All the riches of the vine,

Till from out the reddened wine-press

Flows a river full of wine.

All the day its flow continues,

Bloody-red, without alloy,

Gushing freely, richly, sweetly,

Filling all the earth with joy.

10 In appearance now the grape vine

Barren is and pitiful;

Having given all, it enters

Into night inscrutable.

No one offers to repay it

For the cheering wine that's drunk,

But 'tis stripped and cut e'en further

To a bare and branchless trunk

11 Yet its wine throughout the winter

Warmth and sweetness ever bears

Unto those in coldness shiv'ring,

Pressed with sorrow, pain, and cares.

Yet without, alone, the grape vine

Midst the ice and snow doth stand,

Steadfastly its lot enduring,

Though 'tis hard to understand.

12 Winter o'er, the vine prepareth

Fruit again itself to bear;

Budding forth and growing branches,

Beauteous green again to wear;

Never murmuring or complaining

For the winter's sore abuse,

Or for all its loss desiring

Its fresh off'ring to reduce.

13 Breathing air, untainted, heavenly,

As it lifts its arms on high,

Earth's impure, defiled affections

Ne'er the vine may occupy.

Facing sacrifice, yet smiling,

And while love doth prune once more,

Strokes it bears as if it never

Suffered loss and pain before.

14 From the branches of the grape vine

Sap and blood and wine doth flow.

Does the vine, for all it suffered,

Lost, and yielded, poorer grow?

Drunkards of the earth and wanderers,

From it drink and merry make,

From their pleasure and enjoyment

Do they richer thereby wake?

15 Not by gain our life is measured,

But by what we've lost 'tis scored;

'Tis not how much wine is drunken,

But how much has been outpoured.

For the strength of love e'er standeth

In the sacrifice we bear;

He who has the greatest suff'ring

Ever has the most to share.

16 He who treats himself severely

Is the best for God to gain;

He who hurts himself most dearly

Most can comfort those in pain.

He who suffering never beareth

Is but empty "sounding brass";

He who self-like never spareth

Has the joys which all surpass.

< E641 C- K- S- >

1 Art thou hung'ring for the fulness

Of the blessing Christ doth give?

Longing now to learn the secret

Of the life He bids thee live?

In His word thine answer standeth,

"Christ who is our Life" it saith;

Open now thy heart, and trust Him,

There to dwell, henceforth, by faith.

2 Christ, the Lord's Anointed, reigning

O'er the life He died to win,

Daily shall reveal more fully

His great power, without, within.

What thou never could'st accomplish

Shall His Spirit work through thee,

While thy soul this witness beareth,

'Tis not I, but Christ in me.

3 In Him dwelleth all God's fulness,

In Him thou art made complete;

Rise, and claim thy heavenly birthright,

Kneeling at thy Father's feet.

He will never disappoint thee,

Praise Him that the gift is thine;

Then go forth to live each moment

On sufficiency divine.

4 Lord, I come, and simply resting

On Thy faithful, changeless word,

I believe the blood doth cleanse me,

And that Christ is crowned Lord.

Grant henceforth a ceaseless outflow

Of Thy life and love through me;

Reaching those who sit in darkness,

Winning priceless souls to Thee.

< E664 C- K- S- >

1 Rise, my soul, thy God directs thee;

Stranger hands no more impede;

Pass thou on, His strength protects thee,

Strength that has the captive freed.

2 Is the wilderness before thee,

Desert lands where drought abides?

Heavenly springs shall there restore thee,

Fresh from God's exhaustless tides.

3 Light divine surrounds thy going,

God Himself shall mark thy way;

Secret blessings, richly flowing,

Lead to everlasting day.

4 God, thine everlasting portion,

Feeds thee with the Mighty's meat;

Saved from Egypt's hard extortion,

Egypt's food no more to eat.

5 Art thou weaned from Egypt's pleasures?

God in secret shall thee keep;

There unfold His hidden treasures,

There His love's exhaustless deep.

6 In the desert God will teach thee

What the God that thou hast found -

Patient, gracious, powerful, holy;

All His grace shall there abound.

7 On to Canaan's rest still wending,

E'en thy wants and woes shall bring

Suited grace from high descending;

Thou shalt taste of mercy's spring.

8 Though thy way be long and dreary,

Eagle strength He'll still renew;

Garments fresh, and feet unweary,

Tell how God hath brought thee through.

9 When to Canaan's long-loved dwelling

Love divine thy feet shall bring,

Thou, with shouts of triumph swelling,

Zion's songs in rest shall sing.

< E672 C499 K499 S- >

1 Not what I am, O Lord, but what Thou art;

That, that alone, can be my soul's true rest;

Thy love, not mine, bids fear and doubt depart,

And stills the tempest of my tossing breast.

2 It is Thy perfect love that casts out fear;

I know the voice that speaks the It is I,

And in these well-known words of heavenly cheer

I hear the joy that bids each sorrow fly.

3 Thy Name is Love! I hear it from yon Cross;

Thy Name is Love! I read it in yon tomb:

All meaner love is perishable dross,

But this shall light me through time's thickest gloom.

4 It blesses now, and shall forever bless;

It saves me now, and shall for ever save;

It holds me up in days of helplessness,

It bears me safely o'er each swelling wave.

5 'Tis what I know of Thee, my Lord and God,

That fills my soul with peace, my lips with song;

Thou art my health, my joy, my staff, my rod;

Leaning on Thee, in weakness I am strong.

6 More of Thyself, Oh, show me, hour by hour;

More of Thy glory, O my God and Lord;

More of Thyself in all Thy grace and power;

More of Thy love and truth, Incarnate Word.

< E677 C- K- S- >

1 Art thou sunk in depths of sorrow

Where no arm can reach so low?

There is One whose arms almighty

Reach beyond thy deepest woe.

God th' Eternal is thy refuge,

Let it still thy wild alarms;

Underneath thy deepest sorrow,

Are the everlasting arms.

Underneath thee, underneath thee,

Are the everlasting arms,

Everlasting, everlasting,

Are the everlasting arms.

2 Other arms grow faint and weary,

These can never faint, nor fail;

Others reach our mounts of blessing,

These our lowest loneliest vale.

O that all might know His friendship!

O that all might see His charms!

O that all might have beneath them

Jesus' everlasting arms.

3 Underneath us, O how easy;

We have not to mount on high,

But to sink into His fulness,

And in trustful weakness lie.

And we find our humbling failures

Save us from the strength that harms!

We may fail, but underneath us

Are the everlasting arms.

4 Arms of Jesus! Fold me closer,

To Thy strong and loving breast,

Till my spirit on Thy bosom

Finds its everlasting rest;

And when time's last sands are sinking,

Shield my heart from all alarms,

Softly whispering, "Underneath thee,

Are the everlasting arms."

< E693 C506 K506 S- >

1 He faileth not, for He is God;

He faileth not, His grace how good!

He faileth not, His Word is clear;

If we have God, whom need we fear?

2 The highest mount, He can make plain;

The wildest flood, He can restrain!

God of Impossibilities!

Poor puny man, now learn His ways.

3 The axe did swim on Jordan's wave!

Our God the Red Sea's waters clave!

He stopped the sun! Made long the day!

This is the God to whom we pray.

4 He bars the sea with feeble sand!

The proud waves bow at His command!

If God is thine, what more your need?

Can He not work for you indeed?

5 Our God is love; your needs are known;

His promises He'll fully own.

Our gracious God bows down His ear

The feeblest, weakest cry to hear.

6 Our God is light, and never yet,

One promise did He e'er forget.

His promises in Christ the Son

Are fully pledged, Yea and Amen.

7 Our faithful God, faith cannot break,

Nor death, nor hell, His promise shake!

Who ask in faith, He'll not deny;

His Word is sure, He must reply.

8 He faileth not, let all men hear;

He faileth not, His Word is clear.

He faileth not, His grace how good;

He faileth not, for He is God!

< E721 C514 K514 S- >

1 I'll sing of the wonderful promise

That Jesus has given to me;

"My strength is made perfect in weakness,

My grace is sufficient for thee."

And lest my poor heart should forget it,

Or ever forgetful should be,

He still keeps repeating the promise,

My grace is sufficient for thee.

Yes, over and over and over,

My Savior keeps saying to me;

My strength is made perfect in weakness,

My grace is sufficient for thee.

2 His grace is sufficient to save me,

And cleanse me from guilt and from sin;

Sufficient to sanctify wholly,

And give me His Spirit within.

His grace is sufficient for trials,

No matter how hard they may be,

This promise stands over against them,

My grace is sufficient for thee.

3 His grace is sufficient for sickness,

Sustaining and making me whole;

His grace is sufficient when sorrows

Like billows roll over the soul.

His grace is sufficient for service,

It sets us from selfishness free,

And sends us to tell the tried ones,

His grace is sufficient for thee.

4 His grace is sufficient to live by,

And should we be summoned to die

'Twill light up the valley of shadows,

And bear us away to Him nigh.

Or when we shall stand in His vict'ry,

And Christ in His glory shall see,

We'll fall at His footstool confessing,

Thy grace was sufficient for me.

5 It is not our grace that's sufficient,

But His grace, it ever must be:

Our graces are transient and changing;

His grace is unfailing as He.

And so I am ever repeating

His wonderful promise to me,

My strength is made perfect in weakness,

My grace is sufficient for thee.

< E733 C529 K529 S305 >

1 In Eden's garden fair we see

That God before two trees placed man,

The trees of life, and knowledge too,

Which for the Lord and Satan stand.

2 The tree of life the center is

Of God's eternal, perfect plan,

Denoting God in Christ as life

To be received as all by man.

3 The tree of knowledge standing there,

Bespeaks a sure and warning voice:

Outside of God there is a source

Of death to all who make this choice.

4 If man would eat the tree of life,

Then God as life he will receive,

And be transformed to precious stones,

God's will and purpose to achieve.

5 If man the tree of knowledge takes,

Then Satan enters into man

As sin, which brings him into death,

That he may not fulfill God's plan.

6 This signifies that only God

Is our full source of life and breath;

To touch ought else is but to touch

The source of knowledge and of death.

7 For knowledge only bringeth death,

Though evil or though good it seem;

For any thing apart from God,

Is but the fruit of Satan's scheme.

8 Not only evil, but the good

Is contradictory to Christ;

Not only knowledge of the bad,

But even good is versus Christ.

9 Lord, teach us only Thee to touch,

That with Thy life we filled may be,

And not to touch the good or bad,

Or anything apart from Thee.

< E734 C530 K530 S306 >

1 The law of God is holy, good,

To practise good it doth command;

Its purpose is to clearly show

That we cannot meet God's demand.

2 Yet in our mind there is a law

Which always tries the good to do;

But in our members is a law

Which always doth this law subdue.

3 The law within our mind is good,

'Tis of our human life obtained

At our creation from the Lord,

That good behavior be maintained.

4 The law within our members is

The evil of satanic life;

Into our members at the fall

It came thru Satan's subtle strife.

5 This evil law of Satan is

The law of sin, in us its seat;

'Tis stronger than the law of good

And always brings it to defeat.

6 But in our spirit is a law,

Which is the Spirit's law of life;

'Tis of the very life of God

Which we from our rebirth derive.

7 This law divine the strongest is,

Transcending all the others o'er;

From sin's law freeing, it fulfills

The full requirement of God's law.

8 We then must always set our mind

Upon the spirit deep within,

And not upon the things of flesh,

The body ruined by the sin.

9 To set the mind upon the flesh

Is sin and death and darkest night;

The mind upon the spirit set

Is life and peace and full of light.

10 This is the way of true release!

This is the way of victory!

Lord, may we in the spirit live,

And by the Spirit walk with Thee.

< E735 C531 K531 S307 >

1 The law of letters God defines,

It is His testimony true;

It shows how loving, holy, just,

Is God, with whom we have to do.

2 According to His nature shown

God's law requires that we must live,

That He our souls may justify

And unto us His blessing give.

3 The law can never give us life,

Nor any strength to us supply,

But doth its full demands exact

And all our weakness show thereby.

4 It was not for God's final plan,

But for man's sin was introduced,

That man by breaking it might know

Himself, his sin to him adduced.

5 'Tis by the law all mouths are stopped

And all are shut up under sin;

It brings us to the Christ of God

That God may bless us all in Him.

6 The law is but a type of Christ,

Who God's full testimony is,

Who fully has expressed His love,

His holiness and righteousness.

7 'Tis Christ, God's testimony real,

Who doth with life divine supply,

That with the law's demands we may

Be more than able to comply.

8 God's living testimony, He;

By whom God's potent life we share;

Thru Him we're dead unto the law,

And in His Spirit fruit we bear.

< E736 C532 K532 S308 >

1 In ancient times the law of God

In letter was engraved on stone;

But now it is a law of life,

Which in our heart is written down.

2 The law in letters good demands

And thus our utter weakness shows;

But now the law of life sustains,

And strength for God to please bestows.

3 The law in letters brings to us

God's knowledge only outwardly;

But now the law of life supplies

A deeper knowledge inwardly.

4 The law in letters can but rule

By dead commandments outwardly;

But now the law of life controls

By living knowledge inwardly.

5 This living law is moving now

In all of our experience,

To regulate us from within

And check us by our inner sense.

6 How deep its regulation is

Within the inmost part of us,

A living consciousness to give,

And God Himself impart to us.

7 'Tis by this living law of life

We need no teaching outwardly,

For all God's living knowledge now

This law will teach us inwardly.

8 Lord, teach us by this law to walk,

Its inner ruling to obey,

That we may of Thyself partake

And know Thee in a living way.

< E742 C537 K537 S314 >

1 Man is a being of three parts,

The body, soul, and spirit too,

Th' eternal purpose to fulfill

With God's inheritance in view.

2 The body is the outward part

That man a world-sense may possess;

Thus he may touch the outward things

And bodily himself express.

3 The soul within - the inward part -

Is but the very self of man;

The sense of self it gives to him

To touch the psychic world of man.

4 The spirit is the inmost part

With which the Lord he may receive;

The sense of God it gives to man

That he the spirit-world perceive.

5 Within the soul of man there are

The mind, emotion, and the will;

These are the functions for the man

His human nature to fulfill.

6 Within the spirit of the man

Are found the conscience, fellowship,

And intuition, which thereby

The man to worship God equip.

7 The man must exercise his soul

To choose that God he may possess,

And by his spirit God partake,

And thru his body God express.

8 Man's spirit had to be reborn

With life divine to him conveyed;

His soul must be transformed by God,

His body like Christ's body made.

9 'Tis by these steps of work divine

In each of man's three separate parts

That man is mingled with the Lord

And His expression full imparts.

< E749 C545 K545 S322 >

1 The Spirit of the triune God

Within our spirit now doth rest;

He ever seeks thru us to flow,

That God in Christ may be expressed.

2 But by the outward, natural man

The Spirit is confined within;

Instead of giving Him a home,

A prison we've become to Him.

3 He's like a treasure of great worth

Contained in vessels earthen-made;

The vessel must be broken through

And thus the treasure be displayed.

4 Oh, how the Lord our self must break,

Our outward man does so impede!

It must be broken thoroughly,

And thus the Spirit will be freed.

5 This is the reason why the Lord

For us a certain measure makes

Of circumstantial suffering;

'Tis thus our outward man He breaks.

6 The outward man, the self, the soul,

Must be consumed, must be decreased;

The inner man, our spirit, then

Shall with the Spirit be released.

7 Lord, grant Thy holy brokenness,

Deliver me from being whole;

And make me willing to receive

The wounds that Thou wouldst give my soul.

8 Oh, cause me to appreciate

Thy breaking, never to complain;

And grant that I may value more

All kinds of loss instead of gain.

< E756 C- K- S- >

1 When Christ of old with healing pow'r

When forth through all the suffering land,

His word so oft was wont to be,

"Stretch forth thy hand, stretch forth thy hand!"

And though the palsied arm might shrink

And tremble at the strange command,

The healing touch was only felt

While stretching forth the withered hand.

O suffering one, stretch forth your hand,

Upon His promise take your stand.

At His command stretch forth your hand,

And Christ shall make you whole.

2 That changeless Christ is still as near

And just as kind and strong to save;

He came to lift our fallen race

From sin and sickness and the grave.

As in the days of Galilee,

Disease still flees at His command;

But ere His touch your frame can feel,

You, too, must still stretch forth your hand.

3 What though you feel so weak and faint?

He can your will with strength endue,

New faith and courage breathe within

And work in you to will and do.

Reach out to meet His quickening touch;

Take up your bed, arise and stand;

And pressing through to meet your Lord,

Stretch forth your hand, stretch forth your hand.

< E758 C- K- S- >

1 Have you found the great Physician,

Jesus Christ of Galilee?

He who bore our pain and sorrow,

On the shameful, cruel tree?

Still He heals the sick and suff'ring,

As before He went away;

For His word most plainly tells us,

"He is just the same today."

He is just the same today;

As before He went away.

Look to Him, believe and pray;

Trust His word and then obey.

"Praise God, He is just the same today."

2 Consecrate your life to Jesus,

Spirit, soul, and body too;

For "the Lord is for the body,"

Every pow'r He gave to you.

Let there be no reservation,

Give the Lord full right of way;

He will come and heal His temple,

For He is the same today.

3 Do you doubt God's will to heal you?

Take His word and ask for light;

If you seek in deep contrition,

He will guide your heart aright.

Do you fear to claim His promise,

He will not your trust betray;

When on earth He gladly healed them,

And He is the same today.

4 Oh! I'm glad to tell you, suff'rer,

Christ has more than healing too;

Life abundant overflowing,

He will gladly give to you.

Step out boldly, claim His fulness,

Let your sadness flee away;

When on earth He made them joyful,

And He is the same today.

< E762 C552 K552 S- >

1 Prayer is the incense of a holy heart

Rising to God from bruised and broken things,

When kindled by the Spirit's burning breath

And upward borne by faith's burning breath

And upward borne by faith's ascending wings.

2 Prayer is the perfume of the plants of grace,

The flowers of patience, faith, and suffering love;

Treasured in "vials full of odors sweet,"

God breathes their fragrance in His courts above.

3 Prayer is th' ascending vapor which supplies

The showers of blessing, and the stream that flows

Through earth's dry places, till on every side

"The wilderness shall blossom as the rose."

4 Prayer is the heavenly telephone that brings

The distant near, till heaven to earth comes down,

And in our Father's ear and heart we may

Our burdens tell and all our sorrows drown.

5 Prayer is the wireless telegraph that sends

Its heart throbs on the ether waves of heaven;

It finds the heart of God, and back to earth

The answering thrill to faith and love are given.

6 Prayer is the golden pipes the Spirit fills,

Which feed the lamps of God with oil divine,

And, as with one accord we wait and pray,

The Spirit fills, the lamps with brightness shine.

7 Prayer is the mightiest force of earth and heaven,

Prayer is the very dynamite of God;

It moves the hand that all things moves, and turns

The living wheels that sweep through earth abroad.

8 Teach us to pray! Move on our hearts, O Lord,

Till Thine own passion all our being move!

Teach us! Pray in us, till our prayer shall be

Christ in us praying to the Christ above!

9 Teach us to pray! Reveal Thy will to us,

Till Thine own purpose all our being move!

Teach us! Pray in us, till our prayer shall be

God in us answering to the God above!

< E764 C553 K553 S326 >

1 Lord, in Thy presence silent I would be,

That in the inmost I to Thee may come;

I would not in my own way pray to Thee,

But let Thy prayer in me my prayer become.

2 It seems Thou art in heaven hearing me,

But right within my spirit Thou dost dwell;

It seems that I am praying unto Thee,

But really from Thyself the prayers do well.

3 When, Lord, no words my burden can express,

My spirit with Thy Spirit deeply groans;

Not verbally I then my plea address,

But Thou dost pray within with words unknown.

4 I would inhale Thee, Lord, e'en as I breathe,

And eat and drink Thee as my life supply.

A deeper fellowship with Thee bequeath

That Thou express Thyself through me thereby.

5 Here in this fellowship Thy light doth shine,

Thy precious blood doth cleanse and make me clean;

May I not only, Lord, Thy light enshrine,

But may Thou be expressed and clearly seen.

6 Thy oil anoints me here in every way,

Anointing Thee within unceasingly;

I more decrease, Thou more increase each day,

Thus full expression Thou shalt have through me.

7 Myself I open that Thou may flow in;

Op'ning myself to others, Lord, flow out;

By such a stream, the fellowship within,

Thou, Lord, expressed will be my life throughout.

< E769 C556 K556 S327 >

1 To the holiest place I'd come,

There within the veil to be;

There to touch the throne of grace,

Let life's water flow thru me.

2 Now the holiest place of all

Right within my spirit is;

Here the Lord in me abides,

And my spirit joins with His.

3 To my spirit I'd return,

For 'tis here the Lord I'll meet;

O how marvellous it is!

He's within, in me complete.

4 Fragrance of the risen Christ

Thru my spirit may be spread;

If in spirit I will pray

Christ will be exhibited.

5 If in spirit Him I touch,

With His riches filled I'll be;

Life and light and love and grace

As a stream will flow thru me.

6 Touching deeply, richly I

Of Himself experience,

Thus the law of life I touch

And His clear anointing sense.

7 In my spirit deeper still

I would touch the Lord I love,

Touch Him in His hidden depth

And His hidden manna prove.

8 When the resurrection life

Is made real in pow'r to me,

As the rod with sprouting buds,

I will then accepted be.

9 Here I find the throne of grace,

Where the living water flows

As a river full of grace

Into me grace to bestow.

10 Then whene'er we meet to pray,

All our spirits we'll release;

Mingled will our spirits be,

And we'll serve the Lord as priests.

11 This the holiest place is too,

Where we all may touch the Lord,

Touch His throne in many ways

Till His grace on us is poured.

< E777 C560 K560 S- >

1 Say to this mountain, "Go,

Be cast into the sea!"

And doubt not in thine heart

That it shall be to thee.

It shall be done, doubt not His Word,

Command thy mountain in the Lord!

2 Claim thy redemption right,

Purchased by precious blood;

The Trinity unite

To make it true and good.

It shall be done, obey the Word,

Command thy mountain in the Lord!

3 Self, sickness, sorrow, sin,

The Lord did meet that day

One His beloved One,

And thou art "loosed away."

It shall be done, rest on His Word!

Command thy mountain in the Lord!

4 Compass the frowning wall

With silent prayer, then raise -

Before its ramparts fall -

The victor's shout of praise.

It shall be done, faith rests assured,

Command thy mountain in the Lord!

5 The two-leaved gates of brass,

The bars of iron yield,

To let the faithful pass,

Conquerors in every field.

It shall be done, the foe ignored,

Command thy mountain in the Lord!

6 Take then the faith of God,

Free from the taint of doubt;

The wonder-working rod

That casts all reasoning out.

It shall be done, stand on the Word.

Command thy mountain in the Lord!

< E791 C573 K573 S- >

1 The priest's position holy is;

He sacrifices e'er to God,

Beholds His beauty, incense burns

Of prayer before the Lord.

Let us the incense burn

Of prayer before the Lord;

The lamp we'd light, through day and night

Our praise to Him outpoured.

2 No natural light, but just the lamp

Within the holy place gives sight;

Whene'er the priest the incense burns,

The lamp he too must light.

3 The grace of God let us extol

And stir our heart sweet praise to sing;

For priests not only light the lamp,

But constant praises bring.

4 I'll offer prayers as incense burns,

Christ's resurrection bring therein,

God's wish thus meet, His heart give joy,

And I'll rejoice with Him.

5 I'll read His Word, His light receive,

E'en as the lamp before Him lit,

His holy light illum'ning me

To others I'll transmit.

6 Unto the Lord His praise I'll sing

As holy priests their songs did raise;

O may my heart be filled with Him

His love and grace to praise.

7 I'll offer Christ to God in prayer,

I'll read the Word, His light to know,

For all His grace I'll sing His praise,

The Spirit then may flow.

< E793 C575 K575 S- >

1 My soul, be silent, wait upon the Lord!

First let Him speak to thee, then speak to Him;

True prayer in thee the Lord initiates,

Thou but a channel art expressing Him.

2 My soul, be silent, wait upon the Lord!

Learn to deny thy thought and all thy will.

Learn to let God anoint thee with Himself

And thru thy prayer His purposes fulfill.

3 My soul, be silent, wait upon the Lord!

Silent to all thy wishes and thy plans,

Silent to all thy earthly cares and calls,

That God may work in thee all His demands.

4 My soul, be silent, wait upon the Lord!

Yield to the spirit all thy heart and mind;

Here let the spirit show what God reveals,

Thee its obedient servant thus to find.

5 My soul, be silent, wait upon the Lord!

Learn thus to let the Spirit pray thru thee;

All of thy being with the Spirit move,

Thy prayer will thus God's own expression be.

6 My soul, be silent, wait upon the Lord!

Till in the spirit thou with God art one,

Till thru the spirit God possesses all

And thus transforms each part unto His Son.

7 My soul, be silent, wait upon the Lord!

Till God may freely, fully flow thru thee,

Till all thy words and actions hour by hour

Are the fulfillment of God's will thru thee.

< E794 C- K- S- >

1 Stir me, oh, stir me, Lord, I care not how,

But stir my heart in passion for the world,

Stir me to give, to go, but most to pray;

Stir till the blood-red banner be unfurled

O'er lands that still in heathen darkness lie,

O'er deserts where no cross is lifted high.

2 Stir me, oh, stir me, Lord, till all my heart

Is filled with strong compassion for these souls;

Till Thy compelling word drives me to pray;

Till Thy constraining love reach to the poles

Far north and south, in burning deep desire,

Till east and west are caught in love's great fire.

3 Stir me, oh, stir me, Lord, till prayer is pain,

Till prayer is joy, till prayer turns into praise;

Stir me, till heart and will and mind, yea, all

Is wholly Thine to use through all the days.

Stir, till I learn to pray exceedingly;

Stir, till I learn to wait expectantly.

4 Stir me, oh, stir me, Lord, Thy heart was stirred

By love's intensest fire, till Thou didst give

Thine only Son, Thy best beloved One,

E'en to the dreadful cross, that I might live.

Stir me to give myself so back to Thee,

That Thou canst give Thyself again through me.

5 Stir me, oh, stir me, Lord, for I can see

Thy glorious triumph-day begin to break;

The dawn already gilds the eastern sky;

Oh, Church of Christ, arise, awake, awake.

Oh! stir us, Lord, as heralds of that day.

For night is past, our King is on His way.

< E802 C582 K582 S341 >

1 Thou art the Word and Spirit, Lord;

Now in one spirit worship we;

'Tis by the Word we understand,

And in the Spirit contact Thee.

2 Since Thou with me has joined in one,

Thou art my all, O Lord, thereby;

And as the Spirit and the Word

Thou cam'st to me as my supply.

3 If Thou art Lord, yet not the Word,

How couldest Thou be know to me?

If Thou art God yet Spirit not,

How could I ever contact Thee?

4 The Word reveals Thyself to me

And knowledge of Thyself imparts;

The Spirit is Thy substance true

Whereby I touch Thee as Thou art.

5 Thou art my life, my light, my way,

My food, my strength and guaranty;

By Word made known, as Spirit these

Become experience to me.

6 The Word in Scripture is expressed,

Thy Spirit, the Indwelling One;

Thy Word is spirit and is life

When to my spirit it doth come.

7 If I Thy Word would understand,

I must Thy Holy Spirit touch;

Not only grasp it with my mind,

But with my spirit, praying much.

8 Thy precious Word my heart doth love,

My spirit fellowships with Thine;

My heart rejoices in Thy Word,

My spirit praises sings in Thine.

< E811 C586 K586 S343 >

1 My heart is hungry, my spirit doth thirst;

I come to Thee, Lord, to seek Thy supply;

All that I need is none other but Thee,

Thou canst my hunger and thirst satisfy.

Feed me, Lord Jesus, give me to drink,

Fill all my hunger, quench all my thirst;

Flood me with joy, be the strength of my life,

Fill all my hunger, quench all my thirst.

2 Thou art the food and the water of life,

Thou canst revive me, my spirit upbear;

I long to eat and to drink here of Thee,

Thyself enjoy through my reading and prayer.

3 Thou art the Word with God's fulness in Thee,

Thou too the Spirit that God my life be;

Thee in the Word I enjoy as my food,

Thou as the Spirit art water to me.

4 Thou from the heavens as food camest down,

Thou to be drink hast been smitten for me;

Thou as the food, my exhaustless supply,

Thou as the water, a stream unto me.

5 Thou in the Word art the Spirit and life,

Thus by the Word I may feed upon Thee;

Thou dost as Spirit in my spirit live,

Thus I may drink in the spirit of Thee.

6 Now to enjoy Thee I come to Thy Word,

On Thee to feed till my hunger is o'er.

Now in my spirit I turn unto Thee,

Of Thee to drink till I'm thirsty no more.

7 Feeding and drinking, Lord Jesus, of Thee,

Feeding by reading, and drinking by prayer;

Reading and praying, I eat and I drink,

Praying and reading - Lord, Thou art my fare.

8 Here, O my Lord, may I feast upon Thee;

Flood with Thy Spirit and fill by Thy Word;

May, Lord, Thou be such a feast unto me

As man hath never enjoyed nor e'er heard.

< E813 C587 K587 S345 >

1 I come before Thy throne of grace

With hungry heart on Thee to feed,

Thy grace and mercy to receive

To help me in this hour of need.

2 Here I behold Thy radiant face,

Its light upon my heart doth shine

With healing rays consuming all

The weaknesses and faults of mine.

3 'Tis here Thy light illuminates

My true condition unto me;

'Tis here Thy blood's effectiveness

To cleanse from sin I gladly see.

4 Thy Spirit too anoints me here

And makes Thy very substance mine;

Thy very self I thus enjoy

And know Thy very heart's design.

5 Thy Word I read before Thee here

E'en as the priests the lamp did light;

Thy Spirit is as oil to me

To light Thy Word and give me sight.

6 E'en as the priests the incense burned,

In prayer to Thee I persevere;

As incense Thou the Spirit art

Mixed with the prayer I offer here.

7 Thy Word is light, Thy Word is food;

Which doth enlighten and supply;

I long to read and feed much more,

For light and food to satisfy.

8 Thou art the living water too

Which full revival doth bestow;

I wish to pray and drink e'en more

That through me living rivers flow.

9 Thou art the incense unto God,

In Thee acceptance is complete;

I want to pray yet more and more,

To offer up this fragrance sweet.

10 By reading I'm enlightened, filled,

By prayer my thirst is quenched indeed;

Thus Thou to me may be supplied,

And Thou through me may meet the need.

11 I long to have such fellowship,

To read and pray and blend with Thee;

I long that Thou wouldst saturate

Till Thou may overflow from me.

< E814 C589 K589 S346 >

1 "Man shall not live by bread alone,

But by each word which doth proceed

From God's own mouth"; these we must eat

And let them be our life indeed.

2 Not just a body we were made,

But body, soul, and spirit too;

The inmost part the spirit is

To contact God and Him pursue.

3 Just as we need the earthly food

Our body's need to satisfy,

We need the food for spirit too -

Thyself, Thy Word, its true supply.

4 Thou art the Spirit, and Thy Word

Thy very Self expressed doth make;

Thus, it is Spirit as Thyself,

Which by our spirit we must take.

5 Thus, to receive Thy Word is not

To read it only with our eyes

And understand it in our mind,

But 'tis the spirit's exercise.

6 Thy Word in spirit we must eat

And to our inmost part receive;

'Tis by our spirit's exercise

To pray with what our minds perceive.

7 Thy Word remaining in our mind

Is only knowledge burdensome,

But when it to the spirit goes

Then life and spirit it becomes.

8 'Tis only when our spirit acts

To take Thy Word and contact Thee,

We truly feed upon Thy Word

And touch Thyself most inwardly.

9 Lord, teach us how to exercise

Our spirit when Thy Word we read;

Then will our spirit nourished be

As thus upon Thyself we feed.

< E817 C- K- S- >

1 We limit not the truth of God

To our poor reach of mind,

By notions of our day and sect,

Crude, partial and confined.

Now let a new and better hope

Within our hearts be stirred:

The Lord hath yet more light and truth

To break forth from His Word.

2 Who dares to bind by his dull sense

The oracles of heaven,

For all the nations, tongues and climes

And all the ages given!

The universe how much unknown!

That ocean unexplored!

The Lord hath yet more light and truth

To break forth from His Word.

3 Darkling our great forefathers went

The first steps of the way;

'Twas but the dawning yet to grow

Into the perfect day;

And grow it shall, our glorious Sun

More fervid rays afford:

The Lord hath yet more light and truth

To break forth from His Word.

4 The valleys past, ascending still,

Our souls would higher climb,

And look down from supernal heights,

On all the bygone times;

Upward we press, the air is clear,

And the sphere-music heard!

The Lord hath yet more light and truth

To break forth from His Word.

5 O Father, Son and Spirit, send

Us increase from above;

Enlarge, expand all Christian hearts

To comprehend Thy love;

And make us all go on to know

With nobler powers conferred:

The Lord hath yet more light and truth

To break forth from His Word.

< E821 C595 K595 S350 >

1 The Church the vessel is to Christ,

Him to contain and Him express,

Just as the human body doth

Man's life show forth, his life possess.

2 As was the temple to the ark,

Receptacle and resting-place;

So Christ the Church's content is,

And in the Church, Christ's dwelling-place.

3 As Christ is God's true mystery,

God to explain and God express;

So is the Church Christ's mystery,

Christ to explain and manifest.

4 The members of the Church of Christ

Are all primarily of clay;

They need to be transformed and made

Transparent, precious day by day.

5 By transformation they are built,

A vessel they to Christ afford;

His all-inclusiveness they hold;

Transparent, they express the Lord.

6 Thru all the transformation work

The triune God performs in them,

The Church a corporate vessel is

And like the new Jerusalem.

7 How precious she in each respect,

Transparent too in every phase;

Christ with God's fulness she contains,

Christ with God's glory she displays.

8 With Christ as life, with God as light,

And with the Spirit's living flow,

The triune God she manifests

For all the universe to know.

< E822 C596 K596 S- >

1 The Church the lampstand is to Christ,

Christ is the lamp with God as light;

The light divine from Christ doth shine,

The Church upholds its glory bright.

2 The light which shines within the lamp

Is God as life, unique, divine;

The stand must therefore be of gold

To match the glory which doth shine.

3 Amid the darkness of this age

The light of life divine doth beam

In many centers of mankind

Where Jesus' testimony's seen.

4 To be this testimony pure

"First love" to Christ the Church must keep;

Then from the "tree of life" she may

The overcomer's portion reap.

5 She must the persecution bear

That she the "crown of life" may gain;

Adult'ry spiritual o'ercome,

The "hidden manna" to obtain.

6 The deeds of "Jezebel" desert,

That she may rule the earth with might;

Defiling deadness overcome

To be arrayed in "garments white."

7 Like "Philadelphia" she must be

To keep Christ's word, confess His Name;

All "lukewarm" pride she must o'ercome

To feast with Him who overcame.

8 Thus will the Church be purified

To be the lampstand of pure gold,

To match the testimony pure,

The life of Jesus fit to hold.

9 The local churches here on earth

The lampstands in this age should be;

The glorious new Jerusalem

The lampstand in eternity.

10 The city as pure gold will be,

The final lampstand consummate;

Christ as the lamp she e'er will hold

And God's full light will radiate.

< E823 C597 K597 S- >

1 God before the world's foundation

Chose the Church in Christ the Son,

That the Church might share the sonship,

Holy, blameless, with Him one;

That the Church be His possession

With the Spirit as the seal,

Of our heritage the earnest

While His Son He does reveal.

2 To the throne Christ has ascended,

Far above all rule and power;

God has made Him Head o'er all things

To the Church, His Body here.

All in He ever filleth,

And His fulness is expressed

Through the Church, which is His Body

And His image manifests.

3 We, once dead in our offences,

Walking in the worldly course,

Lusts of flesh and mind fulfilling,

Satan and his hosts their source,

God with Christ has resurrected,

Seated in the heavenlies;

We, His masterpiece, created

In Christ Jesus, Him to please.

4 Jews and Gentiles are one body -

God His myst'ry has made known -

On apostles, prophets founded,

Jesus Christ the cornerstone;

We in Him are built together

For God's dwelling manifest,

Fitly framed by God the Spirit

For His pleasure and His rest.

5 In eternal ages purposed

That His wisdom be made known,

Was the Church, His hidden myst'ry,

Where the Son could make His home;

That the saints may all in spirit

Apprehend His boundlessness,

Know His love which passes knowledge,

All God's fulness to possess.

6 One in body, hope, and Spirit,

One in faith, one Lord, the Son,

One baptizing, with one Father,

That the Church may thus be one;

Christ to know in all His fulness,

Unto manhood be matured,

Ne'er by winds of doctrine carried,

Nor by cunning men allured.

7 Many gifts the Lord has given,

That His Body He may build,

That the saints may be perfected

And their ministry fulfilled.

Thus we must put off the old man

That we may put on the new;

Thus, renewed in mind and spirit,

We will bear God's image true.

8 Christ in love Himself has given

That the Church be sanctified,

Without blemish, spot, or wrinkle,

To become His glorious bride.

He does nourish her and cherish

As a man his body treats;

He and she become one body -

Thus the myst'ry very great.

9 Body, house, new man the Church is,

Bride, and temple, and yet more:

She's the army too which fighteth

All God's foe to triumph o'er.

She is clothed with all God's armor,

In His mighty strength is strong,

Standing in the Lord, resisting,

With all prayers she fighteth on.

< E824 C598 K598 S351 >

1 The Church is Christ's own Body,

The Father's dwelling-place,

The gathering of the called ones,

God blended with man's race;

Elect before creation,

Redeemed by Calv'ry's death,

Her character and standing

Of heaven, not of earth.

2 New man of new creation,

Born through her risen Lord,

Baptized in God the Spirit,

Made holy by His Word;

Christ is her life and content,

Himself her glorious Head;

She has ascended with Him

O'er all her foes to tread.

3 Christ is her one foundation,

None other man may lay;

All that she has, as Christ, is

Divine in every way;

Her members through the Spirit

Their death on Calv'ry own;

They're built in resurrection -

Gold, silver, precious stone.

4 One God, one Lord, one Spirit -

Her elements all one -

One faith, one hope, one baptism,

One Body in the Son;

The triune God is in her,

One Body members own,

By faith they are united,

In hope of glory shown.

5 From every tribe and nation

Do all the members come,

Regardless of their classes

United to be one.

No high there is, nor lowly,

No Jew, nor Gentile clan,

No free, nor slave, nor master,

But Christ, the "one new man."

6 One Body universal,

One in each place expressed;

Locality of dwelling

Her only ground possessed;

Administration local,

Each answ'ring to the Lord;

Communion universal,

Upheld in one accord.

7 Her local gatherings model

The New Jerusalem;

Its aspects and its details

Must show in all of them.

Christ is the Lamp that shineth,

With God within, the Light;

They are the lampstands bearing

His glorious Image bright.

< E828 C- K- S- >

1 The "churches" here below, so narrow bound,

Reach not the hungry throngs which us surround;

They run partway with truth, but miss the goal.

Earth-vision blurred and dim, their eyes doth hold -

But broken gleams have they of radiance gold;

Too dazzling is the splendor of the whole.

2 Brothers with brothers have not all one heart,

In wrath they turn away and walk apart,

Who from one stream of life had common birth.

What fight for forms! O'er doctrines what vain strife!

Instead together sharing God's one life,

Who worshipped is by heaven and by earth.

3 "Where is the truth?" I asked; for this I longed:

None answered right 'mid all the answering throng;

For ever side by side lay light and shade.

"Where is," I cried, "the one communion pure?

Where is the Church in which, clear-traced and sure,

The Spirit's very likeness is portrayed?"

4 So sought I long, and hopeless was my quest;

These eyes grew dim and blind and found no rest,

Till God's touch opened them, and I was freed.

I found the Spirit's Church in souls made one

In this, that they in troth to Christ had come -

His Bride, to follow where the cross may lead.

5 Thus when I see this small world's narrow thought,

Behold the brother not with brother brought,

Yet serving Christ - as each one deemeth right -

Ah, then a voice from realms of glory calls,

Where the last veil is rent and earthward falls,

And where God's love, eternal, burneth bright.

6 No more we put that query without end,

To which self-chosen church our feet did trend -

What doctrine we believed, what sacred rites.

In Christ we were in bonds that nought could break;

Who, by His cross and death, do all forsake,

Such as were far asunder He unites.

7 No longer does one heed mere formal phrase,

Or seek for others' creeds through winding maze,

For in Himself was truth made manifest.

And out of every tongue and every land

He formed one Church to meet His own demand -

His Body, where His fulness is expressed.

< E829 C599 K599 S- >

1 The Church's seed is nought by Christ Himself

Sown into human hearts as life, thereby

Growing as wheat, producing flour fine

For bread both God and man to satisfy.

2 But Satan hath the false believers sown

Among the saints as tares among the wheat,

To bring confusion and to hinder growth

That they may not fulfill God's plan complete.

3 The Church's life just as the herb must be,

Grown out of Christ, who is the mustard seed;

Hidden and transient, little on the earth,

But good for food the hungry ones to feed.

4 But Satan came and made the little herb

To change its nature and to change its form,

That fully grown it did a tree become

Where many evil ones may lodge and swarm.

5 Satan has also used the fallen "church"

Evil and heathen practice to include,

As leaven mingled with the meal of wheat,

Thus to corrupt its purity as food.

6 But Christ as life would so transform the saints

That they may be as pearl and precious stone,

As the materials suitable to build

Into His Church to make His Kingdom known.

7 Such an assembly grown in Christ as life,

Transformed and built with Christ in them annealed,

Is as the goodly pearl for preciousness

And as the treasure hidden in the field.

8 Lord, separate us from the devil's "tares,"

Each on deliver from the monstrous "tree,"

From all the "leaven" may Thou purify,

That we may be as food to man and Thee.

9 Cause us to grow in life divine each day

That we may be transformed and built by Thee

Into a body to express Thyself,

That Thou in us Thy Church and Kingdom see.

< E831 C600 K600 S353 >

1 The unity of the Church is but

The saints in oneness living;

The Spirit which indwelleth them

This oneness ever giving.

Thus it is realized and called

The unity of Spirit;

'Tis based upon the common faith

Which all the saints inherit.

2 This precious faith of all the saints,

Is constituted solely

Of Christ and His redemptive work,

Which are unique and holy.

In this the saints are truly one,

Together all agreeing,

And it is from this common faith

The Church came into being.

3 The Church within the universe

Is one as Christ's possession;

The Church must therefore locally

Be one in her expression;

For all her elements are one -

One God, one Lord, one Spirit,

One faith, baptism, Body too,

One hope all saints inherit.

4 This oneness is the Church's ground,

The ground of common standing,

The only ground of unity

The Spirit is demanding.

The Church in actual practise thus

May keep her vital union,

And her expressions locally

Be built up in communion.

5 Lord, help us ever strive to keep

This unity by taking

The Church's ground of unity,

The Body-life partaking,

That all Thy heart's profound desire

May fully be effected,

And God's eternal purpose may

Completely be perfected.

< E834 C602 K602 S- >

1 The chief Cornerstone Thou art, Lord,

Jewish builders did despise;

God by resurrection placed Thee,

Thou art precious in His eyes.

Through Thee we receive salvation,

And, together built by Thee,

Jews and Gentiles are Thy dwelling,

One new man, in harmony.

2 Thou too art the smitten Rock, Lord,

That man's thirst by Thee be filled,

That frail man may stand upon Thee,

But e'en more, God's house to build.

The Foundation Stone in Zion,

Tested and secure, Thou art;

And the Rock, the Church supporting,

Her foundation to impart.

3 On Thyself the Church is builded,

And though many storms assail,

Still it stands erect, for 'gainst it

Gates of hell cannot prevail.

Thine authority possessing,

It doth bind and loose in Thee,

Bringing men into Thy kingdom,

Satan's captives setting free.

4 Living Stone of life art Thou, Lord,

Precious, chosen thus to be;

Living stones Thou too hast made us,

One in character with Thee.

Built together as a temple

That our God may dwell therein,

Thus we are a holy priesthood,

Offering sacrifice to Him.

5 Lord, Thou art the Son of David

That God's temple Thou may build;

King and Priest Thou art together,

That Thy calling be fulfilled.

As the King, for God Thou rulest,

Making men submit to Him;

As the Priest before God's presence,

Bringing men to enter in.

6 Thine authority doth issue

From the throne to render peace;

Fellowship is in the river

To supply and give increase.

When these, balanced, go together,

Then God's purpose is fulfilled;

King and Priest in Thee combining,

Thou God's dwelling place dost build.

7 Thou art God, yet flesh becamest,

God with man in Thee doth dwell;

Thou, the Temple for His glory,

God in Thee Himself doth tell.

Thus the Church too is the mingling

Into one of God and man;

So it is with every member

For the building of God's plan.

8 Thou, the everlasting Dwelling,

In all ages art our home;

We in Thee enjoy protection,

Living in Thyself alone.

Thou our Sanctuary art, Lord,

We and God abide in Thee;

Thou, God's presence art within us,

Where we worship ceaselessly.

9 Cornerstone, Foundation, Topstone,

Rock, and Church, and Living Stone,

Dwelling-place, and Sanctuary,

Builder too art Thou, we own.

Praise we give for what Thou art, Lord,

As Thy wondrousness we see!

Grant that we may be built up, Lord,

As the living stones in Thee.

< E837 C603 K603 S356 >

1 We praise Thee, Lord, for Thy great plan

That we Thy dwelling-place may be;

Thou live in us, we filled with Thee,

Thou in the Son expressed might be.

2 Though in Thine image made by Thee

And given Thine authority,

Yet we are only made of clay

Without a trace of divinity.

3 When we receive Thee as our life,

Thy nature we thru grace possess;

Mingled together, we with Thee

One Body glorious will express.

4 When flows Thy life thru all our souls,

Filling, renewing every part,

We will be pearls and precious stones,

Changed to Thine image, as Thou art.

5 But, Lord, we fully realize

These are not wrought men's praise to rouse,

But as material to be built

Together for Thy glorious house.

6 Here, Lord, we give ourselves to Thee;

Receive us into Thy wise hands;

Bend, break, and build together in Thee

To be the house to meet Thy demands.

7 Break all the natural life for us,

Deal Thou with each peculiar way,

That we no more independent be

But with all saints are one for aye.

8 Then we shall be Thy Bride beloved,

Together in Thy chamber abide,

Enjoy the fulness of Thy love.

How Thou wilt then be satisfied!

< E838 C609 K609 S- >

1 Thy blueprint, Lord, I treasure dear,

It shows Thy tabernacle real,

It tells how Thou wouldst have it built,

How Thou Thy glory wouldst reveal.

2 The ark's the center of the tent,

The tent is but its resting-place:

In it the ten commandments are,

And in the tent it ever stays.

3 The ark the God-man, Christ, displays -

God mixed with man, as gold, wood meet;

The law is God's expression full,

Which dwells in Christ the Son complete.

4 Thus Christ's the center of the Church,

Which is to Him a resting-place;

In Christ the Father ever dwells,

And in the Church, Christ's dwelling-place.

5 The tent's the increase of the ark,

Both are of wood with gold o'erlaid;

The Church the increase is of Christ,

God blent with man here too displayed.

6 The boards when joined support the tent

On silver sockets standing sure;

Gold overlaid, with golden rings

And interlocking bars, secure.

7 The Church is thus the gathered saints,

On Christ's redemption standing sure;

In life divine, by Spirit bound,

Together built and framed secure.

8 The tent's four-layered cover shows

The Christ of God in every phase;

God's glory thus is signified,

Covering His holy dwelling-place.

9 Covered by such a glorious Christ,

All saints together knit may be;

Enjoying all He is for them,

In Him they're builded gloriously.

10 The law is placed within the ark,

The ark within the tent doth rest;

So God in Christ within the Church

His wondrous glory manifests.

< E839 C604 K604 S357 >

1 Lord, Thou art a potter skilled

And a glorious builder too,

Molding for Thy vessel great,

Building with Thy house in view.

I am both a man of clay

And a new-made living stone,

That Thy vessel I may be

And the temple Thou wouldst own.

2 Though of clay Thou madest us.

Thou wouldst have us be transformed;

With Thy life as purest gold,

Unto precious stones conformed.

We shall, through Thy building work,

Then become Thy loving Bride,

In one Body joined to Thee,

That Thy heart be satisfied.

3 What Thy heart desires and loves

Are not precious stones alone,

But together these to build

For Thy glory, for Thy home.

Thou, the all-inclusive Christ,

Dost a builded Church require,

That Thy glorious riches may

Radiate their light entire.

4 Not the person spiritual

In an individual way,

But the corporate life expressed

Will Thy heart's desire display.

Members separate and detached

Ne'er express Thee perfectly,

But Thy Body tempered, built,

Ever shall Thy fulness be.

5 Build me, Lord, with other saints,

Independence ne'er allow,

But according to Thy plan

Fitly frame and join me now.

In experience not my boast,

Nor in gifts would be my pride;

For Thy building I give all,

That Thou may be glorified.

< E848 C612 K612 S363 >

1 What a blessing, what a priv'lege!

Called of God a royal priest,

That this glorious, holy office

I should bear, though last and least.

All the building of the Body

On the priesthood doth depend;

Ever praying in the spirit

I this office would attend.

2 If I keep this royal calling

Under Thine authority,

Priestly duty thus fulfilling,

Then the church will builded be.

3 Now the church is but the priesthood;

Thus the priesthood formed we need;

When the priests are knit together,

Then the church is built indeed.

4 Through the church's degradation,

Saints this office desolate;

Through the weakness of their spirits

Preaching doth predominate.

5 Most are leaning on the message

And the preaching emphasize,

Yet neglect the priestly praying

And their spirits' exercise.

6 Deal with me and make me balanced,

As in preaching, so in prayer;

Leading others oft in praying,

As Thy Word I too declare.

7 Only serving by our praying

Will our spirits mingled be;

Stressing prayer as much as preaching -

Thus the church is built for Thee.

< E849 C613 K613 S- >

1 Holy priests are living stones

For God's building work today;

If these stones would builded be

All the priests must learn to pray.

To the holiest often come,

In the spirit touch the throne,

Let the Lord flow thru in prayer,

Thus the building work is done.

2 All the saints must serve as priests,

That the living stones they be;

Each must priestly work perform,

Then their functions we will see.

3 Tent and priests of olden times

Always did together go;

When the priests served in the tent,

Into one the two did flow.

4 Now the building spiritual

And the priesthood all are one;

Now the building of the house

By the priestly work is done.

5 In the priests the substance is

Of the building work replete;

When the priests their work discharge,

Then God's house will be complete.

6 Building God and man in one

Is their work before the Lord;

In this fellowship divine

Saints are built in one accord.

7 When in prayer our spirits blend,

Then together built are we,

Then a priesthood we become,

Off'ring sacrifice to Thee.

8 Grant us grace, O Lord, that we

Treasure dear the priestly call;

In the spirit serve and pray,

That Thy church be built withal.

< E851 C615 K615 S364 >

1 How lovely is Thy dwelling-place!

Within Thy courts I long to be;

Thy presence, Lord, my spirit craves,

For this my heart cries out to Thee.

2 At Thy burnt-offering altar, Lord,

And at Thine incense altar blest,

Even the sparrow finds a home,

And swallow there prepares her nest.

3 Men, as the sparrow, frail and small,

When living in Thy house find rest,

Relying on the altar's blood,

Enjoying there the incense blest.

4 How blessed are those men indeed!

Trusting in Thee they are made strong;

Highways to Zion in their hearts,

The way they care not, rough or long.

5 Passing the weeping valley they

Make it a place of springing wells;

The rain with blessings covers it

And in the way God's mercy tells.

6 From strength to strength they go, and all

Before the Lord in Zion meet;

Thus ever seeking Thine own self,

They need Thy care and grace replete.

7 Better a day within Thy courts

Than days a thousand I would tell;

I'd rather at Thy threshold stand

Than in the wicked's tents to dwell.

8 Thou art a sun, Thou art a shield,

Thou grace and glory wilt supply;

Thy presence and Thy very self

My need in fulness satisfy.

9 Not one good thing wilt Thou withhold

From those who walk in uprightness;

Bless'd is the man that trusts in Thee

With grace and glory measureless.

< E864 C624 K624 S391 >

1 Whene'er we meet with Christ endued,

The surplus of His plenitude

We offer unto God as food,

And thus exhibit Christ.

Let us exhibit Christ,

Let us exhibit Christ;

We'll bring His surplus to the church

And thus exhibit Christ.

2 In Christ we live, by Christ we fight,

On Christ we labor day and night,

And with His surplus we unite

To thus exhibit Christ.

3 Our life and all we are and do

Is Christ Himself, the substance true,

That every time we meet anew

We may exhibit Christ.

4 In meetings Christ to God we bear

And Christ with one another share,

And Christ with God enjoying there,

We thus exhibit Christ.

5 The risen Christ to God we bring,

And Christ ascended offering,

God's satisfaction answering,

We thus exhibit Christ.

6 The center and reality,

The atmosphere and ministry,

Of all our meetings is that we

May thus exhibit Christ.

7 The testimony and the prayer,

And all the fellowship we share,

The exercise of gifts, whate'er,

Should just exhibit Christ.

8 The Father we would glorify,

Exalting Christ the Son, thereby

The meeting's purpose satisfy

That we exhibit Christ.

< E873 C634 K634 S- >

1 Charge, soldiers, charge in battle!

The conflict has begun;

Thy battle song triumphant -

"The victory is won!"

Hell's power must be vanquished

And Satan's forces strewn;

The Captain of the Army

Will come and triumph soon.

2 Charge, soldiers, charge in battle!

And gaze upon thy Lord;

If thou wilt fight His battle,

The throne is thy reward.

This war is of the spirit,

Not fought on earthly ground;

The Lord well knows the foe is near,

Encircling us around.

3 Charge, soldiers, charge in battle!

Christ's throne awaiteth thee;

His resurrection power

Will lift thy spirit free.

Through Him thou wilt have power,

The foe to battle down;

Through Him thou wilt the triumph sing,

And wear the victor's crown.

4 Charge, soldiers, charge in battle!

Thou shalt ascend the throne;

A feast He is preparing,

How happy thou to own.

With Him we're resurrected

Above the battle din;

Transcending all that binds us,

We're far above in Him.

5 Charge, soldiers, charge in battle!

Thou art the royal heir;

The Lord from dust did choose thee,

That thou His kingdom share.

Thou hast no part in darkness,

Thy future, O how bright;

With Christ to dwell forever

And in His love delight.

6 With joyful shouts charge forward!

The kingdom is before;

Upon the peak of Zion

We'll sing, the battle o'er.

The Lamb has won the victory!

The Lamb is on the throne!

With shouts of joy we praise Him,

For He must overcome.

< E882 C- K- S397 >

1 Encamped along the hills of light,

Ye Christian soldiers rise,

And press the battle ere the night

Shall veil the glowing skies;

Against the foe in vales below

Let all our strength be hurled;

Faith is the victory, we know,

That overcomes the world.

Faith is the victory!

Faith is the victory!

O glorious victory,

That overcomes the world.

2 His banner over us is love,

Our sword the Word of God;

We tread the road the saints before

With shouts of triumph trod.

By faith, they like a whirlwind's breath,

Swept on o'er every field;

The faith by which they conquered death

Is still our shining shield.

3 On every hand the foe we find

Drawn up in dread array;

Let tents of ease be left behind,

And onward to the fray.

Salvation's helmet on each head,

With truth all girt about,

The earth shall tremble 'neath our tread,

And echo with our shout.

4 To him that overcomes the foe,

White raiment shall be giv'n;

Before the angels he shall know

His name confessed in heav'n;

Then onward from the hills of light,

Our hearts with love aflame,

We'll vanquish all the hosts of night,

In Jesus' conqu'ring name.

< E887 C642 K642 S- >

1 The name of Jesus is our stand,

It is our victory;

Not on ourselves do we rely,

But, mighty Lord, on Thee.

Our weapons are not arms of flesh,

But ours the Spirit's sword,

And God's whole armor putting on,

We battle in the Lord.

2 Behold, the foe doth meet and plot,

Stand firm in one accord!

Though war be fierce and darkness thick,

Resist him in the Lord!

If one thru fear should backward turn,

He undermines the rest.

Oh, do not let your brothers down,

Nor by you be distressed.

3 The devil knows his time is short,

He is the more enraged,

And by his wiles would weaken us

Before the battle's waged.

The trials now more numerous are,

The suff'ring e'en more sore,

The force of hell opposing us

More dreadful than before.

4 What should our posture be today

In such a desperate hour?

Should we our ease and pleasure seek

And let the foe devour?

Or with increasing conflict strong,

Courageous to endure?

'Tis here that life or death is won!

Who will God's praise secure?

5 For Christ the Lord we then would stand,

He is the Conqueror!

For Him we would endure the pain

Until the fight is o'er.

The hour of triumph soon we'll see -

The Lord will come again;

If now we suffer for His sake,

Then we with Him shall reign.

< E893 C641 K641 S402 >

1 Conflict today is fierce,

The strength of Satan more;

The cry of battle calling now

Is louder than before.

The rebel voice of hell

E'en stronger now becomes;

But list, the midnight cry resounds,

Behold, I quickly come!

2 Trials more bitter grow,

The fighting doth enlarge;

Hell's forces rally all their pow'rs

And gather for the charge.

Yet while we wait and watch

And feel the war severe,

We hear the joyful song ring out,

Jesus, the Lord, is near!

3 'Tis harder at the end

The word to testify,

For Satan fights with all his pow'r

Our witness to defy.

Much greater strength we need

The foe to overcome;

How happy when the Lord we see

And all our sighing's done!

4 Who then will forward go

Strong in His mighty power?

Who then will firmly trust the Lord

Until the vict'ry hour;

Till with the conqu'rors blest,

The triumph song's begun?

That man will then rejoice to hear,

Behold, I quickly come!

5 Who then will choose God's best,

And take the narrow track,

Though passing thru the wildest storms,

Yet never turning back?

Who now will dare press on,

Enduring pain and fear?

All such will then rejoice to see

Jesus, the Lord, is near!

6 Though deep the darkness be

We still would onward go,

Till we the day of rapture greet

And glory 'round shall glow.

'Tis there we'll see the Lord,

And Satan overcome;

The overcomers will rejoice,

Jesus, the Lord, has come!

< E904 C- K- S405 >

1 We have a most glorious King;

The heavens, He says, are His throne;

All worlds are His mighty domain,

All kingdoms His scepter shall own.

He dwells with His people below,

He loves in their trials to share;

We dwell with the King for His work,

His burden we willingly bear.

2 I'm dwelling with Jesus my King;

I've found where He dwells with His own;

I've opened the door of my heart;

He's made it His temple and throne.

Like Mary I sit at His feet,

Like John I recline on His breast;

His presence is fulness of joy,

His bosom is infinite rest.

3 I dwell with the King for His work,

I've part in His glorious plan

To bring in His kingdom to earth

And tell His salvation to man.

The world has its work and rewards,

I count them but folly and loss;

My business is only His work,

My message is only His cross.

4 I dwell with the King for His work,

The work, it is His and not mine;

He plans and prepares it for me

And fills me with power divine.

So duty is changed to delight,

And prayer into praise as I sing;

I dwell with my King for His work

And work in the strength of my King.

5 We'll dwell with the King for His work

And work thru each day of the year.

Perhaps ere it passes, the King

In glory Himself shall appear.

Oh, then in some closer embrace,

Oh, then in some nobler employ

We'll dwell with the King for His work

In endless, ineffable joy!

< E914 C658 K658 S412 >

1 For the Church should be our service,

'Tis the perfect will of God;

'Tis the only way of working

Which the Lord's apostles trod.

For the Church should be our service,

Not our aims to satisfy;

This the perfect will of God is,

And with it we must comply.

2 For 'tis God's eternal purpose

That the Church His vessel be;

He intends that all our service

Build His Church continually.

3 All the gifted persons given

To the Body by the Head

Are to aid the Church's building,

That to fulness she be led.

4 All the gifts and all the functions,

All the spirit's power shown,

All the ministries are given

For the Church and that alone.

5 All the preaching of the Gospel,

All the teaching ministry,

Every other kind of service

For the Church alone should be.

6 Ministry is for the Churches,

Not the Church for ministry;

All the lampstands are the Churches,

Not a form of ministry.

7 This will keep the Church's oneness,

Saving us from every sect;

This will ever test our motives,

And our aim will thus correct.

8 Lord, deliver us from our work,

From the work of any sect;

For Thy Church alone we'd labor

And its building up effect.

< E934 C- K- S- >

1 I cannot tell why He, whom angels worship,

Should set His love upon the sons of men,

Or why, as Shepherd, He should seek the wand'rers,

To bring them back, they know not how or when.

But this I know, that He was born of Mary,

When Bethl'hem's manger was His only home,

And that He lived at Nazareth and labored,

And so the Savior, Savior of the world, is come.

2 I cannot tell how silently He suffered,

As with His peace He graced this place of tears,

Or how His heart upon the Cross was broken,

The crown of pain to three and thirty years.

But this I know, He heals the broken-hearted,

And stays our sin, and calms our lurking fear,

And lifts the burden from the heavy laden,

For yet the Savior, Savior of the world, is here.

3 I cannot tell how He will win the nations,

How He will claim His earthly heritage,

How satisfy the needs and aspirations

Of east and west, of sinner and of sage.

But this I know, all flesh shall see His glory,

And He shall reap the harvest He has sown,

And some glad day His sun shall shine in splendor

When He the Savior, Savior of the world, is known.

4 I cannot tell how all the lands shall worship,

When, at His bidding, every storm is stilled,

Or who can say how great the jubilation

When all the hearts of men with love are filled.

But this I know, the skies will thrill with rapture,

And myriad, myriad human voices sing,

And earth to heaven, and heaven to earth, will answer:

At last the Savior, Savior of the world, is King.

< E941 C745 K745 S426 >

1 God's kingdom is God's reigning,

His glory to maintain;

It is His sovereign ruling,

His order to sustain.

He exercises fully

His own authority

Within His kingdom ever

And to eternity.

2 Upon the throne, the center

Of government divine,

God reigns, and with His purpose

Brings everything in line.

God's headship and His lordship

He only can maintain

As King within His kingdom,

O'er everything to reign.

3 By reigning in His kingdom

God worketh all His will,

And under His dominion

His purpose doth fulfill.

'Tis only in God's kingdom

His blessing we may know;

'Tis from His throne almighty

The stream of life doth flow.

4 Submitted to God's ruling,

All virtue thus will win;

Rebellion to His Headship

Is but the root of sin.

The evil aim of Satan -

God's throne to overthrow;

Our aim and goal is ever

His rule to fully know.

5 Within God's sovereign kingdom

His Christ is magnified;

When Christ in life is reigning,

The Father's glorified.

When God is in dominion,

All things are truly blessed;

When Christ for God is reigning,

God's glory is expressed.

6 In fulness of the seasons

God's Christ will head up all,

Then all will own His reigning

And worship, great and small.

Such reign in life and glory

The Church e'en now foretastes,

And to His rule submitting

Unto His kingdom hastes.

< E943 C747 K747 S428 >

1 Requirements of the Kingdom are

Much stricter than the law's decrees;

No other requisite of God

Has ever higher been than these.

2 "Repent, the Kingdom has come near,"

This is the Kingdom's first demand;

A change of mind we all must have

And on God's side must firmly stand.

3 That we the Kingdom enter in,

Surpassing righteousness we need,

Exceeding that which is of law;

From life alone it must proceed.

4 That we the Kingdom enter in,

We need to do the Father's will,

Not by our choice to work or act

But His one purpose to fulfill.

5 That we the Kingdom enter in,

A simple child we must become -

Adjustable, obedient, meek -

And everything of self o'ercome.

6 The Heav'nly Kingdom e'en requires

That we as God should perfect be;

This standard we must fully meet

That we may share its ecstasy.

7 The Kingdom is the reign of God

To match His nature is required;

'Tis only by the life of God

The Kingdom's entry is acquired.

8 The Kingdom is the rule of heav'n;

With heaven's state we must accord;

'Tis only by the life of heav'n

That we may share it with the Lord.

< E945 C750 K750 S430 >

1 The Son of God has come to sow

Himself, the seed of life, in man,

That thru Himself God's Kingdom grow

And thus fulfill th' eternal plan.

2 He was the only grain of wheat

Whence many grains have been produced

To be the Kingdom's children meet,

Thru whom God's reign is introduced.

3 But Satan, enemy of God,

Sowed many tares among the wheat,

The Kingdom's children to confuse,

And awful damage to create.

4 'Tis by this subtle work of his,

The mixing of the tares with wheat,

The Kingdom in appearance is

Abnormal and grotesquely great.

5 The Kingdom should as mustard be,

A little herb, yet good for food,

But it has changed into a "tree,"

A system of great magnitude.

6 Instead of being good for food,

A lodge of "birds" it has become;

'Tis now a place where evil men

And evil spirits make their home.

7 A great religion of the world

Its outward form to us reveals,

Including pagan, evil things,

As leaven mingled with the meal.

8 A system of the world as such,

It thus has changed in outward form;

By evil things which it imbibes,

Corruption inwardly doth swarm.

9 But something hidden God doth seek,

As "pearl" and "treasure in the field";

As such the Lord would us transform

That pearl and treasure be revealed.

10 'Tis hidden from vast Christendom

And from the Kingdom's great facade,

Yet in its full reality

'Tis transformed like to Christ and God.

11 Lord, separate us from the "tares,"

And save us from the monstrous "tree";

From all the "leaven" purge us now

That we may purely be of Thee.

12 May Thou in life transform our souls

That we as precious stones may be,

Meet for Thy house to build and in

Thy Kingdom's full reality.

< E946 C749 K749 S- >

1 Lo, the glory! Lo, the splendor!

Heaven's Kingdom manifest!

And its glorious King, our Master,

Is by God's appointment blest.

Once in flesh He came so lowly,

Hated and despised by man;

Now He comes again in glory

To fulfill the Kingdom plan.

2 Going to receive the Kingdom

From His God, the Ancient of Days,

Now He cometh with the Kingdom

And its glorious, ruling rays.

He's "the Stone" which breaks the nations

Into pieces lowliest,

Which "a mountain great" becometh

As the Kingdom manifest.

3 Lo, the earth, all lands and kingdoms,

By the Lord and Christ possessed;

Earth beneath their sovereign ruling

Will be full of peace and rest.

No more war and no more hatred

'Twixt the nations will there be;

But God's knowledge shall suffuse them

As the waters fill the sea.

4 All the Christian overcomers

Shall with Christ in glory reign,

And the remnant saved of Israel

Then God's priesthood shall obtain.

As God's people shall the nations

'Neath their rule and teaching be,

And a glorious restoration

All creation then shall see.

5 Satan will be bound and banished;

From his rule will earth be freed;

With Christ's sovereign reign and headship

Earth will then be blessed indeed.

All to Christ will then be subject,

To His pow'r and to His will;

As the Head and Center glorious,

He God's purpose will fulfill.

< E958 C758 K758 S438 >

1 Since long ago at Bethany we parted,

Within my heart there is a ceaseless void;

How can I take my harp down from the willow?

How can my songs without Thee be enjoyed?

And when at night I'm keeping lonely vigil -

Grown numb alike to sorrow and to cheer -

Then I recall the promise of Thy coming,

But sigh: O Lord, why, why Thou dost not yet appear?

2 Thy manger wakes the thought: I too am homeless;

Thy cross strips earthly pleasures from my soul;

Thy coming bids me seek a better country,

For Thou Thyself art now my final goal.

Since Thou art gone my joy has lost its flavor,

My song the sweetness I would fain convey.

Since Thou art gone the sense of void o'erwhelms me.

Oh, how I long that Thou wilt come and not delay.

3 Though even now I know Thy loving presence,

Yet in my heart there's still a sense of lack.

Enlightening and tenderest sustaining

Can no more satisfy: I want Thee back.

Despite Thy peace within, I still feel lonely;

Despite Thy joy there still remains a sigh;

When I feel most content, the silent yearning

To see Thee face to face becomes an uttered cry.

4 What exile cannot but desire his homeland

And long his people once again to greet?

What soul on alien soil forgets his kindred?

What parted lovers never yearn to meet?

O Lord, how can these earthly loves and pleasures

With all the joy of Thy return compare?

Then, if I cannot here behold Thy countenance,

What can I do but sigh till Thou, my Lord, appear?

5 Could'st Thou, O Lord, forget Thy word of promise

Soon to return and take me unto Thee?

Yet day by day and year by year I've waited

And still I wait, and no return I see!

Remember, Lord, the years I have been waiting

While Thy dear footsteps linger far away.

How long? How long? Oh! must I wait still longer

Till Thou shalt come again in glorious array?

6 From generation unto generation

Thy saints have come and gone, but have not seen

Thy glorious promise pass into fulfilment.

How long, how very long the time has been!

Why cannot we, dear Lord, discern Thy footsteps?

Why are the heavens still so closely sealed?

Oh! must our waiting be prolonged still further

Before Thou in Thy matchless splendor art revealed?

7 Lord, I recall the many years I've waited

For Thy return - yet, Lord, not I alone,

But Thy dear saints through many generations -

Beseeching Thee to come back for Thine own.

To countless tears and countless fervent pleadings,

By Thine appearing haste to make reply.

Oh, may Thou come, the echo of the ages,

Come, come and answer now this mighty corp'rate cry!

< E959 C760 K760 S- >

1 Since Thy departure from Olivet's Mountain,

Why is Thy coming again so delayed?

Thru the long years we have longed for Thy coming;

Hast Thou not heard all the prayers that we've prayed?

Come Thou, come now:

Lord, for Thy coming we yearn;

All our desire is Thy promised returning,

Oh, may Thou quickly return.

2 Beloved Lord, since the year Thou ascended

Everything here has been tasteless and dry;

Often in praying and often in watching,

In every movement, for Thee, Lord, we sigh.

3 Scenes although lovely, yet when will we meet Thee?

Birds and the flowers fair beauty embrace;

All are delightsome, but none satisfy me,

For I am longing for Thy loving face.

4 Lord, we're impatient awaiting Thy coming,

We do not know how much longer 'twill be;

From every sunrise to every bright sunset

Hope we each moment Thy coming to see.

5 Whene'er 'tis raining, or strong winds are blowing,

Whene'er the moon shines, or rises the sea,

We ever hope to discover Thy coming;

How disappointed when no sign of Thee!

6 If it were not for the bidding Thou gav'st us,

We'd be discouraged, Thy service we'd shirk;

But Thou dost want us while waiting Thy coming,

For Thee to live and in diligence work.

7 Oh Lord, remember the days have been lengthened

Since Thou hast promised ere going away;

We hope and hope and are endlessly hoping,

That Thou wilt come. Canst Thou come e'en today?

< E960 C756 K756 S439 >

1 My King will soon come back again,

The sky be filled with Him;

The universe to be redeemed

Will see His light therein.

The Lord will soon fulfill His plan,

His footsteps now I hear;

His glorious frame I faintly see

Beginning to appear.

2 I'm longing for His presence blest

And dare not slothful be

While waiting for my Lord's return,

His own dear self to see.

My only hope - that He may come

And change my faith to sight;

There is no other joy on earth

Which gives my heart delight.

3 My heart is always with Himself,

My eyes are heavenward,

My lips would utter nothing else

Than meeting with my Lord.

The coming of the Lord draws nigh,

His coming is for me;

His promise ever standeth firm

And soon fulfilled I'll see.

4 My Savior, all Thy holy words

Can never doubted be;

With them encouraged day by day,

I'm faithful unto Thee.

Oh, may Thy glory soon appear,

The foe be overthrown;

Thy promises be realized,

And we brought to Thy throne.

5 Thy saving arm a refuge is,

My Savior God, to me;

Thou as the father keepeth them

Who put their trust in Thee.

The sheep and shepherd are of one,

The head and body same;

None e'er can pluck from out Thy hand

The child who trusts Thy Name.

6 A thousand hands won't hinder me,

Nor will ten thousand eyes;

The thorns upon the road but help

Me onward to the prize.

Arise, my spirit and my heart,

And let the world go by;

The Lord of life will take me soon

To be with Him on high.

7 Thou healing sun! Thou hope of man!

I really love Thy ray.

Oh, righteous Lord! Oh, glorious King!

I bow to Thee and pray:

Oh, may Thou soon ascend Thy throne

And quickly show Thy face;

Thy heav'nly kingdom may Thou found

And grant all men Thy grace.

8 The truth should triumph and be king,

And freedom should be queen;

But falsehood, which has rampant run,

Head of the world is seen.

We ask Thee, Truth, to quickly come

And bring Thy light from heav'n;

The foe be crushed and all Thy sons

Into Thy bosom giv'n.

< E961 C- K- S- >

1 The Church has waited long,

Her absent Lord to see,

And still in loneliness she waits,

A friendless stranger she.

Age after age had gone,

Sun after sun has set,

And still in weeds of widowhood,

She weeps a mourner yet.

2 Saint after saint on earth

Has lived, and loved, and died;

And as they left us one by one,

We laid them side by side;

We laid them down to sleep,

But not in hope forlorn;

We laid them but to ripen there,

Till the last glorious morn.

3 The serpent's brood increase,

The powers of hell grow bold,

The conflict thickens, faith is low,

And love is waxing cold.

How long, O Lord our God,

Holy, and true, and good,

Wilt Thou not judge Thy suffering Church,

Her sighs, and tears, and blood?

4 We long to hear Thy voice,

To see Thee face to face,

To share Thy crown and glory then,

As now we share Thy grace.

Should not the loving bride

Her absent bridegroom mourn?

Should she not wear the signs of grief

Until her Lord return?

5 The whole creation groans,

And waits to hear that voice

That shall her beauteousness restore,

And make her wastes rejoice.

Come, Lord, and wipe away

The curse, the sin, the stain,

And make this blighted world of ours

Thine own fair world again.

< E964 C- K- S- >

1 'Midst the darkness, storm, and sorrow,

One bright gleam I see;

Well I know the blessed morrow

Christ will come for me.

'Midst the peace, the joy, the glory

And the light, God's own,

Christ for me is watching, waiting,

Waiting 'til I come.

2 Long the blessed Guide has led me,

By the desert road;

Now I see the coming splendor,

Splendor of my God.

There amidst the love and glory

He is waiting yet;

On His hands a name is graven

He can ne'er forget.

3 Who is this, who comes to meet me,

On the desert way,

As the Morning Star foretelling

God's unclouded day?

He it is who came to win me,

On the cross of shame;

In His glory well I know Him,

Evermore the same.

4 O the blessed joy of meeting,

All the desert past;

O the wondrous words of greeting,

He shall speak at last!

He and I together ent'ring

The fair realm above;

He and I together sharing

All the Father's love.

5 Where no shade nor stain can enter,

Nor the gold be dim,

In His holiness unsullied,

I shall walk with Him.

Meet companion then for Jesus,

From Him, for Him, made -

Glory of God's grace forever

There in me displayed.

6 He who in His hour of sorrow

Bore the curse alone;

I who through the lonely desert

Trod where He had gone;

He and I, in that bright glory,

One deep joy shall share -

Mine, to be forever with Him;

His, that I am there.

< E968 C- K- S- >

1 Hail to the Lord's Anointed,

Great David's greater Son!

Hail, in the time appointed,

His reign on earth begun!

He comes to break oppression,

To set the captive free;

To take away transgression,

And rule in equity.

2 He shall come down like showers

Upon the fruitful earth;

And love, joy, hope, like flowers,

Spring in His path to birth:

Before Him on the mountains

Shall peace, the herald, go;

And righteousness, in fountains,

From hill to valley flow.

3 Kings shall fall down before Him,

And gold and incense bring;

All nations shall adore Him,

His praise all people sing;

For He shall have dominion

O'er river, sea, and shore,

Far as the eagle's pinion,

Or dove's light wing can soar.

4 To Him shall prayer unceasing

And daily vows ascend;

His kingdom still increasing,

A kingdom without end.

The mountain dews shall nourish

A seed in weakness sown,

Whose fruit shall spread and flourish,

And shake like Lebanon.

5 O'er every foe victorious

He on His throne shall rest,

From age to age more glorious,

All-blessing and all-blest.

The tide of time shall never

His covenant remove;

His Name shall stand forever,

His changeless Name of Love.

< E973 C772 K772 S452 >

1 Our goal - the holy city with the Lord,

It is our portion, 'tis where He's adored;

Although our bodies still are living here,

Our spirits with our glorious Lord are there;

Our spirits with our glorious Lord are there.

2 Our goal divine - the new Jerusalem -

That holy city made for God with men;

For all redeemed, who have Thy pathway trod,

Shall have the right to share the bliss with God,

Shall have the right to share the bliss with God.

3 And every time we toward that city gaze,

Then every time we long to see Thy face;

We long to hear the shout that calls to Thee,

With Thee to share Thy God eternally,

With Thee to share Thy God eternally.

4 Our heart's desire is not the peace so sweet,

Our longed for hope is not the joy we'll meet;

But Thou Thyself, Thou art "our hope," O Lord,

For 'tis Thyself that will be our reward,

For 'tis Thyself that will be our reward.

5 O Jesus, Lord, we pray Thee hear our cry,

Come! Bring us to that city from on high!

That in that glory we may share with Thee,

Thy loving Self partake eternally,

Thy loving Self partake eternally.

6 O Lord, Thou sayest, "I make all things new,"

New heav'ns, new earth, and all within them too!

Our God Himself our portion then shall be;

O Lord, come quickly! Take us up with Thee,

O Lord, come quickly! Take us up with Thee.

< E975 C774 K774 S454 >

1 It was a garden in the primal age,

But at the end it is a city square;

Creation's center in the garden was,

God's building issues in the city fair.

2 Both in the garden and the city fair

A river and the tree of life are seen,

Christ typifying as the life supply,

The Spirit showing as the living stream.

3 Both in the garden and the city bright

Three kinds of precious substances are found;

There are the gold, the pearls, and precious stones

Which for the building work of God abound.

4 But in the garden all these precious things

Are just materials lying in the earth,

Yet in the city all are builded up

And form that dwelling of transcendent worth.

5 Man in the garden of the clay was formed,

In nature as the Lord created him;

The tree of life was then without the man,

Not having yet become his life within.

6 But in the city glorious the tree

Within the corporate "man" doth grow, thereby

Revealing Christ Himself as life divine

Being to man his inward life supply.

7 'Tis for the city man is wrought upon,

Therefore regenerated and transformed

To purest gold, to pearls and precious stones,

As Christ's own Body, to Himself conformed.

8 Within the garden also was a bride,

Who was to Adam as his counterpart;

Lastly, the city is itself the bride

As Christ's own fulness, precious to His heart.

9 The city is God's building work replete,

A composition of the justified;

A habitation it affords to God

And is to Christ His own beloved bride.

10 'Tis God's expression, ultimate and full,

Corporate and universal, marvelous;

God's glory it completely manifests,

And is Christ's counterpart most glorious.

< E976 C775 K775 S455 >

1 O Lord Jesus, Thy redeemed ones

Are Thy Body and Thy Bride;

As Thy fulness, Thine expression,

In her Thou art glorified.

Thou, her all in all forever,

She Thy riches doth declare;

Thou dost fully saturate her

And Thy glory with her share.

Lo, the holy city,

Full of God's bright glory!

It is God's complete expression

In humanity.

2 God with man completely blended,

Mystery of godliness,

God in glory, full, resplendent,

Man, His dwelling, doth express.

'Tis a vessel universal

All God's fulness to express;

All His beauty manifesting,

Mingled with His holiness.

3 'Tis a living composition

Of the saints He hath transformed;

As the pearls and stones most precious,

To His image they're conformed:

From the throne of God, its center,

Flows the living water free;

Christ the tree of life doth flourish,

Bearing fruit abundantly.

4 'Tis th' eternal golden lampstand,

Holding Christ, the lamp of light;

God in Christ the light of glory

As the Spirit shineth bright!

'Tis the ultimate expression -

Man in God and God in man;

'Tis their mutual habitation,

Goal of God's eternal plan.

< E977 C- K869 S- >

1 Glorious things of thee are spoken,

Holy city of our God;

He whose word cannot be broken

Formed thee for His own abode;

On the Rock of Ages founded,

What can shake thy sure repose?

With salvation's walls surrounded,

Thou may'st smile at all thy foes.

2 See the streams of living waters,

Springing from eternal love,

Well supply thy blessed members,

And all fear of want remove;

Who can faint, when such a river

Ever flows their thirst t' assuage?

Grace which, like the Lord, the giver,

Never fails from age to age.

3 Blest constituents of Zion,

Washed in the Redeemer's blood;

Jesus, whom their souls rely on,

Makes them kings and priest to God.

'Tis His love His people raises

Over self to reign as kings:

And as priests, His worthy praises,

Each his thankful offering brings.

4 Savior, if of Zion's city

I, through grace, a member am,

Let the world deride or pity -

I will glory in Thy name.

Fading is the worldling's pleasure,

All his boasted pomp and show;

Solid joys and lasting treasure

None but Zion's members know.

< E979 C776 K776 S- >

1 How glorious, how bright it shines,

The holy, new Jerusalem;

It is God's dwelling place with man,

The spotless bride of Christ, the Lamb.

2 Saints of the Old and of the New,

Heirs of the promise God bestowed,

Components of the city are,

Together built for God's abode.

3 Perfectly square the city lies,

All sides are equal - length, width, height;

No measurement more long or short,

No part oblique, it stands upright.

4 The city with its street pure gold

As clear as glass transparent is,

Showing that God's transcendent life

Its quality and nature is.

5 Twelve city gates are each one pearl;

Thus man is through redemption shown

Reborn and as a pearl transformed,

Entering to a realm God's own.

6 The twelve foundations of its wall

Are with twelve precious stones adorned;

Through fire and pressure recomposed

And with eternal value formed.

7 The wall of jasper, crystal clear,

God's glory by it fully shown;

His glorious light through it does shine,

And He appears as jasper stone.

8 The wall a separation makes,

Excluding all that is unclean;

Gold, pearls, and precious stones alone

The holy city has within.

9 God and the Lamb the Temple are!

We shall behold His glorious face;

His presence never will depart,

We'll worship Him thru endless days.

10 The city needs no sun nor moon

For God's own glory is its light;

The Lamb's the lamp the city bears,

In all directions blazing bright.

11 Out from the throne of God and the Lamb

Flows midst the street a living stream,

And on its banks, on either side,

The tree of life is thriving seen.

12 This signifies the life of God

Not just for food or water flows,

But carries God's authority

As it throughout the city goes.

13 The street of purest gold therein

God's nature as the way doth show;

A river in it flows for drink

And fruits of life abundant grow.

14 The number twelve means government,

Perfection which eternal is;

God blent with man it also tells -

Three multiplied by four shows this.

15 Darkness and death shall be no more,

Sorrow and pain shall pass away,

Old will be gone and all be new,

God will abide with man for aye.

16 The city has God's image full,

It rules for Him, the sovereign King,

Fulfilling His eternal plan,

Complete content to Him to bring.

< E980 C778 K778 S457 >

1 Throughout the whole of Holy Writ

The saints in type are manifest

As like a bride, God's heart to please,

And as a building for His rest.

2 The types and figures of the Church

In the Old Testament are these:

A building meet for life and rule,

A bride the man to match and please.

3 God's people in the ancient times

Were called by God His very spouse;

Among them and with them were built

God's ruling city and God's house.

4 Incarnate God, the God-man, Christ,

As Bridegroom for the Bride has come;

With His own life He quickened her,

That she His counterpart become.

5 In resurrection Christ doth now,

As David's Son, God's temple build,

That God may have a resting place

And there accomplish all He willed.

6 The Church is thus the Bride of Christ,

In whom His full delight doth rest;

It is a dwelling place to God

Where He may live and be expressed.

7 The new Jerusalem will be

The full perfection ultimate

Of all the types of house and bride,

Th' eternal plan to consummate.

8 It is the Bride which matches Christ,

Thru whom He may Himself express;

It is God's tabernacle too

In which our God can rule and rest.

9 The ultimate completion 'tis

Of God's work in humanity,

His full expression glorious

Thru His redeemed eternally.

< E981 C779 K779 S458 >

1 In His Christ to head up all things

Is our God's economy;

Taking Christ as Head and Center,

All is one in harmony.

2 Christ as Head will be the Center;

God within will be the Light;

Christ enthroned, with God, His substance,

Will fulfill His heart's delight.

3 Christ as life will be the content,

Heading up all things in light;

All the saints will be the vessel,

To express His glory bright.

4 Satan hath himself injected

Into man all things to spoil,

Bringing darkness and corruption

God's eternal plan to foil.

5 Christ has come, Himself imparting

Into man as life to save,

That the pow'r of death and darkness

May no more all things enslave.

6 Thru the Church which is His Body

Christ as Head will sum up all;

All will fitly join together,

All things either great or small.

7 Under Christ, by His full headship,

All in union will subsist;

In the light the Church expresses

All in oneness will exist.

8 Owning Christ as Head and Center,

All will be in harmony;

Thru the shining of His Body

All will share His liberty.

9 No more darkness and corruption,

No more death and vanity;

All will be released from bondage

Throughout all eternity.

< E1024 C723 K723 S476 >

1 Christ the Savior is just the One you need,

He's God incarnate, as a man indeed;

In His body He suffered every pain

And died to cleanse your every stain,

So you need Jesus!

You need Jesus! You need Jesus!

Men and women all need Him!

For redemption you need Him,

For salvation you need Him!

And for everlasting life,

Yes, you need Jesus!

2 He has risen and gone up into heav'n,

That life eternal might be fully giv'n;

Just receive Him, believing in your heart,

Then all you need He will impart,

So you need Jesus!

3 He'll enlighten your darkened heart with light,

Forgive your sins and rescue you with might;

He will cleanse you from all stains with His blood,

And give to you the life of God,

So you need Jesus!

4 In your living there is a lack you sense,

And thru the years it grows the more intense;

Only Jesus this need can satisfy;

All vanity He will defy,

So you need Jesus!

You need Jesus! You need Jesus!

Men and women all need Him!

To escape from vanity,

To obtain reality,

To make life significant,

Yes, you need Jesus!

5 All this world now is rife with toil and pain,

In troubled times there's nothing to sustain;

All is empty, on what can you rely?

All things reveal and testify,

That you need Jesus!

< E1030 C707 K707 S- >

1 I hear my risen Savior say:

"Follow me, follow me, follow me";

His voice is calling all the day,

"Follow me, follow me, follow me;

For thee I trod the bitter way,

For thee I gave my life away,

And drank the gall thy debt to pay,

Follow me, follow me, follow me."

2 "I know thy life of guilt and pain;

Follow me, follow me, follow me!

I know each ache of heart and brain;

Follow me, follow me, follow me!

How often I have called in vain,

And offered pardon in my name,

And now I plead yet once again!

Follow me, follow me, follow me!"

3 "Though thou hast sinned I'll pardon thee;

Follow me, follow me, follow me!

From every sin I'll set thee free;

Follow me, follow me, follow me!

In all thy changing life I'll be

Thy God, thy guide on land and sea,

Thy bliss through all eternity,

Follow me, follow me, follow me!"

4 "Come, cast on Me thine every care;

Follow me, follow me, follow me!

Thy heavy load I will upbear;

Follow me, follow me, follow me!

Come, look to Me - dismiss thy fears;

And trust Me through eternal years;

My hand shall wipe away thy tears;

Follow me, follow me, follow me!"

5 Dear Lord, I yield to Thee my will;

I'll follow Thee, follow thee, follow thee!

Oh, bid my struggling soul be still;

I'll follow Thee, follow Thee, follow Thee!

Lord, cleanse me, with Thy Spirit fill,

And keep me safe from every ill;

And all Thy Word in me fulfill;

I'll follow Thee, follow Thee, follow Thee!

< E1032 C721 K721 S- >

1 Come, ye sinners, poor and wretched,

Weak and wounded, sick and sore;

Jesus ready waits to save you,

Full of pity, love and pow'r:

He is able, He is able,

He is willing, doubt no more.

2 Come, ye needy, come and welcome;

God's free bounty glorify;

True belief and true repentance,

Every grace that brings us nigh,

Without money, without money,

Come to Jesus Christ and buy.

3 Let not conscience make you linger,

Nor of fitness fondly dream;

All the fitness He requireth

Is to feel your need of Him:

This He gives you, this He gives you,

'Tis the Spirit's rising beam.

4 Come, ye weary, heavy laden,

Lost and ruined by the fall;

If you tarry till you're better,

You will never come at all:

Not the righteous, not the righteous,

Sinners Jesus came to call.

5 Agonizing in the garden,

Your Redeemer prostrate lies;

On the bloody tree behold Him!

Hear Him cry, before He dies,

"It is finished!" "It is finished!"

Sinner, will not this suffice?

6 Lo! th' incarnate God, ascended,

Pleads the merit of His blood;

Venture on Him, venture wholly;

Let no other trust intrude:

None but Jesus, none but Jesus,

Can do helpless sinners good.

< E1068 C737 K737 S489 >

1 In tenderness He sought me,

Weary and sick with sin,

And on His shoulders brought me

Into His flock again.

While angels in His presence sang

Until the courts of heaven rang.

Oh, the love that sought me!

Oh, the blood that bought me!

Oh, the grace that brought me to the flock,

Wondrous grace that brought me to the flock!

2 He washed the bleeding sin-wounds,

And poured in oil and wine;

He whispered to assure me,

"I've found thee, thou art Mine:"

I never heard a sweeter voice,

It made my aching heart rejoice.

3 He pointed to the nail-prints,

For me His blood was shed;

A mocking crown so thorny,

Was placed upon His head:

I wondered what He saw in me,

To suffer such a deep agony.

4 I'm sitting in His presence,

The sunshine of His face,

While with adoring wonder

His blessings I retrace.

It seems as if eternal days

Are far too short to sound His praise.

5 So while the hours are passing,

All now is perfect rest;

I'm waiting for the morning,

The brightest and the best,

When He will call us to His side,

To be with Him, His spotless Bride.

< E1076 C- K- S- >

1 O teach me what it meaneth:

That Cross uplifted high,

With One, the Man of Sorrows,

Condemned to bleed and die.

O teach me what it cost Thee

To make a sinner whole;

And teach me, Savior, teach me

The value of a soul.

2 O teach me what it meaneth:

That sacred crimson tide,

The blood and water flowing

From Thine own wounded side.

Teach me that if none other

Had sinned but only I,

Yet still, O blessed Savior,

Thou on the cross must die.

3 O teach me what it meaneth:

Thy love beyond compare,

The love that reacheth deeper

Than depths of self-despair!

Yea, teach me, till there gloweth

In this cold heart of mine

Some feeble, pale reflection

Of that pure love of Thine.

4 O teach me what it meaneth,

For I am full of sin;

And grace alone can reach me,

And love alone can win.

O teach me, for I need Thee,

I have no hope beside,

The chief of all the sinners

For whom the Savior died.

5 O teach me what it meaneth:

The rest which Thou dost give

To all the heavy-laden

Who look to Thee and live.

Because I am a rebel

Thy pardon I receive:

Because Thou dost command me,

I can, I do believe.

6 O infinite Redeemer,

I bring no other plea;

Because Thou dost invite me

I cast myself on Thee.

Because Thou dost accept me

I love and I adore;

Because Thy love constraineth,

I'll praise Thee evermore.

< E1078 C- K- S- >

1 One sat alone beside the highway begging,

His eyes were blind, the light he could not see;

He clutched his rags and shivered in the shadows,

Then Jesus came and bade his darkness flee.

When Jesus comes the tempter's pow'r is broken;

When Jesus comes the tears are wiped away.

He takes the gloom and fills the life with glory,

For all is changed when Jesus comes to stay.

2 From home and friends the evil spirits drove him,

Among the tombs he dwelt in misery;

He cut himself as demon pow'rs possessed him,

Then Jesus came and set the captive free.

3 "Unclean! Unclean!" the leper cried in torment,

The deaf, the dumb, in helplessness stood near;

The fever raged, disease had gripped its victim,

Then Jesus came and cast out every fear.

4 Their hearts were sad as in the tomb they laid him,

For death had come and taken him away;

Their night was dark and bitter tears were falling,

Then Jesus came and night was turned to day.

5 So men today have found the Savior able,

They could not conquer passion, lust and sin;

Their broken hearts had left them sad and lonely,

Then Jesus came and dwelt, Himself, within.

< E1079 C700 K700 S- >

1 If I gained the world, but lost the Savior,

Were my life worth living for a day?

Could my yearning heart find rest and comfort

In the things that soon must pass away?

If I gained the world, but lost the Savior,

Would my gain be worth the lifelong strife?

Are all earthly pleasures worth comparing

For a moment with a Christ-filled life?

2 Had I wealth and love in fullest measure,

And a name revered both far and near,

Yet no hope beyond, no harbor waiting,

Where my storm-tossed vessel I could steer;

If I gained the world, but lost the Savior,

Who endured the cross and died for me,

Could then all the world afford a refuge,

Whither, in my anguish, I might flee?

3 O what emptiness! - without the Savior

'Mid the sins and sorrows here below!

And eternity, how dark without Him!

Only night and tears and endless woe!

What, though I might live without the Savior,

When I come to die, how would it be?

O to face the valley's gloom without Him!

And without Him all eternity!

4 O the joy of having all in Jesus!

What a balm the broken heart to heal!

Ne'er a sin so great, but He'll forgive it,

Nor a sorrow that He does not feel!

If I have but Jesus, only Jesus,

Nothing else in all the world beside -

O then everything is mine in Jesus;

For my needs and more He will provide.

< E1082 C- K- S- >

1 The living of Christ when He sojourned on earth,

The sixteenth Psalm shows us, was wholly of worth.

His attitudes, choices, and interests all tell

The man who in God's tabernacle may dwell.

2 "Preserve me, O God, for in Thee I confide" -

In God He took refuge whate'er did betide.

"O Thou art my Lord, I've no good beyond Thee" -

He spoke in Himself unto God constantly.

3 "As for all the saints who are dwelling on earth,"

To Him they're the people of excellent worth.

Of them He has said He has all His delight -

In proving this all the four Gospels unite.

4 "The Lord is my portion, the Lord is my cup" -

For everything He to the Father looked up.

"The Lord I will bless who my counsel doth give" -

Himself He denied and by God's word did live.

5 His heart thus was glad and His spirit rejoiced,

And e'en in His death praise to God could be voiced;

His soul God would never abandon to hell,

But in resurrection His body would dwell.

6 God raised Him, and He with God's glory was crowned;

Then fulness of joy in God's presence He found.

E'en now at the Father's right hand is His seat,

Where flowing forever are pleasures complete.

< E1083 Cs225 K1049 S45 >

1 O how nigh the Lord is unto all who call on Him!

When we call, His very presence strengthens us within.

Seeking Jesus, He is found, and calling, He is near -

O what a comfort to our hearts to call His name so dear!

Jesus! O what a name!

O Lord Jesus! Life-giving name!

Name victorious, name all-glorious,

Name exalted - O what a name!

Jesus! Strengthening name!

O Lord Jesus! Comforting name!

Name to breathe in prayer, calling everywhere,

"O Lord Jesus!" O what a name!

2 Call upon the name of Jesus, and you will be saved,

O Lord Jesus, hallelujah, nevermore enslaved!

We may take salvation's cup by calling on the Lord;

Salvation from a host of things does His dear name afford.

3 To the Lord, the Jew, the Greek and everyone's the same;

He is rich unto all men that call upon His name.

O Lord Jesus, what a joy to call and really live;

When breathing in Thy name, what pleasure Thou to us dost give.

4 In the God of our salvation we may take delight,

Calling on His name at all times, though in bliss or blight.

I will call upon His name as long as I shall live,

Because He has inclined His ear, and grace so full does give.

5 We will call upon the Lord, who's worthy of our praise;

Thus our grateful hearts in worship we to Him may raise.

We are those who call upon His name in every place

With all the saints who from a pure heart

call and taste His grace.

< E1091 C- K- S- >

1 We praise Thee, O Lord Jesus, Thou didst come,

The way into God's presence to reveal.

We worship Thee that Thou didst leave Thy throne,

To come as our High Priest with sin to deal.

Lord Jesus, Thou hast offered Thine own blood,

And settled once for all our peace with God.

2 Thy blood has now been sprinkled on the throne

In full redemption for Thy people's sin.

The sweetness of the love that Thou hast shown

Has ris'n to fill the holiest place within.

And by the blood once offered in that place

God flows to us in mercy and in grace.

3 Yet, Lord, Thou camest not just to atone,

But Thou didst come and bear our sins away.

We, with a conscience purged, approach the throne,

For all our sins were laid on Thee that day.

Thou, separated from the Father's face,

Didst pay the awful price for us in grace.

4 The way into God's presence thus is cleared,

For ransomed sinners who have heard Thy call.

Thou, Lord, hast taken all that we had feared

When Thou didst shed Thy blood and give Thine all;

Our heart in grateful praise to Thee we bind,

And now our life in Thee alone we find.

< E1093 C- K- S- >

1 Through countless ages, many men

Have longed and sought and tried to see

The secret of the universe,

So vast, so great a mystery.

2 Yet not through struggling could frail man

The secret of this myst'ry find;

Nor change, by stumbling, come upon

Such hidden things - to these he's blind.

3 Behold in heav'n a throne is set,

And One upon the throne revealed;

And held in His right hand a scroll -

The mystery is tightly sealed.

4 Through all the universe, a cry -

'Can one be found of such great worth

The scroll to take? ... yet no reply,

From heav'n, below, or on the earth.

5 Were it a matter now for man

By chance, or some ability,

Then surely one would now step forth

To open God's economy.

6 Yet sad and solemn was that sight.

John wept as then he looked around;

And we, too, still might weeping be

If none at all were worthy found.

7 But then the angel said, 'Weep not!

Behold, the Lion has prevailed

To take the scroll and loose its seals;

He has the mystery now unveiled!'

8 So, John looked up the Lion to see,

But, lo, he then beheld a Lamb;

Christ both o'ercame the enemy,

And wrought redemption's work for man.

9 The angels fall before His throne,

Four living creatures offer praise,

All glory to the Lion-Lamb;

Let us with theirs our voices raise!

< E1094 Cs2 K- S- >

1 Lo, the nations all assemble

And imagine vanity,

Kings and princes plot together

'Gainst the Lord in unity.

"Let us break their bonds asunder,

Cast away their cords from us."

'Gainst the Lord and His Anointed

Worldly rulers counsel thus.

2 He who sitteth in the heavens

In contempt will laugh at them,

Vex them in His fierce displeasure,

Terrifying all such men.

Yet upon the hill of Zion

God has His anointed King -

This is God's own declaration,

All the kings admonishing.

3 Now 'tis Christ, 'tis God's Anointed,

Who declares the Lord's decree:

"Thou'rt my Son (in resurrection),

This day I've begotten Thee.

For Thine own inheritance.

Thou shalt dash them into pieces

In Thy kingly excellence."

4 Now be wise, O be instructed,

All ye rulers of the earth,

Fear the Lord, rejoice with trembling,

Serve the only One of worth.

Kiss the Son, lest He be angry

And ye perish in the way.

"All who trust in Him are blessed,"

All who trust in Him will say.

5 Lord, we praise Thee, we have seen Him -

Thy unique Anointed One -

And from vanity repenting,

We in love have kissed Thy Son.

"All who trust in Him are blessed" -

Not "all those who keep the law."

In that risen One believing,

We are blest forevermore.

< E1097 Cs3 K781 S63 >

1 O Lord, our Lord, how excellent

Thy name in all the earth!

Let every people, tribe, and tongue

Proclaim its boundless worth.

Out of the mouth of little ones

Thou hast established praise,

That Thou may still Thine enemy

And swiftly end his days.

2 When we the universe behold,

The work of Thy great hand -

The sun, the moon, and all the stars

By lofty wisdom planned;

O what is man that Thou should'st care

That Thou should'st mindful be?

The son of man Thou visitest

In Thine economy.

3 O Jesus Lord, Thou art that man,

The One who joined our race,

Who put upon Himself the flesh

And took a lower place.

But now with glory Thou art crowned,

With sovereignty complete.

Now through Thy Body Thou dost rule

With all beneath Thy feet.

4 Thine incarnation, rising too,

And Thy transcendency,

Thy Lordship, Headship, kingdom full,

And Body here we see.

By all these steps of work divine

Thou hast established praise.

With overflowing hearts to Thee

Our joyful voice we raise.

5 Oh, soon that blessed day shall come -

All tongues these words shall peal!

But in the local churches now

We have a foretaste real.

O Lord, our Lord, how excellent

Thy name in all the earth!

Let every people, tribe, and tongue

Proclaim its boundless worth.

< E1098 Cs6 K- S64 >

1 Our hearts are overflowing

To speak a goodly thing -

To tell what we've experienced

Of our exalted King.

Our tongues as pens are ready,

We've volumes here to "write" -

The glories of our Bridegroom,

Our Lord and our delight.

2 Lord Jesus, Thou art fairer

Than all the sons of men;

Thy goodness is transcendent -

Hallelujah! Amen!

Upon Thy lips most holy

Abundant grace is poured;

Forever God has blessed Thee,

Our gracious, glorious Lord!

3 Thou art the mighty Warrior

Who rides to victory;

In Thy majestic glory

Ride on triumphantly!

The peoples fall beneath Thee -

The conquering One Thou art.

Thine arrows in their sharpness

Have entered Satan's heart!

4 Thy throne, O God, forever

And ever shall endure;

The sceptre of Thy kingdom

Upon the earth is sure.

'Tis with the oil of gladness

God has anointed Thee

Above all Thy companions -

How worthy there to be!

5 Of aloes, myrrh, and cassia

Do all Thy garments smell:

Thy death and resurrection

Do all Thy deeds forthtell.

Out of the local churches

Shall praises make Thee glad,

And praises upon praises

Thy joyful saints shall add.

< E1099 Cs7 K- S- >

1 The queen in gold of Ophir

At Thy right hand doth stand;

King's daughters are the women

Who fill Thy honored band.

The church in all her glory

Shall match her glorious King,

And all the saints, the women,

Thy likeness there shall bring.

2 O daughter, now consider,

E'en now incline thine ear:

Remember not thy people

And all thine own things here.

Thy beauty then shall blossom -

'Twill be the King's desire;

For He thy worthy Lord is,

Thy worship to inspire.

3 The daughter's glorious garments

Are made of inwrought gold -

Within the inner palace,

How wondrous to behold!

The glory of God's nature

Is given her to wear,

That all His holy being

She may in life declare.

4 In clothing too embroidered

She'll to the King be led,

In that fine linen garment

To be exhibited.

'Tis by the Spirit's stitching

That Christ in us is wrought,

And with this glorious garment

We'll to the King be brought.

5 What gladness and rejoicing

When we the King shall see!

We'll shout His worthy praises

Through all eternity.

And though the King we worship

Or glory in the Queen,

In all this blest enjoyment

The glory goes to Him.

< E1100 Cs9 K- S- >

1 God shall rise, His foes be scattered,

All that hate Him flee away.

As the wax before the fire,

All the wicked He shall slay.

But the righteous shall rejoice

With a loud, triumphant voice,

Singing praises, singing praises,

Singing praises unto God!

2 He is riding through the deserts,

Bringing in His saints in need.

He's a Father to the orphans

And a refuge tried indeed

In His holy habitation -

What a wonderful salvation!

Hallelujah, hallelujah,

Hallelujah, Amen!

3 Here the lone have found a family,

Here the desolate a home;

Prisoners are brought from bondage

To prosperity unknown.

For the flock - what wondrous grace -

God prepared this dwelling place:

Hallelujah, hallelujah,

Hallelujah, Amen!

4 Now the Lord in mighty triumph

Sends the news of victory;

We the "women" spread the tidings -

"Kings of armies flee, they flee!"

No more sweat and dreary toil;

We at home divide the spoil!

Hallelujah, hallelujah,

Hallelujah, Amen!

5 Lo, on high Christ hath ascended,

Leading captives in His train;

These as gifts He has perfected

That the Lord may dwell with them.

Brothers, sisters, we are those,

We're those transformed, vanquished foes!

Hallelujah, hallelujah,

Hallelujah, Amen!

6 Blessed be the Lord forever:

Day by day He loads with good,

E'en the God of our salvation -

Spread His worthy praise abroad.

His the goings forth from death,

Every foe He conquereth!

Hallelujah, hallelujah,

Hallelujah, Amen!

7 They have seen, O God, Thy goings

In Thy holy dwelling place,

Thy triumphal, high processions

Midst a mighty voice of praise.

See the singers go before,

Praising, praising o'er and o'er:

Hallelujah, hallelujah,

Hallelujah! Amen!

8 Little Benjamin is leading,

Then great Judah's company:

Son of sorrow at God's right hand,

Lion with the scepter see.

Zebulun and Naphtali

Make the joyful tidings fly:

Hallelujah, hallelujah,

Hallelujah! Amen!

9 Saints, thy strength has been commanded

From the temple glorious;

Still we pray that God may strengthen

All that He has wrought for us.

Higher yet our praises shall rise

Till the utmost earth replies:

Hallelujah, hallelujah,

Hallelujah! Amen!

< E1102 C- K- S- >

1 The Lord said unto my Lord,

"Sit Thou at My right hand;

Thy foes shall be Thy footstool,

Upon them Thou shalt stand."

The sceptre of Thy strength shall

The Lord from Zion send

To rule o'er all the nations

Forever 'til the end.

2 A voluntary offering,

The young ones are to Thee;

In consecration's splendor

How beautiful to see!

For as the dew of morning

Refreshes all the land -

The young ones given to Thee

Are precious in Thy hand.

3 The Lord hath sworn forever

And never will turn back,

"Thou art a priest forever,

As was Melchizedek."

Oh, Thou hast no beginning

Of days; of life: no end!

And on Thine intercession

We ever do depend.

4 The Lord is at Thy right hand

And in His day of wrath

He'll strike through rulers, judging

The nations in His path.

While riding on to triumph

He'll drink of us, the stream,

His head uplifted, strengthened,

The whole earth to redeem.

5 Oh Lord, Thou art ascended

To God's right hand to sit;

As Head o'er all things, to Thee

God doth Thy foes commit.

Our King - for us Thou reignest,

Our Priest - we are supplied,

Our all we give unto Thee,

Thou Conqueror glorified.

< E1103 C- K- S92 >

1 What He is: He's the Father.

He's the everlasting Father.

He's the firstborn of creation.

He's the One who lives inside of me.

He's the Father! Wonderful!

2 What He is: He's the river.

He is the mighty flowing river.

He waters me in a desert land.

He's my hiding place; He is our man.

He's the river! Wonderful!

3 What He is: He's the vine tree.

He's the branch, the root of Jesse.

He's the tree of life: we have the right

To eat of Him and have His life.

He's the vine tree! Wonderful!

4 What He is: He's the Shepherd.

He's the lamb of God, the he-goat.

We rest and feed in the pasture land.

We strike the blood and eat the lamb.

He's the Shepherd! Wonderful!

5 What He is: He's the Spirit.

He's the all-inclusive Spirit.

He's our everything; He's our all in all.

He gives life to us whene'er we call.

He's the Spirit! Wonderful!

6 What He is: He's a Person.

He's a real and living Person.

He is living now inside of us.

This Person is so glorious.

He's a Person! Wonderful!

7 What He is: He's the Body;

He's the fulness of the Godhead;

He's the center of the Father's plan,

Christ and the church, the one new man.

He is wonderful, wonderful.

He is wonderful, wonderful.

He is wonderful, wonderful.

< E1104 C- K1054 S109 >

1 Lord, Thou art our peace offering;

We lay our hands on Thee.

We're one with Thee, Lord Jesus,

In fact and practically.

Here in the tent of meeting

We offer Thee to God

And with the Father feasting

Enjoy Thee as our food.

Christ is our peace! Christ is our peace!

We praise Thee, blessed Lord!

Our peace with God, our peace with man

Have fully been restored.

2 O what a peace it gives us

To see the sprinkled blood.

The blood of our peace offering

Has brought us peace with God.

With boldness we're proclaiming -

Now hear this, enemy -

"Peace by the blood of Jesus!"

This is our victory.

3 Based on the burnt oblation

And the meal offering too,

We now may offer Jesus

As our peace offering true.

The more we eat and drink Him

In His humanity,

The more we may enjoy Him

While feasting corporately.

What fellowship, what fellowship

With God and man we share!

O what a joy, O what a feast

With all God's people here.

4 Here God enjoys His portion -

'Tis inward, hidden, sweet -

And all the priestly family

May here the wave breast eat.

The offering priest - how precious -

May of the best partake:

He gets the right heave shoulder

And one unleavened cake.

5 How sweet to eat the wave breast,

The all-embracing love

Of Christ in resurrection!

It sets us all above.

What strength to eat the shoulder

Of the ascended One

And with the cake be nourished

To walk as He has done.

6 With all the cleansed ones feasting,

How rich the Christ we eat!

Oh, this is true communion,

The only way to meet.

We bring our full thanksgiving

And e'en would make a vow -

We're for the Lord's recovery

As He is for us now.

< E1109 C- K- S- >

1 Take, drink this cup, His blood,

Redemption of our God.

The peace which Christ has made,

Is in this cup displayed.

We fellowship now with the Son:

On Calvary the work was done:

The way is clear, now all can come!

2 Take, drink this cup, each one,

His death show till He come.

Eat, drink, display this feast:

God in the Lamb released!

Around the table, sup and dine;

We eat the bread and drink the wine.

All blessing in this cup we find.

3 No blood of cow or goat

Could give us any hope.

Our sins would all remain

Still year by year the same.

A God-man, sinless, He must find -

No other offering of His kind,

A spotless lamb for all mankind.

4 Come! Now enjoy His blood.

What access this to God!

Here wondrous cleansing power

Flows to us, hour by hour.

One sacrifice for all was made,

And peace our conscience does pervade.

Redemption's price is fully paid!

5 Redeemer! Savior! King!

Of Thy dear blood we sing,

For in it now we see

Thy mercy, boundless, free.

This cup, our portion blessed of God,

Is of the cov'nant in Thy blood -

Dear, precious, precious, priceless blood!

< E1124 C- K- S- >

1 What! Not sing of blood divine?

What! Not tell to all mankind?

What! Not speak to hearts unclean

Of the precious living stream.

2 By this blood, God's life released,

Blood surpassing any beast's;

Perfect, spotless Lamb of God,

Incorruptible His blood.

3 Voice it has, this holy blood;

Pow'r possessed to speak with God;

Speaks it for us at the throne

With its glorious virtue shown.

4 Failure on our conscience is -

Conscience means a "knowing this" -

Causing us much grief and pain,

Telling us of every stain.

5 All the while we're unaware

Of the blood's effectual prayer.

Jesus' blood speaks of our case,

That we might receive His grace!

6 We need not dead works to bring,

Nor another offering.

Nothing else could please our God,

Heav'n is listening for His blood.

7 In His blood forgiveness shines;

Oh, 'tis glorious to find!

Israel just atonement knew,

We have that and cleansing too.

8 Heart and mind are now at peace

Rest! Our conscience has been reached.

Never more we blush in shame,

We are washed from every stain.

9 Hallelujah! Fathomless!

All that's in His blood for us!

Sing we will, and sing we must;

In His blood is all our trust!

< E1129 C- K- S- >

1 "So great a salvation," ye saints of the Lord,

To us is revealed in His marvelous Word!

Since all that He is and has done is for us,

We'll give earnest heed to this word glorious.

2 What He is of God and of Man as the Son,

We now may enjoy since with Him we are one;

Our High Priest and Captain - salvation is He!

He'll cause us to grow in His glory to be.

3 He's washed all our sins, purified them fore'er;

Tasted death on the cross, ended slavery there.

He took on our nature, the devil has slain,

And put you and I in His glorious train.

4 So great the extent of salvation to us -

We're partners of Christ in His plan glorious.

He'll bring us to glory and we'll rule with Him,

To the uttermost saved by His working within.

5 To such a salvation our heed we must give,

Lest drifting away or neglecting we live.

Christ now as our life, future ruling with Him,

We'll miss if we miss this salvation within.

6 "So great a salvation" is given to us

That we may be made like our Lord glorious!

By all that He is and by all He has done

We're brought into glory with God's firstborn Son.

< E1130 C- K- S- >

1 Sing praise to Christ Who lives in us,

The God of our salvation;

Who saves us by His life divine,

And not by regulation;

After we've worked - done all we can,

His life has power to change a man:

His life divine can change us.

2 He saves us to the uttermost

By His life-giving power;

Transfusing Himself into us,

He saves us hour by hour.

He saved the lost by coming in,

He's saving now from more than sin:

He's saving us to glory!

3 Our Lord was constituted priest

To be a real life-giver;

Life is the nature of this One

Who can from self deliver:

His life is indestructible,

By it He saves us to the full:

Praise God, He's fully able!

4 His life is fully qualified

To bring us through to glory;

Were it not for His tested life,

'Twould be another story:

His life was fully tried on earth,

To crucifixion from His birth:

He passed through death and Hades.

5 He's pledged to save us to the full,

His life is operating;

He's doing everything for us

'Tis all for our perfecting;

Our life's a failure at its best,

Only His life can stand the test:

His life brings full salvation!

6 He's living now to intercede,

Continuing forever;

He undertakes into the age,

His priesthood changes never;

He always lives to intercede,

Such a High Priest is what we need:

He's higher than the heavens.

7 Come forward now to God through Him,

Ne'er shrink back to destruction;

Come forward now to get the life,

Which brings the proper function;

Come forward now the life to take,

By life His people us He'll make,

And swallow death forever.

< E1132 C- K- S- >

1 Lord, teach us how to pray,

Not as the nations do in vain,

But turn us from our way,

And cause us, Lord, to call on You each day -

Lord Jesus, grow in us.

2 Lord, You're the seed of life;

You've sown Yourself into our heart,

And now You have a start;

So day by day more life to us impart -

Lord Jesus, grow in us.

3 Lord Jesus, soften us;

You know the source from which we came.

By calling on Your name,

Lord, let no earth unturned nor rocks remain -

Lord Jesus, grow in us.

4 Lord, how Your light makes clear

That we could not but e'er fail You;

Yet there's a message true,

The seed of life within us will break through -

Lord Jesus, grow in us.

5 Make us in spirit poor;

Lord, take whate'er we think we know.

We'll open to life's flow,

And thus take in the life that makes us grow -

Lord Jesus, grow in us.

6 Lord, make us pure in heart;

For we'll be not content until

You all our being fill,

O Lord, renew our mind, emotion, will -

Lord Jesus, grow in us.

7 Yes, Lord, impress our heart

That we must take You in each day;

The seed will have its way;

Your growing brings the kingdom here to stay -

Lord Jesus, grow in us.

8 Amen! - The growth in life!

There's nothing that Your life can't do;

Our every part renew.

We'll make it, we'll make it just by You.

Lord Jesus, grow in us.

Lord Jesus, grow in us.

< E1135 C- K838 S- >

1 Oh, sanctify us, Lord; now add Thyself to us,

In our experience, Thy Person spread in us,

That in reality the church be glorious,

O Lord, do add Thyself, we pray.

Oh, sanctify us, Lord, today;

Lord Jesus, You're the only way.

We take Your Person, Lord;

Oh, spread Yourself abroad.

Oh, sanctify us, Lord, today.

2 Oh, purify us, Lord, by speaking in our heart;

Thy living, spoken word this washing will impart.

Increase Thy speaking, Lord, and cleanse our every part.

Oh, purify us, Lord, we pray.

Oh, purify us, Lord, today;

Wash all our natural life away.

Speak now Thy words in us,

And make us glorious.

O Lord, do speak in us today.

3 O Lord, do nourish us; You are the food we need;

As we are eating You, we'll be transformed indeed;

We're fully satisfied as on Yourself we feed,

So nourish us, O Lord, we pray.

O Lord, do nourish us today

As all our self You wash away.

Not only purify,

But fill and satisfy;

O Lord, do nourish us today.

4 O Lord, do cherish us, as on Thyself we feed;

Warm us so tenderly and meet our every need.

Our hardness soften, Lord, till we are Yours indeed;

Oh, cherish us, dear Lord, we pray.

O Lord, do cherish us today,

Until our coldness flees away.

Oh, hold us close to Thee

And cherish tenderly;

O Lord, do cherish us today.

5 Lord, make us glorious, by all Your inner work,

Not glory for ourselves, but glory for the church;

That You may have Your Bride, thus ending all Your search.

O Lord, do work on us, we pray.

O Lord, do work on us today!

To form the church Your glorious way.

Oh, spread Yourself in us

Till we are glorious;

Oh, make us glorious, Lord, today.

< E1136 C- K- S- >

1 Oh, Lord, grant us revelation,

Grant us light and sight to see

That as life, within our spirit,

Thou art our reality;

And that from within our spirit,

Now You must possess each part

Spreading out to all our being,

Making home in all our heart.

2 It is not the outward action -

Pure behavior, conduct good,

Proper poise and perfect manners,

Doing what we think we should;

But it's Christ, a living Person,

Mingled thus with us within,

Spreading into all our being,

So that we might live by Him.

3 Oh, Lord, let our every action,

Everything we do and say,

Come from Thee alone, experienced

In a real and inner way.

We reject the empty teachings,

Leave the methods and the strife.

Let our only way of living

Be the overflow of life!

4 Following the inner feeling,

Living in the overflow,

Moving in the rich anointing,

Not by what we think or know,

Nothing through intent or motive,

Or with purpose duly done,

But just following this feeling,

Living by the living One!

5 Thus we're sanctified completely,

Saturated thoroughly;

Not the old religious concept:

Separated doctrinally.

But 'tis Christ Himself within us,

Added to our every part,

All supplying, satisfying,

Making home in all our heart.

< E1137 C303 K303 S- >

1 His countenance angels can often behold,

But ne'er taste His love in His grace;

His saints, though they know of His pure boundless love,

Have never yet once seen His face.

His saints will before long His visage behold,

E'en in His bright glory will share;

But Mary, beholding His tears as He wept.

Could touch His heart's agony there.

Could touch His heart's agony there.

2 We'll soon see the Lord, as He is, face to face,

We'll know Him as never before;

But that touch today, healing our broken heart,

In that day will be felt no more.

That day, though our lips offer unceasing praise,

No tears, then, nor prayers fervent burn;

Nor is there the comfort received through much pain,

Nor trust gained through trials to learn,

Nor trust gained through trials to learn.

3 Exceeding in glory, that day we'll be crowned,

Yet there'll be no cross to obey;

The sweet fellowship of His suff'rings for us

We only can share in today.

Once we've that rest entered, no weariness then,

Nor chance will remain to partake

The trials nor the hardships, nor happiness lost,

Nor suffering borne for His sake,

Nor suffering borne for His sake.

4 Oh, chances to suffer for Him are so few,

His shame and derision to bear;

Such blest opportunities soon pass away,

That He in our troubles may share.

All loneliness, misunderstandings and scorn

Despisings and sorrows will flee;

I treasure these blessings, for through them, O Lord,

I enter sweet oneness with Thee,

I enter sweet oneness with Thee.

5 I long to behold, Lord, Thy countenance soon,

What rapture with Thee, Lord, to meet.

But neither seek I all these trials to avoid;

Such times, Lord, are too rare and sweet.

Have mercy on me, fill me with Thy great love,

For Thee, Lord, to live at all cost;

Lest Thy servant, hoping for that blessed day,

That day, regret chances were lost,

That day, regret chances were lost.

< E1144 C- K- S- >

1 In the Word of old, we are clearly told,

In His image God created man.

To express His worth, to subdue the earth,

Have dominion and fulfill His plan.

Image, image,

In His image He created man.

Image, image,

For dominion, to fulfill His plan.

2 Yet no rules He gave, no instructions, save:

"Every tree shall be to thee for meat."

But one tree, He said, surely makes you dead;

Fruit of knowledge isn't good to eat.

Knowledge, knowledge,

Fruit of knowledge wasn't meant for meat.

Knowledge, knowledge,

Fruit of knowledge isn't good to eat.

3 Midst the garden fair, see the life tree there -

God Himself the tree of life does show.

But the enemy, somehow subtly

Tempted man the other tree to know.

Fallen, fallen,

Man has eaten of the deadly tree.

Fallen, fallen,

Man requires a full recovery.

4 Then came Jesus Christ as the tree of life,

Satisfying all that God required.

He redeemed the earth, giving man new birth.

And became the food that man desired.

Jesus, Jesus,

Jesus Christ is really good to eat.

Jesus, Jesus,

He is real drink and real meat.

5 Jesus ne'er designed e'er to feed our mind;

All good knowledge only puffeth up.

But He came, He said, as a feast instead,

Not to analyze, but only sup.

Take Him, take Him,

Wholly satisfying, glorious.

Take Him, take Him,

Jesus is the tree of life to us.

6 As we eat the Lord, growth He does afford,

Life and numbers soon will be increased.

We must clearly see God's recovery -

Christ is not religion, but a feast.

Eat Him, eat Him,

Christ as life is all the food we need.

Eat Him, eat Him,

He who eateth Him shall live indeed.

7 Eating is the way to live Christ today,

Of the eating there should be no lack.

As the churches eat, they become complete,

Eating Christ will bring the Bridegroom back.

Eating, eating,

Of our eating there must be no lack.

Eating, eating,

Eating Christ will bring the Bridegroom back.

< E1155 C- K983 S- >

1 How I love Thee, precious Jesus,

That Thy love laid hold of me;

Thou hast drawn and wooed and kissed me

That a lover I may be!

Our Beloved, how we love Him,

So attractive, our delight.

We are captivated wholly

And are comely in His sight.

2 As a company of horses,

Thou, O Lord, has likened me,

Strong and swift, with Pharaoh's chariots,

Full of natural energy.

3 Just a lover with the dove's eyes

Fixed on Him and Him alone;

Changed are all my natural concepts,

Oh, the Lord in me has grown!

4 Now a lily of the valley,

Standing out among the thorns,

In the Lord alone I'm trusting,

Of my self-strength I've been shorn.

5 Make us doves that hide in Thee, Lord;

Bring us to the secret place.

There You find our voices sweet, Lord,

And desire to see our face.

6 Make us then, Lord, smoking pillars,

Coming from the wilderness.

By Thy death and resurrection

All our natural will suppress.

7 You desire a couch to rest on -

We become a rest to Thee;

Thou the Person in our being,

Gone our personality.

8 Now a palanquin You're making -

Nothing natural You'll allow.

For Your move and Your expression

Start this work within us now!

9 You supply the wood and pillars

For the structure and support,

Bottom gold and seat of purple

For our King of royal court.

10 Only this, O Lord, we offer

For Thy palanquin so fine:

Just our love, so pure and fitted,

The interior design.

11 What a sight when our Beloved

Wears a crown upon His brow;

Christ, the Church, are now united -

Boast and glory to Him now!

< E1158 C275 K- S- >

1 Dear Lord Jesus, precious Jesus,

Thou hast won each love from me;

Who like Thee - so fair and comely?

Who like Thee - so sweet and lovely?

Matchless One, unrivaled beauty,

None can e'er compete with Thee!

2 Dear Lord Jesus, precious Jesus,

Gladly will I hear Thy call;

Since Thy voice my heart hath entered,

I from all things could but sever;

Void are all my other seekings,

Every pride hath disappeared.

3 Dear Lord Jesus, precious Jesus,

How can I still stubborn be?

At Thy feet cast all my hard'nings,

And return with songs and singings;

'Tis my love to be Thy bondslave,

'Tis my joy to Thee obey.

4 Dear Lord Jesus, precious Jesus,

Thy way only will I choose;

Though in tears while I'm obeying,

Yet I would not change my standing;

All I long for is Thy pleasure,

And the peace Thy love would bring.

5 Dear Lord Jesus, precious Jesus,

When Thy presence does depart,

Seems the dawn has lost its traces,

Hidden are my smiling faces;

All I yearn for is Thy coming

And Thy presence' sweet embrace.

6 Dear Lord Jesus, precious Jesus,

Can I tell it all to Thee?

Thou my love and satisfaction,

Thou my everlasting portion;

Thou art all that I desire,

Nothing else I would pursue.

7 Dear Lord Jesus, precious Jesus,

All I have I give to Thee;

Who like Thee - so fair and comely?

Who like Thee - so sweet and lovely?

Matchless One, unrivaled beauty,

None can e'er compete with Thee!

< E1159 Cs305 K831 S278 >

1 Jesus Lord, I'm captured by Thy beauty.

All my heart to Thee I open wide;

Now set free from all religious duty,

Only let me in Thyself abide.

As I'm gazing here upon Thy glory,

Fill my heart with radiancy divine;

Saturate me, Lord, I now implore Thee,

Mingle now Thy Spirit, Lord, with mine.

2 Shining One - how clear the sky above me!

Son of Man, I see Thee on the throne!

Holy One, the flames of God consume me,

Till my being glows with Thee alone.

Lord, when first I saw Thee in Thy splendor,

All self-love and glory sank in shame;

Now my heart its love and praises render,

Tasting all the sweetness of Thy name.

3 Precious Lord, my flask of alabaster

Gladly now I break in love for Thee;

I anoint Thy head, Beloved Master;

Lord, behold, I've saved the best for Thee.

Dearest Lord, I waste myself upon Thee;

Loving Thee, I'm deeply satisfied.

Love outpoured from hidden depths within me,

Costly oil, dear Lord, I would provide.

4 My Beloved, come on spices' mountain;

How I yearn to see Thee face to face.

Drink, dear Lord, from my heart's flowing fountain,

Till I rest fore'er in Thine embrace.

Not alone, O Lord, do I adore Thee,

But with all the saints as Thy dear Bride;

Quickly come, our love is waiting for Thee;

Jesus Lord, Thou wilt be satisfied.

< E1164 C- K- S245 >

1 Jesus, the all-inclusive land,

Is everything to me:

A Christ of brooks, of depths and streams,

And fountains bubbling free.

Springing from valleys and from hills,

Flowing till every part He fills,

He waters us - how glorious -

By His life!

2 Jesus is now the land of wheat -

Incarnate, crucified.

But resurrection life is He

By barley signified.

He is a land of figs and vines -

Blood of the grape, the cheering wine.

With such supplies He satisfies -

Christ our land!

3 O what a rich, abundant Christ:

Our pomegranate true,

The olive tree whose oil is now

Anointing us anew,

Rich milk and honey He doth bring,

Sweet, satisfying, nourishing.

Our Christ is such; He is so much!

What a Christ!

4 In our good land we eat the bread -

There is no scarcity.

We never lack one thing in Him,

So rich, so full is He.

He is a land so vast, immense;

He is complete in every sense.

How He expands - land of all lands -

In our heart!

5 Christ is a land of iron stones,

Whence comes authority.

We must dig out this solid Christ

To bind His enemy.

Then we must through the sufferings pass

To be refined as burnished brass.

With iron bind, as brass refined,

Is our need.

6 Lord, how we bless Thee for this land,

The all-inclusive Christ!

We've eaten Him, we're filled with Him,

O how He has sufficed!

Teach us to labor constantly

Upon this vast reality;

This is our joy, this our employ -

Christ our land!

< E1166 C- K- S- >

1 God has set the land before us,

And the land we will possess.

God has finally found a people

Tired of the wilderness.

Down with every weight and sin;

Let's go up and enter in.

Hallelujah, Hallelujah,

Hallelujah, Amen.

2 God has cleared the way before us

Through the victory of His Son;

Raised the Victor's banner o'er us,

All the battles He has won.

All that's left for us to do

Is by faith to follow through.

3 It's a land of hills and valleys,

Brooks of water flowing free;

Fountains rich with living water,

Streams that flow abundantly.

Brothers, joyfully we stand

In His promise, Christ the land.

4 God has made the fruit to grow here,

Filled the land with produce sweet:

Olive oil and pomegranates,

Fig trees, honey, vines and wheat.

We need nothing else besides,

All we need the land provides.

5 We have eaten unto fullness,

And with joy we bless the Lord,

For the good land He has given;

Faithful to His promised Word.

Here we find there is no lack -

Never, never we'll go back!

6 All we need to do is labor,

Working on the land each day;

Not expecting 'manna' blessing,

Working in a normal way.

God and man cooperating

While for harvest we are waiting.

7 Labor thus will bring the increase

Of the land with all its worth,

And the Lord will have the harvest,

When He comes to reap the earth.

To provide the Lord the way,

We must labor day by day.

< E1168 C- K- S247 >

1 Laboring on Jesus, the good land so real,

Plowing and planting and watering the field.

He yields the produce of reality,

God reaps the harvest of Jesus in me.

O Jesus! You're God's good land

For me to labor on!

I'll bit by bit possess You

Until the whole is won!

With Canaan is God's purpose,

The labor He will bless;

Lord Jesus, here I gain Yourself,

Your Person to possess.

2 Laboring on Jesus! My heart has been set,

Labor's begun, and I have no regret,

For with my labor God's sending the rain,

And all my labor on Christ yields much gain.

3 Laboring on Jesus this practical way -

Praying His Word in the spirit each day,

Foll'wing His living anointing within,

Built up with others, the church life to win.

4 Laboring on Jesus yields reality,

Meetings of fullness for all men to see;

There God and man are indeed satisfied,

And there God's presence cannot be denied.

5 Labor on Jesus to have Him increased!

Then seek God's dwelling and come to the feast!

There bring and offer your surplus to God,

There eat the riches, rejoice in the Lord!

< E1172 Cs133 K1013 S- >

1 Lo, the conflict of the ages

Is upon us today,

And the forces of rebellion

Are in total array.

The humanity of Jesus

Now the saints must possess,

His true image and dominion

On the earth to express.

Let us stand up in Jesus

In His full human life,

Human virtues prevailing

'Gainst corruption so rife;

In this wickedness concerted,

In this age perverse, perverted,

The humanity of Jesus

Must the church now display.

2 Lo, how Satan came to damage

Human life on the earth;

But the Lord in all this ruin

Raised a man full of worth!

From the seed of the woman

God incarnated became

The man Jesus - the last Adam -

To destroy Satan's aim!

3 It's by calling, drinking, eating

The man Jesus today,

His humanity enjoying

Bruises Satan each day.

To the Lord we must be turning,

All our soul life deny,

To destroy all Satan's working

And the new man supply.

4 See the ruin of a nation

Going downward in sin;

All humanity is fallen

And corrupted within.

But as children of the kingdom

We are salting the earth;

His humanity preserves us

In the midst of such dearth.

< E1176 C- K- S- >

1 Pow'r exceeding great God did demonstrate

When He raised His Son from the dead.

May this pow'r we see, with it strengthened be,

And in resurrection life be led.

Power, power, resurrection power,

Energize us mightily within!

Power, power, resurrection power,

Energize us in the inner man!

2 Pow'r exceeding high God did magnify

When He raised His Son far above all.

Principalities, pow'rs, and majesties

At the name of Jesus Christ must fall.

Power, power, all-transcending power,

Elevate us mightily within!

Power, power, all-transcending power,

Elevate us in the inner man!

3 Pow'r surpassing too, all things to subdue

Has been given to Christ, pow'r complete.

We His Body are; so, hallelujah,

Everything must be beneath our feet!

Power, power, all-subduing power,

All-subjecting mightily within!

Power, power, all-subduing power,

All-subjecting to the inner man!

4 And the best of all, overruling all,

O'er all to the church Christ is Head.

Pow'r so glorious over all's to us;

To the highest place the church is led.

Power, power, overruling power,

Ruling over all, without, within!

Power, power, overruling power,

Ruling, reigning, through the inner man!

< E1177 C- K- S- >

1 Oh, Christ in all His glory put on humanity

So He could be my Person, and live instead of me.

A man in life and being, He fully fits my case,

So all His glorious Person can me replace.

O Lord, O Lord, You are the man for me!

I take You as my Person, as my full identity.

O Lord, O Lord, subdue my every part,

And every moment, every place, make home in all my heart.

2 Oh, Christ became the Spirit to speak inside of me,

And as the speaking Spirit He speaks unceasingly.

His speaking is the water that washes me within,

Discharging all my oldness, imparting Him.

O Lord, O Lord, speak all You want to me.

Your speaking is Your presence - I must have it constantly.

O Lord, O Lord, speak-wash my every part

And by this metabolic change, make home in all my heart.

3 Oh, Christ will come, the Bridegroom, for us, His glorious Bride,

By coming from within us the church is glorified.

His Person is the glory expanding now in us;

This glory is our Person - how glorious!

O Lord, O Lord, by Your economy

So flood us with Your glory, saturate us thoroughly.

Come out, come out, break forth in glory here,

And from the church, O glorious One, in glory soon appear.

< E1178 Cs122 K- S249 >

1 We have seen Christ is reality:

But it's not sufficient just to see:

He in our experience must be

Everything to us.

We in prayer behold Him face to face,

In the Word and meetings know His grace;

But in daily life, in every place,

What is He to us?

Hallelujah! By His light we see

Oh, how real, how full our Lord will be

If we'll only turn to Him at every time, in every day,

Every thing, in every way and -

Be specific for reality!

And be done with generality!

If we'll just apply Him, we will see

He's everything to us.

2 Life is full of opportunities

Ordered by our Father's hand: we see

Everything's the best that it could be,

So let's gain Christ!

Christ our content and reality

To shine out from us unceasingly:

He must have a way in you and me,

He must have a way.

Hallelujah! In the body we

Bear the death of Christ continually:

Thus His life comes forth for all to see as

The outer man is broken down,

The inner man is shining so that -

In these earthen vessels men can see

There's the treasure of reality!

Thus the gospel's glorious light will be

Shining out from us.

Not just doctrines and theology,

But the content of reality:

Christ as everything in you and me

He's everything to us!

< E1181 C- K- S252 >

1 Lord, to know Thee as our Person,

Earnestly we seek and pray;

To experience Thy fulness

In a constant inner way.

Never longer only outward

Or with soulish thoughts obsessed,

But, O Lord, in realest contact

We by Thee would be possessed.

Lord, Thou art our Person,

In our inmost being,

May we constantly experience

This reality.

2 All the world is under darkness,

Driven by the fallen soul,

And the enemy designing

Does the soulish life control.

Such we were till God, through mercy,

Caused His Son to dwell in us;

Now we fully come to know Him

In His church so glorious.

3 Once we walked a soulish person,

Wandering in the wilderness,

Never knowing that our spirit

Craved God's fullness to express;

At the moment Jesus entered

Instantly the whole was changed.

Now we're people spirit-centered!

Hallelujah! Rearranged!

4 Now our spirit is our person -

What a glorious fact is this!

Christ Himself in us expressing

God's intent and holiness.

Not the soul-life's vain delusion,

But the spirit strengthened is;

Christ Himself is now our Person -

He is ours and we are His.

< E1185 C- K- S- >

1 In the multitude he lay there

With a sickness many years;

Impotent and lying helpless,

Every fraught with many fears.

Waiting for the water's moving,

Waiting for the angel's stir;

Powerless to move, however,

Helpless, hopeless, lying there.

2 At this pool how clear the picture

Of the hopeless case of all

Who are seeking self-perfection

To recover from the fall.

Though the law is good and holy,

Flesh, to keep the law, is dead;

What we need is not religion,

But the Word of life instead.

3 Though it's feast day, he's not happy,

Though the Sabbath, there's no rest;

Lying in his poor condition,

Miserable and sore depressed.

At that moment Jesus saw him,

Knowing he was thus so long.

"Will you be made whole?" He asked him,

"Healed and walking, well and strong?'

4 Though he told his hopeless story,

Scarce believing what he'd heard,

Yet, soon to his feet arising,

He received the living word.

This is all our situation,

We - like him - were lying there

In the sheep-fold of religion,

Under law's prevailing care.

5 While we yet were weak and helpless,

Christ the Son of God did come.

By His word we're now enlivened;

He's the life-imparting One!

Hallelujah for this Jesus,

He's the Word of life to men;

For law's bondage He releases,

Death is turned to life again!

< E1186 C- K- S- >

1 The scribes and Pharisees all thought

A leader great would come.

So they to John the Baptist came

To ask if he's the One.

"Art thou the Coming One?' they asked,

To which he made reply:

"I'm not the Christ - I am not He -

A voice, that's all, am I."

2 And on the morrow, John stood there

And spoke to two or three.

And as he lifted up his eyes,

He then did Jesus see.

He said, "Behold the Lamb of God,

'Tis He Who walks this way.

He's here to take the sins of all

And bear them all away!"

3 Yet poor religion counted not

These things of any worth,

But seeking for a leader great

It lingered on in dearth;

And looking for a movement strong,

Continued in its strife.

Preoccupied with these things,

They missed the Lord of LIFE!

4 Religion is Christ's enemy,

It's even so today.

For though they name Him, should He come,

They'd put the Lord away.

They did it then, they'd do it now,

They'd miss the Lord again.

So let us seek the Lord Himself,

The lamb, the dove obtain.

5 Now in the Lord's recovery

We're drawn to Christ alone.

The Spirit as the gentle dove

Has found in us a home.

Let all religion turn away

To movements wide and great;

This testimony of Himself

Our Lord will vindicate!

< E1188 C- K- S- >

1 Upon the throne of Jesus Christ

We've taken up our seat.

The world and Satan, sin and self

Are all beneath our feet!

Christ's finished work did put us here,

When once for all He died;

No more are we the sinners poor,

We're fully glorified.

2 We're dwelling in the house of God,

The church life glorious.

The shrinking-back, low Christian life,

Is not the life for us!

We're passing through the Holy Place

Of mind, emotion, will;

We're dwelling in the Holiest

Where God our being fills.

3 We're under the New Covenant,

With glorious items, three:

The law of life, spontaneous,

Transforming utterly;

We are His people, He's our God -

Oh, bless'd reality;

We all are fully able now

To know God inwardly.

4 A supplement God added then;

This item we must know:

Christ Jesus did put sin away

Two thousand years ago.

No memory of sin at all,

It's hist'ry, done and gone;

In spirit now the law of life

Will take us swiftly on.

5 Two things accomplished by our Lord

On Calvary's cross, we see:

The law of life, the end of sin!

Our God's economy.

Since all His work was finished there,

He entered into rest;

Now on the throne He prays that we

Will take our full bequest.

6 We'll drop our former concepts, Lord,

To take this finished way;

Appropriating each bequest,

We'll praise You more each day.

We'll heed our High Priest's inward call -

"Come forward!" to the end -

Until we reach the final goal;

The New Jerusalem!

< E1190 C- K- S- >

1 O Lord, You've called to us, and Canaan we would win,

To be Your corporate man and dwell with You therein;

But how the darkness of this world does hold us in -

O Lord, appear to us, we pray.

O Lord, appear to us today;

We see this is the only way.

The idols to forsake

And Canaan land partake,

O Lord, appear to us today.

2 O God of glory, shine; draw and we'll follow You.

Our strength and motive be, it's nothing we could do.

Your light attracts us, Lord, 'til all else fades from view -

O Lord, do shine on us, we pray.

O Lord, do shine on us today;

Till all our background fades away,

Till You alone we see,

Shining so gloriously -

O Lord, do shine on us today.

3 In Your appearing, Lord, we have Your speaking clear;

Your word empowers us and drives away all fear.

So, Lord, keep calling us, Your voice we need to hear.

O Lord, do speak to us, we pray.

O Lord, do speak in us today;

You know the words You need to say.

To open all our heart,

Your very Self impart.

O Lord, do speak in us today.

4 O Lord, it's not of us, we've seen it's all of You;

You are the calling One, Originator too!

We can receive this call by our beholding You -

O God of glory, come, we pray.

O God of glory, come today;

We've seen this is the only way

To answer Your dear call

That You might be our all -

O God of glory, come today.

< E1192 C- K- S- >

1 Chapter one of Genesis:

Life is God's one emphasis,

Showing Christ subjectively,

Step by step He grows in me.

2 Just as earth became a waste,

Death and darkness once I faced.

God had judged, no light did shine;

Hollowness and void were mine.

3 Satan's fall had filled the seas

With corruption, sin, disease.

Yet the Spirit brooded o'er

The abyss: chaos no more!

4 God then spoke: the air was cleared!

Darkness which I once had feared

Was dispelled by God's own light.

A new day! No longer night!

5 As the light began to shine

His discernment became mine.

I began to see aright;

God divided dark from light.

6 Then the waters He did split;

An expanse between them fit,

Earthly things from heavenly,

Separated hence they'd be.

7 On the third day God designed

That the waters be confined.

In our lives dry land must be;

No more death and no more sea!

8 God commands: death's water halt!

Christ, the good land, we exalt!

Separated from all strife

We enjoy Christ as our life.

9 Growing in us inwardly;

Grass, then herb, then fruitful tree.

We begin as but a blade;

Soon our being He'll pervade.

10 Then the fourth day lights He set;

Bearers these, more definite.

Richer light to radiate,

Higher life to generate.

11 Sun, the greater light we see

Ruling day triumphantly;

Yet when darkness fills the skies,

Waxing moon is on the rise!

12 'Tis the Church she typifies;

For her light on Christ relies.

In His image meant to be,

She reflects Christ perfectly.

13 Lastly, precious stars He placed,

Strong in spirit, full of grace;

Shining when the moon seems faint,

These are overcoming saints.

14 What a glorious picture here:

Sun and moon and stars appear!

Lord, our prayer is that we'd be

Full of light and life in Thee.

< E1193 C- K- S223 >

1 Life is God the Father in Christ Jesus

As the Spirit flowing into us.

How enjoyable, this Person wonderful!

He's our life so rich and bountiful.

2 We experienced regeneration

When we opened to this living One.

We were born again; another life came in.

Now it floods us till we're full of Him.

3 He within us is the living Spirit

In our spirit, flowing out of it

Into all our heart, transforming every part

By the life which He Himself imparts.

4 Now He must have our cooperation.

We must set our mind upon the Son.

We must turn away from all that leads astray,

Till our mind is set on Him each day.

5 Lord, our human spirit now contains You.

Still Your purpose in us You would do;

If our wandering mind would leave old thoughts behind,

Then Your life and peace in it we'll find.

6 Lord, we would our every thought be captured

By the rich enjoyment in Your Word.

In it we're supplied, our mind there will abide,

Till our thoughts are wholly sanctified.

7 Let's keep practicing the application

Of this life by minding just the Son.

Praise Him for the way to live by Him today!

Lord, on You our minds will ever stay.

< E1194 C- K- S- >

1 There are two lines to live by in our living today -

One the life line to bring us into Christ all the way.

But the other is knowledge which will make us die;

We must be very careful on which line we abide.

Oh, we'll stay on God's life line, never turning aside.

We don't care for vain knowledge, which will cause us to die.

Lord, we'll touch You by calling on Your name each day;

Living in Your appearing, in Your presence we'll stay.

2 Lord, we would be as Abel, fully contacting You;

Not by knowledge or concept, but by life fresh and new.

Just as Enosh began to call upon Your name,

And as Enoch who walked with You, we'll do just the same.

3 Keep us living and walking as did old Abraham;

In Your holy appearing to be transfused like him.

As did Isaac and Jacob, Moses lived this way -

So dependent upon Your presence with him each day.

4 Full enjoyment had David, ate the life-giving tree.

Daniel prayed to his God and lived by Him constantly.

Jesus lived by the Father to be life complete;

Now as His living Body of the life tree we'll eat.

< E1195 C- K- S285 >

1 Life is mysterious, life is God Himself,

Whose whole intention focuses on man.

God made him to take in the tree of life,

To have a man of life for His own plan.

2 But man was tempted and seduced to sin,

By taking knowledge from the other source.

This man then fell as knowledge entered in

And dominated him with all its force.

3 This knowledge has developed in the man

Into the human culture on the earth.

So man, created to fulfill God's plan,

Became a failure full of Satan's dearth.

4 Then God came in the Person of the Son;

Lived He on earth, Christ Jesus was His name -

A living model so that everyone

Could live by life, God's fullness to obtain.

5 This God-man, Christ, went to the cross and died,

By death He ended knowledge, the old man.

Things negative forever crucified,

Death He subdued, a new life He began!

6 From death He resurrected and became

The living Spirit to give life to us.

When we believe and call upon His name;

This living Spirit comes to dwell in us.

7 By this the very Triune God is now

The living Spirit mingling deep within.

Our spirit joins in oneness; this is how

We are one spirit evermore with Him.

8 'Tis by this Spirit that we walk and act,

We have our being, think, and see all things;

We're now within this Spirit! What a fact!

This Spirit to us all God's fullness brings!

9 So now we have to set our mind on Him;

Each day, each hour, our mind on Him must be;

That by this Spirit we'd be saved within

By life and reign in life eternally.

10 'Tis by this Spirit that we shall be freed

From Sin whose law inside us death would bring.

Our mortal bodies will have life indeed;

Thus sanctified we'll be in everything.

11 This Spirit shall transform our natural life,

Save us from self, build us in one new man,

Till we're conformed to be like Jesus Christ,

Thus finishing our God's eternal plan.

12 Life is our God and life is Christ our Lord.

Life is the Spirit. Life's the only way -

Till we're transfigured and redeemed to God.

We're waiting, looking forward to that day!

< E1200 C- K- S- >

1 There's a stormy wind a-blowing from the north;

Let it blow! Let it blow!

God as our exp'rience will the wind bring forth;

Let it blow! Let it blow!

Let it blow! the rushing mighty wind;

Let it blow us into life!

Let it blow! the gracious wind of God;

Let it blow us into Christ!

2 There's a hov'ring cloud a-following the wind,

Covering us! Covering us!

And the presence of the Lord the cloud does bring,

Covering us! Covering us!

Covering us, God's overshadowing cloud -

God has come to stay with us.

Covering us, the gracious cloud of God -

Strength and comfort glorious!

3 With the cloud continually a fire does flash

Burning us! Burning us!

It exposes sin, the soul life, and the flesh,

Burning us! Burning us!

Let it burn! the jealous flame of God;

Let it burn continually!

Let it burn! this all-consuming flame;

Let it burn us thoroughly!

4 Then from out the fire does the electrum glow,

Shining forth! Shining forth!

The redeeming God does our experience show,

Shining forth! Shining forth!

Let Him shine! This gold and silver One;

Let Him shine for all to see!

'Tis the Lamb-God who has now become

Our enjoyment inwardly.

5 Let the wind, cloud, fire and th' electrum be

Wrought in us, o'er and o'er;

Let this cycle be repeated constantly

More and more, more and more!

Blow and hover, burn and shine forth, Lord,

All our being to possess,

That we all may gain Thee constantly

All Thy likeness to express.

< E1201 C- K- S- >

1 From the north where God is dwelling

Comes a rushing, stormy gale.

Now the mighty Spirit blowing

All our being does assail.

We are stirred to our foundations -

How this wind awakens us!

Thus we're open for God's dealings,

And the cloud descends on us.

2 With the cloud we have His presence

Sweetly hov'ring over us;

So enveloped by His nearness;

In the Lord we put our trust.

But the cloud brings with it fire

To consume our selfish lusts;

That as ashes something higher

May be added into us.

3 Then from out the flashing fire

Comes th' electrum glowing bright.

God as gold and man as silver

Now are mingled. What a sight!

This bright metal, O Lord Jesus,

Is Thyself, Lamb-God sublime.

O Lord, work Thyself within us

Till th' electrum in us shines.

4 By our passing through this cycle,

Living creatures we become

To express the life of Jesus;

He with whom we've been made one.

We express Him as a human,

As a man so good and fine;

Balanced, normal, never striving;

Fully human, yet divine.

5 We express Him as a lion

Conquering every enemy;

As an ox obedient, lowly,

Faithful in His ministry.

We express Him as an eagle,

So transcendent, soaring high;

Never held by fear or flatter,

He above it all does fly.

6 Hallelujah! What a figure

Of the way God deals with us!

From the wind, cloud, fire, electrum,

To the creatures glorious:

As the man, the ox and lion,

As the eagle - all the four

Will be our complete expression

As we eat Him more and more.

< E1202 C- K- S- >

1 God in His justifying has a plan,

A deeper purpose for a corporate man.

When we were called, this mighty Lord of all

Appeared to us to save us from the fall.

2 We walked as strangers unaware of Him,

But in His glory God shined deep within,

Infusing His own element in us;

This precious essence was our Lord Jesus.

3 What glory! How attractive was this light!

How we appreciated such a sight!

Our first reaction was belief in Him -

This precious God has placed Himself within.

4 Our first reflection of this element

Reflected Jesus back to God, Who sent

His own response to count as righteousness

Our faith in Him Who was infused in us.

5 But we would hold to this reality,

Our Jesus Christ in us our all to be,

Enjoying all He is abundantly,

Content to have this One eternally.

6 Thus God could never be so satisfied;

Knowing that we cared only to abide

In our experiences of His Son,

Not caring for His goal to make us one.

7 Still He would seek those faithful saints who'd hear

His call to give up everything so dear,

To offer up their individual Christ;

To come together for the Body life.

< E1203 C- K- S- >

1 God is righteous in His doings,

He is perfect in His ways;

Just is He in all His actions,

And He well deserves our praise.

Righteous was His condemnation,

Righteous His requirement;

For the law had deemed us sinners,

And for judgment we were meant.

2 Oh, how blest the love that spared us,

For the law had judged us dead.

God, to meet the righteous judgment,

Passed it on His Son instead.

Hallelujah! Our Redeemer,

Christ, to God has purchased us;

Now enjoying His redemption,

We become God's righteousness.

3 God is holy in His nature,

Holiness is what He is.

In this way He sanctified us,

Makes our nature one with His.

Spreading from our quickened spirit,

He renews each inward part,

Moving into all our being,

Making home in all our heart.

4 Oh, how blessed is this process!

It's the Lord's life-saving way.

It's our constant, real experience;

It's our life from day to day.

As we're minding just the spirit,

Then the mind is life to us,

And the Lord in us is gaining

Transformation marvelous!

5 Glory is God's true expression,

All He is, in full, expressed;

Final stage of our redemption,

Bodily made manifest.

Glory is the consummation

Of this life which sanctifies;

Our complete transfiguration

Is the goal which life supplies.

6 'Tis for this we wait, expecting

To be raptured, glorified.

Then the earth will see God's fullness;

Christ completely testified.

We fore'er will just express Him,

Nature will rejoice to see

All the sons of God in glory

Manifested finally.

7 By His mercy, we're selected,

Ours a glorious destiny.

Not by running, nor by willing,

But through God's own sovereignty.

Once we were wild olive branches,

Now the root and fat partake,

Grafted in, rejoice together,

Growing for the kingdom's sake.

8 As we're daily in this process

And by life are sanctified,

How we thank Him for the blessing

Of the church life He's supplied.

Here God is our full enjoyment,

Practical and real to us;

Sons we are, and heirs together,

In the church life, glorious!

< E1207 C- K793 S- >

1 There's a way before us and a race to run -

Christ our way, Christ our way!

Turn away from everything distracting us -

Run the race, run the race!

From the altar through the Holy Place,

Through the veil into our God,

To the law of life within the ark;

'Tis the goal, our great reward.

2 There's a cloud of witnesses surrounding us,

Urging us, forward come!

There is Abel, Enoch, Jacob, Abraham,

Moses, David, Solomon.

John the Baptist greater than them all,

Even he bids forward come!

These all died in faith, receiving not

Promises that were to come.

3 The Old Testament believers give the call,

"Forward come, forward come!"

For complete perfection they depend on us

Going on! Going on!

We are at the consummation now

Of our God's economy;

Better things we are experiencing.

Praise the Lord - reality!

4 E'en the least of us is greater than their great.

We're not small, we're not small!

They are waiting, watching, and expecting us.

"Forward come!" hear their call!

They have run the race and for their sakes

We'll obey the law of life.

Till the day we'll all be joined in one

To express God's glorious Christ.

< E1209 C- K- S- >

1 Praise God for tidings glad -

We're at the throne of grace;

Our gospel's not so low,

We're in the highest place.

We're meeting here around the throne,

Enjoying God with all His own.

2 Start in the outer court,

But aim to get inside;

The Holy Place is good,

But do not there abide.

Leave sin behind - it's put away;

We're in the veil with God to stay.

3 To rise from earth to heav'n,

A deeper turn we need;

To be where Christ is now

Upon the throne indeed.

We're gathered at the throne of grace,

Beholding Jesus face to face.

4 We're being turned as one,

Not individually;

Not private Christians now.

But Body Christians we.

As members here in one accord,

We are the Body of the Lord.

5 As Body Christians now

We have a higher word.

Foundation's word we see,

'Tis altar, cross, and blood.

Perfection's word is little known,

'Tis fellowship around the throne.

6 Christ is objective too,

But subjective are we

In our experience;

Our spirit is the key.

God, throne, and holiest - we see

Our spirit now contains all three.

7 Leviticus is past,

And Aaron's work is o'er;

Melchisedec is here,

High Priest forevermore;

His ministry is now so fine:

He comes to feed us bread and wine.

< E1210 C- K- S- >

1 Through God's word, my hope at His returning

Is that all my being be redeemed;

Yet in times of grief and tribulation,

Doubt and fear arise, no hope is seen.

In those hours, when prayer cannot be uttered,

Only groaning from my breast is heard.

Then the Spirit, in like manner, helps me,

Praying in my weakness unto God.

2 Lord, my prayer is not for deeper suffering,

But that from each trial I'd be free.

Let the cup of bitterness be taken;

Yet, Thy will, not mine, dear Lord, must be.

Even now, though trials sore surround me,

Still within my heart there is a peace,

For the love of God outpoured within me

Floods my heart and bids my doubting cease.

3 Blest assurance! God has fully ordered

Every matter by His sovereign hand;

Every person (though we see so dimly),

Every thing's according to His plan.

Every trial is but the Father's answer

To the groaning of the Spirit's prayer;

May He gain in every tribulation,

Until we Christ's glory fully share.

4 How could God from all His dealings spare us,

After He spared not His only Son?

Could the Potter's hand upon the vessel

Ever leave the shaping work undone?

For the center of God's heart's desire

Is that many brethren we will be

Unto Christ, His precious First-begotten,

And to Him, conformed we'll fully be.

5 Heirs of God! Joint-heirs with our Lord Jesus!

What a hope of glory this for us!

Though the suff'rings presently seem grievous,

Greater far the glory then for us!

Yea, in all these things we more than conquer,

Through the One whose love has us possessed;

Soon the day for which waits all creation,

When the sons of God are manifest!

< E1211 C- K- S- >

1 Given us, given us, God has given us

Precious faith, power divine, greatest promises.

We believed, we received, now we have all three;

By these we may grow unto maturity.

2 Precious faith in each saint, precious equally,

Precious faith holding us, holding ceaselessly.

Disagree or agree, still it holds us fast,

Day by day, eternally this faith shall last.

3 Power divine wrought in us is the source so great;

Power divine is in us now to operate.

Hence will spring everything for our life within

And for godliness without, expressing Him.

4 Promises, promises, all God's called ones share;

Promises, given us, great and precious are.

These we take to partake of God's nature true,

Having thus escaped the world's corruption too.

5 Christ within, as the pow'r, in our spirit lives;

Christ without is the Word - all God's promises.

Now the key is that we daily contact both,

Calling, praying, reading to produce the growth.

6 Faith and pow'r, promises - these our full supply.

Diligence, diligence, let us now apply;

For if we, to these three, full attention show

From the seed of faith the fruit of love will grow.

7 In the growth from the seed many items come;

By this growth in the Lord fruitful we become.

For this we need to see what the Lord's begun,

Ne'er forgetful be nor blind to what He's done.

8 Diligence day by day will this growth insure;

Diligence thus will make our election sure.

When indeed with this seed we cooperate,

We're supplied the kingdom's entrance, rich and great.

9 For this growth, for this growth, Lord, ourselves we give,

By the faith, promises, and the pow'r to live.

Nothing more, nothing less, will our basis be

By Thy grace we will cooperate with Thee.

< E1222 Cs16 K- S370 >

1 Sing aloud your praises to the Lord of all,

Now He is dwelling in Jerusalem.

Tell among us all His doings great and small,

His throne, the heavens, yet He walks with men.

Oh, the salvation out of Zion comes;

He brought us back from our captivity.

Now we rejoice and are exceeding glad;

Now we rejoice and are exceeding glad!

2 In the Holy City with His own He dwells;

O Lord, our Lord how excellent Thy name!

He's enthroned upon the praises of His saints;

All His delight in Zion does remain.

The local churches are His move today -

He is our portion, we are satisfied.

Oh, what a goodly heritage have we;

Oh, what a goodly heritage have we!

3 Who shall in His holy tabernacle dwell,

Who shall ascend to His most holy hill?

Those who seek for Him and purify their heart;

This generation now that seeks His face.

Oh, seek His face, ye children of the earth,

Open your heart, and let the King come in.

He will come in, and He shall live and reign;

He will come in, and He shall live and reign!

4 Look! God's tabernacle now is with the saints;

Emmanuel - God with us, we proclaim.

Everything is done, so let His children come;

Christ and the church - where God and man are one!

Lift up your heads, ye cities of the earth;

Open your gates, and let the King come in.

Shout to His praise - He's coming in to reign!

Shout to His praise - He's coming in to reign!

< E1223 Cs506 K- S371 >

1 O walk about, walk about Zion,

Go round about her in love.

O walk about, walk about Zion

And count the towers thereof.

2 O set your heart on her bulwarks,

O set your heart on her walls,

O set your heart on her bulwarks,

Consider her palaces.

3 In elevation how beauteous,

The joy of all the earth!

In elevation how beauteous

Is Zion, that city of worth!

4 O there is a river in Zion

That flows so deep and so broad.

O how the streams of that river

Make glad the city of God!

5 Praise waiteth for Thee, Lord, in Zion,

Praise waiteth, O God, for Thee,

Praise waiteth for Thee, Lord, in Zion,

For Zion is filled with Thee.

6 How great the Lord is in Zion,

How greatly to be praised,

How great He is in that city

Which over the earth is raised.

7 O bless the Lord out of Zion,

O let His praises swell,

O bless the Lord out of Zion,

Ye who in Jerusalem dwell.

8 The Lord bless thee out of Zion,

The Lord bless thee o'er and o'er!

The Lord bless thee out of Zion

With life for evermore!

9 Behold how good and how pleasant

With all the brethren to be!

Behold how good and how pleasant

To dwell in unity!

10 O tell it to all generations,

O tell it to all who will come,

O tell it to all generations,

The Spirit and Bride say, "Come!"

< E1226 Cs508 K998 S373 >

1 Oh, the church of Christ is glorious,

and we are part of it -

We're so happy that the Lord has made us one!

There's a Body in the universe

and we belong to it -

Hallelujah, for the Lord has made us one!

Hallelujah for the Body!

We are members of the Body!

We are wholly for the Body!

Hallelujah, for the Lord has made us one!

2 Not the individual Christians,

but a corporate entity -

God must have it for His full expression now;

Not just individual churches

but the Body corporately -

Hallelujah, we are in the Body now!

Hallelujah for the Body!

Satan trembles at the Body!

We're victorious in the Body!

Hallelujah, we are in the Body now!

3 There are seven golden lampstands

in the nature all divine -

Nothing natural does the Body life allow.

When we're one and share God's nature,

how the lampstand then does shine -

Hallelujah, it is brightly shining now!

Hallelujah for the Body!

For the lampstands of the Body!

For the golden, shining Body!

Hallelujah, it is brightly shining now!

4 How may we express such oneness,

be divine and shining too?

Hallelujah, eating Jesus is the way!

He's the tree of life, the manna,

and the feast that's ever new -

Hallelujah, we may eat Him every day!

We are one by eating Jesus!

We're divine by eating Jesus!

How we shine by eating Jesus!

Hallelujah, eating Jesus is the way!

< E1229 C- K- S374 >

1 The church is Christ's deep longing

And His good pleasure too.

His every word and action

Is made with her in view.

His heart's love is established,

And nought can Him deter;

Before the earth's foundation

His thoughts were filled with her.

2 The eve of all creation

He mused on His delight,

And pondered every feature,

Well-pleasing in His sight.

Creation sprang to being,

But deep in Him did hide

A heart of depth unfathomed

Fixed on a glorious Bride.

3 And thus His will was 'stablished

His counterpart to gain:

This blessed, firm intention,

Eternally the same.

Though sin should e'en beguile man,

Then mock his helpless state,

He never could forsake her,

His yearning ne'er abate.

4 Then mercy richly flourished,

And love was, oh, so vast,

As graciously He sought her

With wisdom unsurpassed.

The love He gave to win her

God only comprehends!

His life laid down, an offering

Whose fragrance yet ascends.

5 And now in resurrection

To her He draws most near,

And with untold affection

In glory does appear.

As she beholds her Bridegroom,

His glory floods her heart,

'Til she, His Bride, is raptured,

His longed-for counterpart.

< E1232 Cs616 K796 S376 >

1 Once by nature we were dead in sin,

In a world of utter discord;

But together God has quickened us,

Raised us up to sit together with the Lord.

Jesus is getting us together,

Come and see the saints in one accord.

His love is knitting us together,

To the stature of the fullness of the Lord.

2 Thus with all saints we can apprehend,

All the vast dimensions of God.

Knowing Christ's love passes all we know.

We're together filled to fullness with our God.

3 Now we know the purpose of our God,

Visible the mystery became:

Christ, the church, together now we see,

And together put the enemy to shame.

4 For this cause we pray the Father God -

Strengthen Thou with might our inner man;

Make Yourself at home in all our hearts,

Root us, ground us in Your love and for Your plan.

5 In the Body we'll be fitly framed

As the many members Christ supply;

Working in the measure of each part,

All by growth in love the Body edify.

6 Now we're one His purpose to fulfill,

As the one new man of His plan.

Unto Him be glory in the church,

And in Jesus Christ forevermore - Amen!

< E1237 Cs712 K- S379 >

1 Splendid church life! His green garden!

He has brought us, praise the Lord!

To experience the Christ Who's growing here!

He is full of rich enjoyment

to His saints in one accord;

He is new and fresh, available and dear!

I'm so happy in this lovely place,

In the garden growing in His grace!

There is no finer pleasure than to eat the living tree

And to get the living water into me.

2 It is not a school or factory or a chapel in the air;

But a garden where our Lord can plant and sow.

So He's placed us all here corporately

to be his garden fair

Where He's free to cultivate and make us grow.

3 Thus within the church-life garden

there's a fruit-producing tree

Full of life and so available to eat.

So be simple, don't be hardened,

drop your concepts - eat that tree!

Take in Jesus every moment - He's so sweet!

4 With the tree there is the water,

flowing God in Christ to us,

Quenching all our dryness, ending all our strife.

Hallelujah! In His garden Jesus flows Himself to us,

As the full supply for us to grow in life.

5 Aren't you satisfied and thankful

that our Lord has brought you in

Where His pleasures and His riches flow so free?

So be happy and be joyful, in the spirit feast on Him,

So God's garden can bear fruit abundantly.

< E1240 Cs406 K832 S- >

1 Deeper, deeper, in the cross of Jesus;

Deeper let me go;

Death and life, they always go together;

Deepen, Lord, the flow.

Oh, deeper yet we pray,

Do work in us each day;

Go deeper, through and through,

Till in Thee we're wholly new.

2 Higher, higher, in the life of Jesus;

Lord, we are so low.

By Thy life we all can go much higher -

Higher let us go.

Oh, higher yet we pray - Transform us every day -

And richer in the flow;

May Thy life be all we know.

3 Growing, growing, in us He is growing,

More and more each day.

Into all our living He is flowing -

This is now His way.

For growth, O Lord, we pray;

Increase in us each day.

It's not enough to know;

Now Thy life in us must grow.

4 Living, living, Christ is all our living,

He's so practical:

Small things, big things, anything and all things -

He's involved in all.

Live Christ in every way;

Oh, live Him out today.

His name you now must call,

And give Him your all for all.

5 Person, Person, Jesus is our Person,

Living now in us.

He's our tastes, our attitudes and actions;

Oh, how glorious!

Our Person, Lord, Thou art;

Make home in all our heart.

As life in every way

Be our Person, Lord, each day.

6 Churches, churches, in the local churches

We all find the flow:

Deeper, higher, Christ as all our living,

For the church we grow.

The churches are today

Just Christ in every way.

For this, from self we cease,

For Thy Body, Thine increase.

7 Building, building, we will see the building

Of the church this way:

Christ experienced will produce the building -

He's the only way.

Oh, build us, Lord, we pray,

By growth of life each day.

Oh, make us now such men

For the new Jerusalem.

8 Coming, coming, Jesus soon is coming

For His chosen Bride.

In the churches we are all preparing

To be glorified.

Lord Jesus, come again -

This cry is deep within.

We'll praise Thee to the end,

Oh, come back! Come back! Amen!

< E1241 C- K- S- >

1 God's life and building can be seen

Within the Song of Songs;

He shows by types His seeking ones,

The Bride for whom Christ longs!

2 She, as a team of horses shows

A love, so swift and strong!

But this is love that's natural -

It pulls the world along!

3 As time goes by, her concepts change,

With dove's eyes she can see

That naught can with her love compare -

There's none so dear as He!

4 A lily she is now to Him

(For still the Lord draws on),

Her faith is not in earthly toil,

But in the wondrous Son.

5 She's next a dove who hides herself

Within a cloven rock;

Now in her Lord's ascended life

Is love which knows no shock!

6 Of smoke, a pillar she's become,

And now, as wand'ring ends,

Her wills to His will are subdued,

What fragrance sweet ascends!

7 Behold His couch... (O, can this be?)

E'en midst the fearsome night...

She now affords her Lord such rest,

The foe is put to flight!

8 A vessel to contain the King!

(This type is full of worth.)

A palanquin He's made Himself

For His move on the earth!

9 Of wood this vessel is composed:

Christ's ris'n humanity.

Its silver pillars for support

And floor of gold we see!

10 The seat of purple signifies

Christ is of kings the King.

To Him, as fittings for within,

Their love His dear ones bring!

11 The day will come - ('tis surely soon)

And glad will be Thy heart -

What boast and glory to Thyself;

Thy crown, Thy counterpart!

12 A garden fair, enclosed is she

With spices, fragrant, sweet.

She now brings forth materials

The building to complete!

13 A city pleasant, comely, too;

No greater building, this!

So beautiful, yet to the foe

A conq'ring army 'tis!

14 As we eat Jesus, praise the Lord,

The transformation's done,

Until at last, the work's complete -

Christ and His Bride are one!

< E1242 Cs125 K- S- >

1 The Lord, the seed of life, has sown Himself into our heart

To grow up into fullness and become His counterpart.

The seed requires no rules or forms, for water is its need -

By this the all-inclusive seed will grow in us indeed!

The seed is simply Jesus! Oh, Jesus lives in me!

And by His growth this seed in us will reach maturity.

2 The growth of Christ, the seed, in us

will soon produce the wheat,

The life within break forth - yet work divine is not complete;

For wheat alone can never be the seed's expression true;

So all the grains must blend together into something new.

The seed is simply Jesus; now wheat is Jesus too!

The grains of wheat must blend together into something new.

3 The individual grains of wheat no longer must be free,

But crushed together, ground to powder, every grain must be,

Until the wheat becomes the meal from which the loaf is formed

Till all the saints will blend and to His Body be conformed.

We all must take the grinding until the Christ within

Can mold into His Body all the individual grains.

4 The seed is planted, wheat is grown and meal is the sum

Of all the growth upon God's farm, where Christians grow as one;

But all the growth in life is for the building of the church,

That God and man may have a home and both may end their search.

The farm is for the building, for God and man a home,

Where both may dwell among His people gathered into one.

5 God's building is produced by silver,

precious stones, and gold -

From meal through transformation,

pressure, heat, and pain untold.

The meal must not be satisfied to stay as meal alone,

But must submit to transformation into precious stone.

The meal must pass through suffering

that precious stones be formed;

Then built into God's building, to His purpose full conformed.

6 From fullest growth and transformation comes a pearl of worth;

This simple, precious, all-inclusive gem will then come forth.

Conceived in death and formed in life by that all-glorious One,

The church, His Bride, the fruit

of all the work that He has done.

The pearl is what He's after, the Bride to please His heart,

So single, pure and precious, and His very counterpart.

7 The growth in life begins when planted

on God's farm we're found;

The growing seed becomes the wheat

from which the meal is ground.

But building work proceeds when meal

submits to be transformed;

Then gold and silver, precious stones

for building will be formed.

The farm is for the building, built up by precious stones,

From which the priceless pearl comes forth

to be His Bride, His own.

8 Lord, keep us poor in spirit, pure in heart that we may be

Good ground in which the seed of life may grow abundantly,

Until the final stage is reached and You are satisfied

And have Your priceless, chosen pearl,

Your joy complete, Your Bride.

Lord, keep us poor in spirit and purified in heart,

That growing up in us You may bring forth Your counterpart.

< E1249 C- K- S- >

1 How oft believers through the years

Have sought the will of Jesus,

And would have offered everything

To walk as Him it pleases.

If you should seek the will of God,

Don't waste another minute;

The church life is His glorious will,

And you too must get in it.

2 "What is the will of God for me?"

How oft you've asked this question.

It is the church life, corporately,

Where God finds His expression.

Don't watch the church life from afar,

Or erringly construe it;

Come gaze upon it from within -

You'll give your whole life to it.

3 The church life here is realized,

'Tis all the Lord intended;

And in this rich experience

All further seeking's ended.

The church life is His glorious will -

Now for yourself begin it.

The surest way to know His will

Is simply to get in it.

4 So let us give our all for this,

And hold ourselves not dearly;

The church life is the will of God,

Let's take our standing clearly.

Oh, we have found the will of God;

Christ died and rose to win it.

The church life is His glorious will,

And, praise the Lord, we're in it!

< E1250 C- K- S- >

1 O surely I will not come in

Within my house to stay,

Nor yet give sleep unto my eyes,

Till Jesus has His way.

Upon the earth, the Lord desires

A place where He may live;

For this, Thy habitation, Lord,

Myself I fully give.

2 We heard of it while yet far off,

We found it in the way;

We then came up into her courts,

And here we'll ever stay.

Arise, O Lord, into Thy rest,

Thou and Thy ark so strong.

Thy priests are clothed with righteousness;

Thy saints with joy and song.

3 The Lord has sworn in truth to us,

He will not turn away -

His Seed shall sit with Him enthroned,

And reign with Him for aye.

The Lord hath found a place to dwell,

Hath chosen Zion fair;

His habitation it will be,

It is His rest fore'er.

4 Her food abundant He will bless,

Her needy, satisfy;

And with salvation clothe her priests,

And all her want supply.

The horn of David's budding here,

A lamp for earth's dark night.

His enemies are clothed with shame,

His saints with crowns of light.

5 And now within these latter days,

Amidst earth's dark unrest,

God's house is being built again

And all His people blessed.

Secure within the local church,

With saints in one accord

We meet to just release our praise,

And thus enjoy the Lord.

< E1251 Cs507 K1004 S382 >

1 To Jerusalem we've come,

We are through with Babylon,

We have gathered to be one,

O glory be to God!

Of the teachings we're bereft,

All opinions we have left,

Spirit from the soul is cleft,

In the local churches now.

Hallelujah! Hallelujah!

We are all in one accord

For the building of the Lord,

Hallelujah! Hallelujah!

We are living in the local churches now!

2 That recovery may proceed

Real priests are what we need -

Those who live in Christ indeed,

O glory be to God!

Saturated with the Lord,

They have Christ as their reward.

These the building work afford

In the local churches now.

3 And the kingship we must see

With divine authority -

To this rule we'll all agree,

O glory be to God!

To the Spirit we'll submit

For the church's benefit -

This is His prerequisite

In the local churches now.

4 We the altar must obtain,

Have our all upon it lain.

The burnt-offering must be slain,

O glory be to God!

This we never should dispute,

For the church be absolute,

All that's otherwise uproot

In the local churches now.

5 The foundation now is laid -

O what glory doth pervade!

We are all with joy arrayed,

O glory be to God!

Let us raise a mighty shout -

They will hear us far without,

And the enemy we'll rout

In the local churches now.

< E1254 Cs606 K830 S384 >

1 This is the time for building the temple of the Lord

That all the local churches may fully be restored.

'Tis not the time for our house while God's house lieth waste -

O brothers, for God's building, rise up, make haste!

Be strong, be strong, God's dwelling place to build!

The Lord of hosts is with us, with His glory 'twill be filled!

Be strong, be strong, and work in one accord,

That all the nations may behold the temple of the Lord.

2 O hear, the Lord is speaking: Consider now your ways,

Ye sow and bring in little, for lacking is My praise.

Go up into the mountain, material to provide,

And build My house that I may be glorified.

3 Ye who are priests, ye remnant of Christians now obey -

The Lord Himself is with us, whatever men may say,

With spirits stirred and burning, now let us come to work;

May none his part with others in building shirk.

4 I'll fill this house with glory, the Lord of hosts has said,

And the desire of nations will be exhibited.

Its glory will be greater than all that's gone before,

And we will share this glory forevermore.

< E1257 Cs514 K- S- >

1 Do you see them in the cities,

Meeting on the local ground?

They're the local, golden lampstands,

Where the Lord His home has found.

'Tis the local church, the church God has chosen,

Where all the saints dwell as one!

'Tis the local church, the church God has chosen,

Where all the saints dwell as one!

2 Do you see them in the meetings,

Lifting up their voice on high,

Every brother, sister sharing,

Christ the Lord to magnify?

3 Do you hear them all pray-reading,

Breathing in the living Word?

Praying, praising, drinking, feeding,

How they all enjoy the Lord!

4 Do you hear them call, "Lord Jesus"?

How they love that blessed name!

All the more their joy increases

As His Lordship they proclaim.

5 Have you heard their hallelujahs,

Like a mighty thunder blast?

Hallelujah! Hallelujah!

Down the enemy is cast!

6 Do you see the saints migrating?

Praise the Lord the move is on

For the church in every city

That our blessed Lord may come!

7 Do you see the Lord is coming

For the church for whom He died?

In the churches He's preparing

Now His holy, chosen Bride.

'Tis a glorious church without spot or wrinkle,

Filled with the glory of the Lord!

'Tis a glorious church without spot or wrinkle,

Filled with the glory of the Lord!

< E1263 C- K- S- >

1 There's a church in New York City

Standing on the local ground;

There's a lampstand brightly beaming,

Shining out to millions 'round.

We were raised from every nation,

Every people, tribe, and tongue -

With us God has gained a dwelling,

'Tis where all His own may come.

2 In your midst, O New York City,

Little do you realize -

Fallen is a seed within you,

'Midst corruption it shall rise;

Rising up in resurrection,

With an increase many fold,

It shall blossom, manifesting

Riches of God's life untold.

3 For the church in New York City

Faithfully the saints have prayed.

'Gainst the church in New York City

How the devil is enraged!

For behold, within the center

Of his kingdom, dark and grim,

God has gained a testimony,

Moving, fighting on for Him.

4 There's a church in New York City

Who the gospel does proclaim,

To the hungry, poor, and weary,

Sick, imprisoned, and the lame.

Now this gospel of the kingdom

Shall be preached until the end;

Till the Lord who with the kingdom

Of the heavens does descend.

5 There's a church in New York City,

Honoring the risen Christ;

Caring for the other churches -

Following in truth and light;

With them in coordination,

We the kingdom will possess;

Fighting as one mighty army,

Till the kingdom's manifest.

< E1265 C- K827 S387 >

1 The churches are the Body

Of Christ on earth today.

They are His testimony,

That He may have a way.

They are the golden lampstands

In cities far and wide.

They are His fighting army,

And His beloved Bride.

The churches, the churches,

Upon the earth today;

Lord, stir our hearts for Thy desire,

And build us, oh, build us, Lord, we pray.

2 Oh, how we need the churches,

All of them, great or small!

We need their many portions

To profit us withal.

Yes, Lord, enlarge the churches;

We love their needs to bear.

Enlarge our hearts, Lord Jesus,

In fellowship and prayer.

3 The Lord's eyes o'er the whole earth

Are running to and fro;

Those seven, burning, searching,

Our heart's desire to know.

His purpose - many churches,

Built up in one accord;

This golden testimony

Will thus express the Lord.

4 And soon will be the coming

Of our triumphant King!

He's coming for the churches

Where His sweet praises ring.

Come, Lord, come reap the firstfruits,

As draws the harvest nigh,

And to Thy throne do take us,

To reign with Thee on high.

< E1267 C- K- S- >

1 We are for the great migration,

And, O Lord, we seek Thy face.

Who? and when? and where? Lord Jesus,

Grant us now Thy blessed grace.

2 This is for Thy house and city,

This is for Thy kingdom, Lord;

To subdue the earth before us

We are all in one accord.

3 Of the Father, through Christ Jesus,

By the Spirit's flowing free;

In our spirit, on the church-ground -

This the way of victory.

4 Burden us with Thy great plan, Lord;

Consecrated we would be.

To fulfill Thy holy purpose

Saturate us thoroughly.

5 Build, O build us all together,

Let us here our lessons learn,

Send us forth to many cities

For the church-life there to burn.

6 Many places need a beachhead

To bring in Thy reign and rule.

Lord, build up the local churches

That Thy kingdom come in full!

7 Then the earth will give Thee glory

And the devil get the shame.

For Thy kingdom's rule and reigning

All will praise Thy glorious name.

8 Blessed days are quickly coming;

We rejoice and give Thee praise

For the glorious consummation

And Thy royal ruling days.

9 Hallelujah to the Father,

Hallelujah to the Son,

Hallelujah to the Spirit -

Hallelujah, it is done!

10 Hallelujah for the churches,

Hallelujah for the saints,

Hallelujah for the meetings

And their holy, sweet constraints!

11 Hallelujah, hallelujah,

Hallelujah we will sing;

Hallelujah, hallelujah,

Hallelujah to our King!

< E1268 C- K- S- >

1 When Noah worked upon the ark as God to him decreed,

So many others watched, yet to his words they gave no heed.

But Noah heard the voice of God and did His word obey;

His business was to build the ark; he couldn't waste a day.

Now Jesus' testimony, we in the churches see,

The ark of testimony built in each locality.

2 The generation at that time was evil and perverse;

The wickedness upon the earth was waxing worse and worse.

But Noah stood against the age and ne'er the vision lost.

The ark of testimony must be built at any cost.

3 There were at that time many men who said they worshipped God;

They served Him and they sacrificed and yet 'twas very odd,

The very thing that God desired they mocked and ridiculed.

Their heart was set upon this age and by the devil ruled.

4 One day the ark was finished and eight souls were led aboard.

God shut the door and then the heavens opened and outpoured.

It rained, but Noah took no thought for he was safe inside.

When all the earth was flooded, he above it all did ride.

5 The ark was just God's testimony on the earth that time.

For God had found a corporate man

through whom His light could shine.

He needed something built through which

He'd fully be expressed,

And now it is the local church where God is manifest.

6 Be careful lest this age would lead you from

God's heart's desire.

For Jesus' testimony must set all our hearts afire.

The local churches are the ark, God's testimony true.

For this we leave the age behind and give our hearts anew.

< E1269 C- K- S- >

1 There in old Chaldea, product of man's fall,

God appeared to Abram - called him from it all.

"Get thee from thy country, from thy father's clan,

Get thee from thy kindred to another land."

Our Lord God Jehovah called a corporate man,

One that would express Him and fulfill His plan.

2 Through the Lord's infusion, Abraham became

Father of the faithful - life had changed his name.

Though the Lord's appearing, brought him to the land,

Still he needed Isaac to fulfill God's plan.

3 Isaac from his father did inherit all:

Sonship's full enjoyment, blessing of God's call.

Though all things receiving, incomplete was he;

Lacking transformation and maturity.

4 In his father's footsteps, Jacob then became

Prince of God, a wrestler, Israel his name;

By the Spirit's dealing, fully grown, he reigned;

O'er the earth, through Joseph, ruling pow'r obtained.

5 Thus do Jacob, Isaac, Abraham portray

Path that we, God's called ones, must walk in today:

Members of the Body, as a corporate man,

We complete His calling and fulfill His plan.

< E1270 C- K- S- >

1 We are the Hebrews! Praise the Lord!

We're from the other side.

Throughout our hist'ry we have passed

Through rivers deep and wide.

Praise the Lord! Praise the Lord!

He has brought

All us river-crossing Hebrews

To the land, to build up

The temple of our God.

2 Old Noah's age was so corrupt,

In deep depravity;

So Noah passed across the flood -

That separating sea.

Praise the Lord! He has brought

From the old

To a new recovered region

Where he built in this land

An altar for his God.

3 Then Abraham was called apart,

For God to take a stand;

So through the river he was led

Into a new, good land.

Step by step he was led

From Chaldee

Through the river into Canaan,

That good land, there to be

The servant of his God.

4 The Israelites in bondage were

To Pharaoh's choking hand.

The God of Hebrews made a way

For them to leave that land.

Through the sea, they all passed;

Egypt fell,

Hallelujah! In the good land

They built up God's own house

To satisfy His heart.

5 Then wand'ring through the wilderness,

The land they could not find;

Till through the Jordan they did pass

To leave themselves behind.

Praise the Lord! In the land

They built up

God's own temple. Hallelujah!

Praise the Lord! There they dwelt,

His people and their God.

6 But then religion conquered all,

So John the Baptist came

And buried all beneath that flood.

The Jews were not the same.

Buried all! Buried all!

Buried all!

Underneath the Jordan River

Buried all to become

The Hebrews passing through.

7 Now in the church life, we have left

The world, religion too;

Now we're the river-crossing ones,

Enjoying Christ so new!

Praise the Lord! Praise the Lord!

We have passed

From the oldness, Hallelujah,

Into Christ - one new man.

And now we're one with Him!

8 O Lord, You've taken us across

The fiery sea of glass,

With all the worldly things beneath;

Across the sea we've passed.

Praise the Lord! Praise the Lord!

Now we stand

As the Hebrews, Hallelujah,

On the sea! Praise the Lord!

We've passed through everything!

< E1271 C- K981 S- >

1 We're the river-crossers, Hebrews is our name;

Crossed the Euphrates, idols all are slain.

Entered into Canaan, left the other side;

Seeking a city, which shall e'er abide.

We are the Hebrews, that's our real name;

We've crossed the river, we are not the same.

Building God's house that He may dwell on earth,

Building God's house that He may dwell on earth.

2 We were bound in Egypt, building for the foe;

God of the Hebrews said, "Let My people go!"

We have crossed the Red Sea, reached the other side;

Pharaoh, his army, perished in the tide.

God of the Hebrews, speak again today;

God of the Hebrews, lead us all the way.

Save all Your people from this crooked age,

Save all Your people from this crooked age

3 We're released, and now we build the house of God;

His tabernacle is our true abode.

Forty years of oldness left in Jordan's tide,

Fight we for Canaan on the kingdom side.

Salvation's Captain sounds the trump of war;

City by city, take we more and more,

To gain His kingdom, enter into rest,

To gain His kingdom, enter into rest.

4 What was once God-given soon a form became;

Then John the Baptist did God's word proclaim -

Make another crossing, God is going on;

Judaism's over; listen to My Son!

Turn from the prophets, turn unto the Son;

He's My Beloved, He and I are one;

His Word will save you to the uttermost,

His Word will save you to the uttermost.

5 Now we're overcomers on the sea of glass;

This final crossing will forever last.

Sing the song of Moses, make the praise complete,

Look! All our enemies beneath our feet.

We're overcomers, that's our real name.

God has His city; Satan gets the shame.

God is our portion for eternity,

God is our portion for eternity.

< E1274 Cs512 K- S- >

1 In Revelation two and three,

The seven local churches see:

The lessons there for you and me

Are for the Lord's recovery.

2 The words to them are words to us,

So that the church be glorious,

And all their warnings we must heed

So that the Lord can meet His need.

3 To Ephesus, the word is clear:

"To your first love you're not so near;

You've left to work so far away;

Repent, return to Him today."

4 Thus, we must all turn back to Him,

Leave other loves, for these are sin.

Oh, let us hearken to His call -

If we miss this, we've missed it all!

5 Then unto Smyrna, suffering, sore -

"You have been tried, but something more -

Be faithful unto death," we're told

(Not just of body but of soul).

6 Be faithful 'til what's natural dies;

Your circumstances don't despise;

The Lord has sent them all to you

To prove that your first love is true.

7 From Pergamos we clearly see

The world has wed Christianity!

And faithful Antipas did fall -

He dared to stand against it all.

8 To wed the world we all must fear:

His spoken word will save us here -

If to His speaking we give heed,

We'll separated be indeed.

9 Then Thyatira comes at length:

Her mixture with the world her strength.

Fine flour leavened by the yeast,

A harlot riding on a beast.

10 Lord, we are mixed but hardly know;

To us this mixture fully show.

Each added thing we will refute

Until we're wholly absolute.

11 And then from Sardis, we can know

Life is the way that we must go!

She says she's living, but she's dead;

She needs to touch the Lord instead.

12 Lord, take us all the way to life

To overcome the deadness rife.

Away from deadness we would flee

That full of life we'll always be.

13 Now Philadelphia comes at last;

That which she has she should hold fast -

The brothers' love, the name, the word;

This church has satisfied the Lord.

14 We as the brothers all are one;

We're one by life, and life alone.

If we His word and name do keep

A glorious building God will reap.

15 Laodicea warns us all:

From Philadelphia some will fall.

By saying, "I am rich," it's then

The Lord is outside wanting in.

16 Lukewarmness we must ever spurn

And in the spirit always burn,

The inward life experience gain,

And pay the price with Him to reign.

17 Lord, shine Your light on us today

That we may fully go Your way;

Anoint our eyes and let us see

So You can have recovery.

< E1275 C- K- S389 >

1 Glorious things of thee are spoken,

Philadelphia, church of love.

These things saith the One who's holy,

He who's real speaks from above;

He that has the key of David,

Who the kingdom's entrance won,

"I will open, no man shutteth" -

He has spoken; it is done.

2 Hallelujah, Philadelphia,

Thine are works that please the Lord.

Strength thou hast, though just a little

And hast kept His living Word.

Thou His holy name denied not,

But confessed it here below -

Lo, a door is set before thee,

Through which none but thee can go.

3 Thou, beloved Philadelphia,

Dost His Word of patience keep.

From the hour of trial He'll save thee,

Which o'er all the world shall sweep.

Troublers too shall know He loves thee;

They to thee must then bow down.

"Hold thou fast, for I come quickly,

That no man may take thy crown."

4 Hallelujah, overcomers,

"In the temple of My God,

I will build them in as pillars,

Nevermore to go abroad."

God's own name is written on them

And the new name of the Lord.

With the triune God they're blended;

They're the city of our God.

5 Hallelujah, out of heaven,

Comes the New Jerusalem:

Gates of pearl and walls of jasper,

Mingled with each precious gem.

Philadelphia, Philadelphia,

Has become His Bride so dear.

Now the Spirit in the churches

Speaks to all who have an ear.

< E1276 C- K- S- >

1 Oh, the Lord is quickly coming,

He has spoken in His Word;

And confirmed it by the churches,

For His Spirit we have heard.

2 Not to all the seven churches

Did the Lord speak in this way;

To the church in Philadelphia

Did He choose these words to say.

3 Philadelphia, Philadelphia,

Church so full of brotherly love,

You're the church to bring the Bridegroom

Back to earth from heav'n above.

4 He that hath the key of David,

He that shuts and opens too,

Knows thy works, O Philadelphia;

That's why you're His Bride so true.

5 Not so strong by worldly standards,

Hidden from religion's fame;

Jesus loves you, Philadelphia,

For you're faithful to His name.

6 By His Word you're overcoming -

How the Amen does resound!

Just hold fast to what you've gotten,

That no man may take your crown.

7 You have kept His Word of patience;

He will keep you from that hour

Which upon the whole world cometh

When the Lord comes in His power.

8 "I come quickly," Philadelphia,

Speaks the Lord to none but you;

"Amen! Quickly come, Lord Jesus,"

Answer back His faithful few.

< E1287 Cs243 K- S404 >

1 Let's take the land! The land that God has given us;

In all our living, Christ can be so much;

To take this land, we have th' equipment that we need -

The blood, the Word, the Spirit, and the church.

Let's take the land! O Christian brothers,

The land that God has given us.

Be strong and take it, for we can make it

And gain this land so glorious!

Let's take the land! O Christian sisters,

And to these things give earnest heed.

The Lord implores us; He's gone before us

And given everything we need!

2 We have the blood! Christ is our spotless offering,

Who gave Himself, our God to satisfy;

And so we come with boldness to the throne of grace,

And all day long, the precious blood apply.

3 We have the Word! The written Word's our daily food;

We mix this Word with faith and say "Amen!"

Then thro' the day, the spoken Word will speak to us

And regulate our living from within.

4 The Spirit's ours! The Spirit of reality,

He's independent of the way we feel;

He dwells in us, and teaches us to dwell in Him,

And guides us into everything that's real.

5 We have the church! All saints are needed to possess

The fullness of this vast reality;

Together we will gain this all-inclusive Christ,

And He to us our everything will be.

< E1290 C- K- S- >

1 O Lord, we've seen Your purpose to bring the many sons

To share in Your full glory and see Your kingdom come.

We praise You, Lord, this glory is You, Yourself within,

Spread out in all Your people to shine in all of them.

2 Since we received Your life, Lord, a seed's been growing there:

The seed of inward glory, the glory we will share!

By growing 'til the blossom of glory blooms in full,

We'll thus enjoy Your increase and glory bountiful.

3 Hail! Captain of Salvation! Our heav'nly Pioneer!

Our praises, midst the battle and tumult, You will hear.

We're following our Captain all through the mighty fray.

Our glorious, faithful Captain sustains us all the way.

4 Lord, fighting on to glory, You now have gone before;

Now fighting in Your footsteps we'll conquer o'er and o'er.

From glory unto glory, we'll fight until we see

The glory from within us shall manifested be.

5 Then, Lord, at last the fighting and battle cry will cease,

And we'll appear in glory, Your kingdom and increase.

That day we'll be completed, that day Your face we'll see,

For in that blessed day, Lord, we'll in the glory be!

< E1294 C- K- S- >

1 Come let us speak till the kingdom of the Lord comes down.

Yes, let us speak till the kingdom of the Lord comes down.

Why hold your peace?

The Word release.

Let us speak until the kingdom of the Lord comes down.

2 Oh, loose the Word! It shall not return unto Him void.

Yes, loose the Word! It shall not return unto Him void.

Let's sow the seed,

This is our need;

Loose the Word, and it shall not return unto Him void!

3 It's gospel time! Let us spread the gospel all around.

Yes, gospel time! We will never fear the people's frown!

God's done His work;

Let us not shirk;

We're but pilgrims here, and we'll not fear the people's frown!

4 If we will speak, Christ will witness in the hearts of men.

If we will speak, Christ will witness in the hearts of men.

Tell every man,

Win all we can.

Through our speaking, Christ is speaking in the hearts of men!

5 The harvest's ripe! We are preaching the full gospel now!

The fields are white! We are preaching the full gospel now!

For this men search - Christ and the church!

Let us reap the harvest, preaching the full gospel now!

< E1295 C- K1014 S420 >

1 Ours is a fellowship in the gospel

Since we received the Lord;

We're for the furtherance of the gospel,

Spreading to all His Word.

For its defense and strong confirmation

We all partake of grace -

He who began this work will perfect it

Till we shall see His face.

2 May all the things that come to us daily

Unto the gospel turn,

That all may see we're bound for the gospel

And of the Lord may learn.

May we be bold and fearless in spirit,

Speaking the Word of God,

Do it in love and do it in power,

While living in the Lord.

3 Lord, we're expecting that we'll be given

Boldness with every breath.

Christ must be magnified in our body

Whether by life or death.

We hope in nothing to be ashamed,

For us to live is Christ -

He is the Person in all our living,

Our everything, our life.

4 May all our lives be worthy the gospel

Whatever may betide,

All standing fast in oneness of spirit,

All striving side by side.

Let us proclaim the gospel in fullness

To satisfy the Lord:

Christ is the life, the church His expression,

Sound everywhere abroad.

< E1296 C- K- S- >

1 The universe of God consists

Of heaven, earth, and air.

The enemy of God resists

His purpose everywhere.

At first the mighty rebel one

The earth from God obtained;

Then from the Lord the air had won,

Establishing his reign.

2 So God's intention was to gain

His kingdom on the earth,

The place where He could fully reign

And show to all His worth.

Thus He began in Genesis

To forward His great plan.

Out of this darkened, lost abyss

Our God created man.

3 But Satan caused the man to fall

From God's eternal grace.

Then Abraham received the call

To head the chosen race.

The Jews were led from Pharaoh's hand

Through sea and wilderness

Into the promised Canaan land,

God's kingdom to express.

4 The Israelites refused God's reign,

Desired an earthly king;

The kingdom then was lost again

Till David was to bring

God's kingdom back to earth once more

For God to rule through him;

But Israel failed as once before

God's kingdom to bring in.

5 Such was the situation when

Our God became a man,

Declaring to all men, "Repent!

The kingdom is at hand."

A perfect model of God's rule,

The King, full qualified!

But Satan as a desperate fool

Had Jesus crucified.

6 This Jesus went into the grave

And death He overcame.

Now resurrected He will save

The earth from Satan's reign.

He as the Spirit enters man

To fill him with His life.

These men, the church, fulfill His plan

To save the earth from strife.

7 Now on the earth the church we see,

God's kingdom here expressed,

Where He has full authority

His rule to manifest.

The place where Satan has to flee

Our mighty conquering rod,

The kingdom through the church will be

Brought to the earth for God.

< E1300 C- K- S- >

1 The Lord has been revealed in us,

The kingdom-seed so glorious;

He's planted deeper than our heart,

And from us He will ne'er depart.

This seed is never satisfied

Just in our spirits to abide;

He wants to grow and spread today

To live in us in every way.

2 We're like a glove, an empty man,

So meaningless without a hand;

Lord, saturate each inward part

And form Yourself in all our heart.

The Lord must spread into our mind,

Our natural thoughts and concepts bind;

Imaginations, dreams be gone,

The kingdom-seed in us is sown!

3 In our emotions He must grow;

Raw, fragile feelings overthrow;

Our love, our hatred, must be His -

Lord, we agree with You for this.

Another part the Lord must fill -

Our hard, unbending, stubborn will;

Lord, our resistance quickly break,

Subdue us for Thy kingdom's sake.

4 Our conscience too the Lord must clear,

That we may walk in godly fear;

Our conscience must be keen today,

Else we cannot the Lord obey.

'Tis by His growing, spreading thus,

The Lord will have His home in us;

A place on earth where He is Lord,

Full rights to Him we will afford.

< E1303 Cs914 K- S- >

1 The kingdom of God is at hand:

Ten virgins with lamps lit arise

To go forth to meet the Bridegroom,

But only five virgins are wise.

The wise have abundance of oil,

The foolish are empty instead;

The wise used their time to buy oil,

The others their chance forfeited.

2 Lord Jesus, Thy message is clear:

You're coming for those who are wise,

Who buy up their oil today,

Who deal with all hindering ties.

Those virgins whose souls are transformed,

Whose vessels much oil contain,

Who love not their lives unto death -

They in Thy great kingdom shall reign.

3 Our lamps to shine forth must be trimmed

By calling on Thee every day.

In spirit we must exercise

To burn all the oldness away.

But there is a much deeper need:

Reality in us must grow,

Until it make home in our hearts,

Till oil in our vessels o'erflows.

4 We see how this age is so dark,

We know that blest hour is near.

Our Lord may return anytime -

Lord, strike in us this holy fear,

That we may each moment redeem

By taking Thy Word in by prayer,

By learning each lesson You give,

And thus for that hour prepare.

5 Lord Jesus, how blest to be those

Who bring in Thy kingdom to earth,

Affording Thee rule over all

And showing to all Thy great worth!

How blest to be those at the feast,

Where Thou wilt be one with Thy Bride!

Lord, make us wise virgins for Thee,

Who e'er in Thy presence abide.

< E1304 C- K- S- >

1 Christ comes quickly for His Bride,

Wedding feast He will provide,

Garments bright and pure supplied -

Dress in time!

Taking Christ as life she's dressed,

By much suffering stitched and pressed;

Righteous acts are thus possessed -

Dress in time!

Be in time! Be in time!

For the marriage feast of Jesus

Be in time!

If your soul life you deny

And the Spirit you apply,

Then you'll fully qualify -

Be in time!

2 Virgins Christ comes quickly for,

Those with oil an extra store,

Not the fools who oil ignore -

Buy in time!

For the oil a price we pay,

Deal with self without delay,

Fill your vessels every day -

Buy in time!

3 For His servants Christ will come

And reward each faithful one;

Slothful ones will be undone -

Serve in time!

Make your single talent count,

All self's problems now surmount,

Serve with Christ, the living fount -

Serve in time!

4 Christ comes quickly for His grain,

Ripened firstfruits to obtain;

Unripe harvest will remain -

Ripen now!

From earth's water grain must dry,

From the world your soul deny;

To mature the self must die -

Ripen now!

5 Overcomers Christ will take,

Those who all for Him forsake,

Those who of first love partake -

Win in time!

All the deadness overcome,

With the living Christ be one,

Toward the goal now swiftly run -

Win in time!

6 Christ comes for His kingdom too;

Heav'nly reign we must pursue,

Let His rule our self subdue -

Yield in time!

Rebel self must be dethroned,

Lessons must not be postponed,

Quickly yield to Christ enthroned -

Yield in time!

< E1307 C- K- S- >

1 The day approaches; Jesus soon is coming.

Redeem the time; it must not slip away.

Lord, make us ready for the cry: "Behold Him!"

By using every moment of each day.

When Jesus comes, will we go in to meet Him?

When Jesus comes, will we from self have ceased?

He's coming soon to take the wise ones with Him.

Oh, let us not be left outside the feast.

2 Lord, help us to redeem these golden moments;

Our vessels fill with ointment from above;

Help us amen each trial and tribulation;

Increase in us; make us abound in love.

He's coming soon - these moments are so precious.

The oil is here - Oh, let us buy the more.

Amen the trials and welcome tribulations -

The kingdom's ours through these afflictions sore.

3 Lord, ever turn us from our soulish pleasures

To gaze upon Thy tender, loving face.

Oh, keep us running forth to meet the Bridegroom

And patiently attending to the race.

When Jesus comes, will we be in His presence?

When Jesus comes, will we His face behold?

Oh, let us not return to sloth and folly,

But jealously His loving presence hold.

4 As His dear Bride, let us go forth to meet Him,

Our lamps well-trimmed, our fires burning bright,

Our vessels filled, our eyes set on His glory,

To be with Him completely satisfied.

Yes, satisfied - Christ and His Bride together,

Yes, satisfied - throughout eternity.

Oh, what a rest, what joy, what love, what favor

To be His Bride when He comes to His feast!

< E1313 C- K861 S- >

1 In that bright and golden moment

when the Christ we love shall come,

And the radiance of His glory we shall see;

When the Bride shall meet the Bridegroom

and His loving wife become,

What a meeting, what a meeting that will be!

What a meeting, what a meeting,

What a meeting with our Lover,

with our Bridegroom in the air!

What a meeting, what a meeting,

What a meeting any moment we will share!

2 When to all who love His coming

He shall speak the word, "Arise!"

Oh, how blessed for that summons to be free!

With what rapture we shall greet Him

as we join Him in the skies -

What a meeting, what a meeting that will be!

3 Now in all the local churches

we are meeting day by day

And expecting any moment Christ to see,

But when Jesus comes the meeting starts

that ne'er will pass away -

What a meeting, what a meeting that will be!

4 Even now while we are meeting, Lord,

we hope to see Thy face

And forever without ceasing be with Thee.

Then we'll just go right on meeting

in another meeting place -

What a meeting, what a meeting this will be!

< E1317 C- K- S- >

1 When our Lord comes in glory and we're raptured to His side,

When that bright and glorious moment we shall see,

We shall know our dear Bridegroom as He comes to take His Bride,

And He'll know the Bride He's loved so tenderly.

We shall know Him! We shall know Him!

When we see Him, our Bridegroom glorified!

He shall know us! He shall know us!

We're His church, His beloved, and His Bride!

2 Even now in the Spirit He reveals Himself to us,

And His Person dear we've learned to recognize.

But our eyes shall behold Him - O what rapture glorious

When we gaze on Him unveiled in the skies!

3 In the Word we have seen Him shining forth in truth and grace,

O how blessed to behold His features thus!

But the day soon is coming when we'll see Him face to face,

He, the living Word, in full revealed to us.

4 In the brothers and sisters, O how blest to see the Lord,

In their attitudes and actions Christ expressed!

But the day soon is coming when in rapturous accord

We shall see His Person fully manifest.

5 In the meetings of the churches He's unveiled increasingly -

O the joy unspeakable and glory too!

As the meetings grow higher we're expecting soon to see

The full glory of our Lord come into view.

< E1321 C- K- S- >

1 The grace which God bestows on us

Is just His Son in full;

The rich enjoyment of this Christ

Is plenteous, bountiful.

'Tis far too great to comprehend,

Too wondrous to contain:

How we, once children of despair,

God's masterpiece became.

2 The whole creation now beneath

The weight of bondage sore,

In seeing God's sons manifest

Is freed forevermore.

Th' eternal purpose of our God

Will be full manifest;

The hope of glory now concealed

Is then to all expressed.

3 The briars will be myrtle trees,

The thorn will be no more,

And peace will reign where war did rage,

The curse will then be o'er.

'Tis then the trees shall clap their hands,

And all the hills shall sing;

This glorious freedom shall God's sons

Thus manifested bring.

4 God's deepest work of grace goes on

Each day, though hidden, small,

Until that day, when manifest,

It is revealed to all.

By then God's wrought His finished work:

Himself dispensed to us;

And all creation 'round admires

His product, glorious.

5 The angels that before our God

In brightest splendor stand,

Will join the universal praise

To Him for all He's planned.

And of the devil, of his end . . . ?

We'll praise the Lord for how

Just distant smoke is all that's left

Of all that troubles now.

6 So shall we not delight to give

Ourselves in every way,

And let the Lord dispense Himself

Into us more each day;

The grace that we receive each day,

Though hidden oft, and small,

Is God Himself wrought into us,

That day to shine o'er all.

< E1322 C- K- S- >

1 In spirit, in the church we see

The high estate we're destined for.

It's higher, vaster, more profound

Than anything we've seen before.

2 It's not a view in doctrine bare

But an unveiling of the Christ.

He's marvelous and far beyond

Our mental thought or power to share.

3 He's rich, unlimited, profound,

Immeasurable, and marvelous.

Yet 'tis a greater wonder still

He needs heirs of salvation - us.

4 God has accomplished many things -

He's planned, created, and brought forth.

The Son is now appointed Heir,

Administrator of God's worth.

5 But in th' economy of God

There is not one, but many sons.

One is the firstborn Son of God

With many other living ones.

6 Christ will inherit all God's things,

And we're the heirs of God with Christ.

We're growing now to be matured;

As heirs we'll soon be legalized.

7 We're joint-heirs with the firstborn Son,

Inheriting the universe.

We're in this corporation vast -

All partners of Christ and the church.

8 In spirit, in the church, we see

Our calling of unrivaled worth.

We're destined, not to go to heaven.

We're destined to be kings on earth.

9 We're paupers, yet we're glorious kings.

Inheriting the kingdom vast,

The earth, God's throne, and e'en all things

And all the Father is and has.

< E1323 C- K- S- >

1 The voice of my Beloved,

Behold, He quickly comes;

He leaps upon the mountains,

And o'er the hills He runs.

The signs of His appearing

Are seen on every side;

The Bridegroom soon is coming

To claim His loving Bride.

2 How real that He is coming -

Come quickly, Lord, again!

We watch for His appearing,

His precious Word amen.

Oh, don't delay His coming,

Pray without ceasing, pray;

He's eagerly awaiting

That coming wedding day.

3 He longs to hear our voices,

He longs to see our face -

Our voices filled with sweetness,

Our countenance with grace.

"Arise, My love, My fair one,"

We long to hear Him say.

The voice of our Beloved -

"Arise and come away!"

4 The winter rain is over,

The flowers appear on earth;

The rising sun of Jesus

Fills all our hearts with mirth.

It is the time of singing,

The turtle dove is heard;

For our Beloved's coming

The sweetest chords are stirred.

5 Oh, let us take the foxes

That spoil the blooming vine;

Our vineyards are in blossom,

And all, Beloved, is Thine.

The day is quickly dawning,

The shadows flee away;

Upon the mount of spices

Our Lord may come today.

< E1324 C- K- S- >

1 Our God is a God of purpose,

What He plans, He will fulfill!

Genesis to Revelation

Shows His full and glorious will.

What He's after is a building.

In creation He began

With a simple garden planted -

This, the setting for His plan.

2 Man was made, the first step God took

To achieve His final goal,

As a vessel, a container,

Three parts - body, spirit, soul.

God, of dust, a body formed him,

Breath of life into him breathed -

This part is man's human spirit

By which God may be received.

3 In the garden God had planted

Every tree He made to grow,

Good for food, to sight most pleasing,

And the tree of life also!

Second, then, in God's intention

Was that man should freely eat

Of the life-tree in the center

To obtain His life complete.

4 Third, we see a river flowing,

Out of Eden coming forth,

With its flow in four directions -

East and west and south and north.

As on Christ our life we're feeding,

Living water in us flows.

Hallelujah for this river

And the watering it bestows!

5 In the flowing of the river

Gold, pearl, onyx stone we see;

Three materials, raw yet precious,

For God's building meant to be.

Look, these elements are shining!

How can we, then, shine as they?

Simply by the Lord, the Spirit,

Us transforming every day.

6 God the Father (in this fourth step),

Source of life, is gold divine;

Christ the Son was wounded by us

To produce the pearl so fine.

God the Spirit brings the stones forth -

Transformation of the clay.

By the flowing of the Spirit

Changed we'll be from day to day.

7 Insufficient are materials

Precious though they be and best;

These must be built up together

That God's house they may express.

Fifth step: We ourselves hand over

To the building that we be

Built into God's house, His dwelling,

One in each locality.

8 Finally, in Revelation,

Is the picture of Christ's Bride -

Consummation of God's purpose;

He is fully satisfied.

New Jerusalem, a city,

Is the Bridegroom's counterpart -

So the church built up together

Forms the Bride for Christ's own heart.

9 How can we, as those who truly

Long to see God reach His goal,

Be united and related?

By denial of our soul!

As we contact Christ in spirit,

Feed on Him as life to us,

Then His life will flow, transform us

To His Bride, all glorious!

< E1325 C- K- S459 >

1 God eternal has a purpose,

Formed in His eternal past,

Spreading to eternal future;

'Twixt these ends all time is cast.

For with time there is the process,

Time for His accomplishment;

And in time we're merely travelers -

For eternity we're meant.

2 God would have a group of people

Built together in His plan,

Blended, knit, coordinated

As His vessel - one new man.

God would come into this vessel

With His nature, life and ways,

Mingling Spirit with our spirits

For His joy and to His praise.

3 God has worked in three directions

For His plan so marvelous:

As the Father, Son, and Spirit

To dispense Himself to us!

All creation gives the setting -

Heav'n and earth are for this plan;

'Tis for this God made a body,

Soul and spirit - three-part man.

4 As the center, as the kernel,

Of God's plan our spirit is;

Calling on the name of Jesus

Makes our spirit one with His.

From the center to circumference

God would saturate each part;

Feeling, mind, and will renewing,

Making home in all our heart.

5 Thus in life we're built together,

Then in love we're knit as one;

God is now His plan fulfilling,

Finishing what He's begun.

Lord, increase Thyself within us

That we might be built by Thee

Into that great corporate vessel

Filled with God exclusively.

6 As the product, the fulfillment,

Will the church in glory stand,

Consummation of the purpose

In eternal ages planned.

God will have His corporate vessel,

All his glory to contain;

Lord, we're wholly for Thy purpose

All Thy goal in us attain.

< E1327 Cs825 K957 S492 >

1 Once I thirsted for a fountain,

Something deep that would satisfy,

But the fountain that I'd drink from,

Left me searching and still so dry.

Then one day I found Him,

He satisfied my thirst,

Became in me a deeper source

Whence living waters burst.

Now I drink Him!

Jesus, Jesus is my life now,

Jesus, Jesus is my life;

I'm fully satisfied now,

Jesus, Jesus is my life.

2 After tasting such a fountain,

Longed my heart for a place of springs;

Caught a vision on a mountain,

In Jerusalem's a gathering.

Then one day He found me,

He brought me to the church,

Pleasures here abound fore'er

I've given up my search.

Hallelujah!

Jesus, Jesus is my life now,

Jesus, Jesus is my life;

I'm fully satisfied now,

Jesus, Jesus is my life.

3 Empty wanderer drop the striving -

Isn't worth all the troublin';

Open up your heart believing,

Call "Lord Jesus" and He'll come in!

Then today you'll find Him,

And calling on His name,

You're joined to Him, you're one with Him -

You'll never be the same.

You won't want to!

Jesus, Jesus is my life now,

Jesus, Jesus is my life;

I'm fully satisfied now,

Jesus, Jesus is my life.

< E1329 C- K933 S- >

1 The wedding feast, the peak of man's enjoyment

Was full of pleasure till the wine ran dry.

The human life, like wine, is soon exhausted,

Till Jesus comes, divine life to supply.

When Jesus comes, new wine is made from water,

When Jesus comes, the darkness turns to light.

He touches death - it's turned to life eternal,

Weakness to strength and blindness into sight.

2 One night a moral righteous man, a ruler

To Jesus came, more teaching to pursue;

But teachings ne'er could change the fallen nature,

So Jesus said, "You must be born anew."

3 "I have no husband," sighed the thirsty sinner.

Indeed her many husbands left her dry.

Daily she came to draw the failing water

Till Jesus came, her thirst to satisfy.

4 A man among the multitude lay helpless,

So weak while waiting till the water stirred.

Religion of the law could never heal him;

Then Jesus came and spoke the living word.

5 Within the tomb, four days and nights he lay there,

Death's grip had come; they 'round the grave did weep.

Silent he lay, all bound and wrapped in grave clothes;

Then Jesus came, and woke him from his sleep.

6 And still today, this Jesus is so living,

Able to save from death in any form.

Now open up your heart and call upon Him;

To you He'll come, in spirit you'll be born.

< E1332 C- K- S- >

1 Do you know that you were chosen

Long before the world began;

That by God you were selected

And appointed for His plan?

Something in your inmost being

Tells you this is surely true;

That's why you are in this meeting,

And you feel the way you do.

2 All the sins you've e'er committed,

Everything you've ever done,

All by God has been forgiven,

Taken care of by God's Son.

Struggle not, no; just believe this,

For His word assures it's true;

All you need to do is thank Him

For all that He's done for you.

3 Did you know that all the Bible

Is a will, a testament?

Everything that Christ accomplished

Is for all God's children meant.

As His child you are included,

For His word stands fast and true;

So by faith you now inherit

All that He has done for you.

4 Did you know God has a family?

Yes, He does, in fact, it's us.

That's why we are here enjoying

All He is, so marvelous.

He's our God and we're His people,

Day by day we love Him more;

We're so happy and so thankful,

We just praise Him o'er and o'er.

5 All we know is that we love Him,

We're so glad for what He's done;

We are brought to Him, and we all

Know the joy of being one.

We're so glad that we're included,

What a fellowship have we!

So we'd like to welcome you, friend,

Into God's own family.

< 1500 >

1 Zion is God's habitation.

Sing praises in Zion,

The city of our King.

Zion, the place of His choosing

Where saints are rejoicing.

Here God is their salvation.

Beautiful Zion, in elevation,

The joy of our King,

His satisfaction,

The joy of the whole earth

2 Zion: how good and how pleasant,

The greatest enjoyment!

It's like the precious ointment.

Zion, how good and how pleasant,

In oneness we're dwelling.

The dew, oh how refreshing!

Beautiful Zion, in elevation

How good and how pleasant,

The best enjoyment!

Our oneness is just Him.

3 Zion: our Oneness a Person,

As ointment, He's moving,

As dew He is descending.

Zion: our God is our dwelling,

As ointment, He's strengthening,

As dew, He's so supplying.

Beautiful Zion, in elevation

How good and how pleasant,

Man's satisfaction,

Our dwelling is this One.

4 Zion: in God we're abiding,

Our oneness and living,

The processed God, our all.

Zion, the ultimate blessing,

Of God with man mingling,

The Triune God dispensing.

Beautiful churches, the golden lampstands

God mingling with man

His satisfaction,

The ultimate consummation!

< 1600 >

1 Christ has come to be life-

the processed Divine Trinity

God the Father's the source-

a Fountain emerging to be

God the Son as a gushing-up spring

In the Spirit, a river, for life-imparting.

Oh! How can this miracle be?

The Triune God flowing in me?

Oh! I've got rivers of life

flowing out of my innermost being!

I've got rivers of life

flowing out of my innermost being!

As this life flows through me,

I'm supplied abundantly

His life nullifies sin;

Pow'r springs now from within

To be free-overcoming spontaneously!

2 Yet this life, though it frees,

is not meant for mere victory

God is full of intent,

and never could flow aimlessly.

So this life has a totality,

A consummate issue encompassing me,

Life moves and life grows, life shapes as it flows,

Now I share in this life's destiny,

Oh! I've got rivers of life

flowing out of my innermost being!

I've got rivers of life

flowing out of my innermost being!

We'll abide mutually

God and man revealed to be

Lamb, Wife, Spirit and Bride!

Come, drink! And riverside

Grows the tree, our enjoyment for eternity!

3 So I've no cause to frown,

As one who received this zoe.

I know life runs its course,

and triumphs inevitably.

I'm required just to stay in the flow.

If I do the drinking then God gives the growth!

So there's joy in my heart, and a spring in my step,

And a smile on my face as I sing,

Oh! I've got rivers of life

flowing out of my innermost being!

I've got rivers of life

flowing out of my innermost being!

< 1602 >

1 There's a life that's deeper than our mind,

With experience of man, yet so divine.

It's a life that knows no bounds;

And with glory is crowned;

It's of depth and height and breadth unsearchable.

Now this life is just the Living One

Manifested in the Person of the Son.

As the Spirit, He flows;

In our spirit He grows,

Growing up to be the church that He desires.

O Lord, we're just for Your flowing;

How we need a deeper knowing!

Life is why we're here

And why You've come in us.

Turn us, Lord, turn us now;

Turn us deeply-Life is how

You will get the church,

The home You're longing for.

2 In the church, we all can apprehend

All the riches of this life that is within.

Not just shallowness with strife,

But a deep and peaceful life

Is just waiting to flow out, a living spring.

With the saints it's easy to be bold,

To pursue this life, to gain it, to lay hold.

All the other things we find,

Must be quickly left behind,

So that only life remains for us to see.

3 Deeper, Lord our turn must be to You;

We would move by life in everything we do;

All our concepts refute,

For Your life be absolute-

Grant us grace to turn much deeper day by day.

When we touch our spirit-such a thrill!

This is far beyond emotion, mind, and will-

It's within our hidden part-

Come, make home in all our heart;

Let Your presence flow as rivers deep within.

< 1706 >

1 Let me stand behind You, Lord.

Let me wash Your feet with my tears.

Let me wipe them with my hair.

Let me kiss them and anoint them with the ointment.

I love You!

Jesus, I love You!

May I waste my all and life on You.

Let me pour the ointment pure

On Your head and on Your feet,

On You, most precious One

Because I love You.

2 Let me take a pound of ointment pure

Of great value to anoint Your feet

And wipe them with my hair

That the house be filled with the fragrance

of the ointment.

(Chorus 1)

3 Lord, they said if You were a prophet,

You should know who and what I am.

I'm a sinner that toucheth You.

A woman not worthy to anoint You.

But I love You!

Jesus, I love You!

You forgave me the most

now I love You, Lord, the most.

Let me pour the ointment pure

On Your head and on Your feet,

On You, most precious One,

Because You love me.

4 Let my love from my being wash Your feet

To my glory without wipe them too

Let me kiss them where the nails would pierce.

All my love, Lord, and glory I'll waste on You.

I love You!

Jesus, I love You!

All my glory and love I pour

and waste on You.

Receive my ointment, Lord.

It's all I have, dear Lord.

For You, most precious One,

Because I love You.

< 1710 >

1 I do not know where they have laid Him.

The stone is taken away from the tomb.

Oh! They have taken Him away!

Oh, where is He?

2 Disciples came and saw the empty tomb,

But went away so soon to their own homes.

They're satisfied with just the facts,

But where's my Lord?

Where is He, my Jesus?

Where is He, my Beloved?

Where is He whom my soul doth love?

Jesus, my love, I just want You.

3 My heart is broken from my deepest need.

Don't ask me, angels, why I'm weeping.

Nothing but Jesus fills my inner being.

Oh, where's my love?

4 Someone is standing right behind me-

It's just the gardener; I can barely see.

Sir, if you carried Him away,

Oh! Where is He?

Where is He, my Jesus?

Where is He, my Beloved?

Tell me where you have laid Him

And I'll carry Him away; I'll carry Him away.

5 And then I heard a voice say, "Mary,"

That sweetest voice that penetrated me.

It is the voice of my Beloved,

Jesus, my love.

I have found my Jesus!

I have found my Beloved!

I have found whom my soul doth love,

Jesus, my love, I just love You!

6 But Jesus told me not to touch Him yet;

He must ascend first to the Father,

"And to My Father and your Father,

To My God and your God.

Go and tell My brothers,

I ascend to the Father,

To My Father and your Father,

And My God and your God; go tell My brothers."

< 1722 >

1A Is there someone who's a friend

That I can open to?

A someone who understands

All that I'm going through?

A someone when there's no one

I can always come to-

There is no someone like this One.

1B There is a someone-

Someone you can open to.

There is a someone-

Someone who will take you through.

There is a someone-

When there is no one.

There is a someone, a wonderful One.

2A Is there someone who can care

Through all my hardest times?

A someone always there

Though it may rain or shine?

A someone I can lean on

When the stormy times come-

There is no someone like this One.

2B There is a someone-

Someone in my hardest times.

There is a someone-

Always there though rain or shine.

There is a someone-

When there is no one.

There is a someone, a special One.

3A Is there someone who will take-

Take me just as I am?

A someone who'll not forsake,

One I can trust to the end?

A someone who knows me

Yet he still wants me-

There is no someone like this One.

3B There is a someone-

Who will take you as you are.

There is a someone-

He will reach you near or far.

There is a someone-

He's the most lovely One.

Just take this someone, the loveliest One.

4A Is there someone who can reach

Down to the depths of my being?

A someone who can fix

All of my broken heart strings?

A someone who can love me

When there's no love in me-

There is no someone

Like this One.

4B There is a someone-

Who can touch your inmost being.

There is a someone-

He can make your heart to sing.

There is a someone-

Love is this precious One.

Just love this someone,

The wonderful One.

5 Christ is this someone

Who can touch your inmost being.

Christ is this someone-

He can make your heart to sing.

Christ is this someone.

Christ is this precious One.

Just love this someone, the wonderful One.

< 1723 >

1 Lord, You are Beloved, Fairest of the fair;

Altogether lovely, unrivaled beauty;

It's You! Your presence, I long for and seek;

You're the One in whom my heart delights,

So, I just love to tell You...

Jesus, I love You,

My treasure, You are;

How could I choose anything less than You?

Dear Lord, my inmost heart You've captured and won.

2 Dead I was in sin, Lord, so lost without You;

Helpless, wounded, weary, rebellious, too;

But Lord, You came! You would not let me go;

The blood and water flowed from Your side,

Constraining me to tell You...

3 Thank You Lord, You opened my blind eyes to see;

I was lame, but now I can walk; You healed me!

My leprosy, Lord, You cleansed all away;

My ears were opened to hear Your voice,

And now I follow You 'cause...

4 Sometimes Lord, I'm drawn off by my selfish cares;

And the world it draws me with glitter and glare.

O Lord, You've trapped me. Don't let me go.

Kiss me and woo me, and win my heart,

So, I will always tell You...

5 Keep my heart so soft, Lord, so open to You;

It would be the good ground to bear fruit for You;

Capture my friends, Lord, and build us, I pray;

Your Bride, We'd match You in every way,

And, corporately we tell You:

Jesus, come quickly,

We're waiting for You;

We're the virgins to You,

So single and true;

Forever and ever Your counterpart true.

< 1724 >

1 Mary poured out her love offering.

To many such love was a waste.

Throughout all of the centuries

Such lovers Your sweetness do taste.

Precious lives and heart treasures too,

Positions and golden futures

Have been "wasted" on You Lord,

Your sweetness-a fragrance so sure.

She took opportunity

To love You; Lord, with her best.

Like her, Lord, I too would pour

My love and all that I have.

2 As I love You I set my being,

My spirit, my soul and body,

With my heart, my mind and my strength

Absolutely on Thee.

Lord, I let my entire being

Be occupied by Thee.

As I enter in Your heart,

I sense the fellowship sweet.

Occupied and lost in You,

My Lord, You're my everything.

Fellowship so intimate;

In spirit, Lord, I enjoy Thee.

3 Lord there's none in heav'n nor on earth

That I desire but Thee.

Though my heart and flesh faileth Lord,

Thou ever my portion will be.

All is vanity, all is dung,

I count all other things loss.

Every thing else drains my love,

But You have captured my heart.

Lord, I've seen Thy preciousness,

Thy worth, Thy reality.

Now, my Lord, I must confess,

My heart is only for Thee.

< 1800 >

1 In this godless age,

Lord, You need some Samuels

Burdened with a vision clear of Your economy.

Where's Your ark today?

And the ones who'd care for You,

E'en to put themselves aside to gain Your heart's desire?

Raise up some to meet Your need, some Nazarites,

Prophets, priests, and judges, and men of prayer,

Speaking forth Your word, with Your authority,

A photo of Your heart for Your move.

2 Train us up today,

Full of vision, seeking You,

We'd await Your timing, fully subject to Your will,

Treasuring Your face,

Staying in Your presence, Lord;

E'en the very index of Your eyes would we obey.

Raise up some to meet Your need, some Nazarites,

To bring in Your kingdom on earth today,

Taking You as King that You may return

To usher in the end of the age.

3 When God wants to move,

He must gain an instrument;

Overcomers separated from the current age.

They have joined themselves

Through His word to His desire.

Overcomers constituted with the holy word.

Raise up some to meet Your need, some Nazarites,

Voluntary consecreated ones,

Who through Your word are joined to Your desire;

Your living testimony on the earth.

4 God needs men who pray;

Those who lay the tracks for Him;

God's economy is carried out through men of prayer.

They love not themselves;

But a willing sacrifice.

What they fear-offending God, losing His presence dear.

Make us those who meet Your need, the Nazarites.

Make us those through who You'd close this age;

Who are one with You to bring the kingdom in,

Young people absolute for Your move.

< 1802 >

1 Oh, my Lord, I give myself to You-

There's nothing else to do,

My world is over now!

All the world lies in the evil one,

But I'm the Father's son;

His love has met my need.

Lord, I give myself to You completely;

Lord, I need to sense the flow of life.

Jesus, Jesus, Jesus, Jesus, Jesus,

I love You, I really do!

2 Lord, I long to have You flow in me.

My heart could never be

Content with less than You.

Deep within, my heart cries out to You,

Hungry and thirsty too

For that sweet flow of life.

3 Shining One, in me direct Thy rays,

Shine through all false displays;

Let me not be deceived.

Lord, I know, I need Thy light to shine,

How else can I be Thine?

You must enlighten me.

4 Cleanse me now; don't let one sin remain.

I cannot be the same;

Your life is all I need.

Oh forgive my failure and my sin.

Make me so clean within

So You can flow in me.

5 Oh, the joy! To have that life and peace!

Darkness and death have ceased

In Thy sweet presence, Lord.

Oh, the joy from fellowship so real!

Even the heav'ns, I feel,

Cannot compare with this.

Lord, I give myself to You completely;

How I praise You for the flow of life!

Jesus, Jesus, Jesus, Jesus, Jesus,

I love You, I really do!

< 1803 >

1 Let me love and not be respected;

Let me serve and not be rewarded;

Let me labor and not be remembered;

Let me suffer and not be regarded.

2 'Tis the pouring, not the drinking;

'Tis the breaking, not the keeping-

A life suff'ring to seek other's blessing,

A life loving and true comfort giving.

3 Not expecting pity and concern,

Not accepting solace and applause;

Even lonely, even forgotten,

Even wordless, even forsaken.

4 Tears and blood my price

For the righteous crown shall be;

Losing all, my cost for a faithful pilgrim's life.

'Twas the life, O Lord, that You chose to live

In those days when on earth You walked.

Gladly suff'ring all injuries and loss

So that all might draw near and repose.

5 I cannot see how much farther I shall go;

Still I press on, knowing there is no return.

Let me follow Your pattern so perfect and true,

Bearing ingratitudes without complaint.

In this time of trial, O my Lord, I pray

That You'd wipe all my hidden tears away;

Let me learn, O Lord, You are my reward,

Let me be other's blessing all my days.

< 1904 >

1 God's economy

And His eternal plan,

His heart's desire and intention

Is to be one with man.

Yet man has failed completely

Throughout all history.

But hallelujah! Praise the Lord!

God's life is now in me.

2 Now this life in me is flowing

As the river of water of life,

Washing away all my sins,

My cares, and all my strife.

This life is overcoming

Situations in my day.

Hallelujah! Praise the Lord!

For this is what I pray:

Lord Jesus, I love You!

I give You the preeminence in what I do.

Enjoying You is the overcoming way.

Thank You for Your recovery;

Your Word we will obey.

3 Thank You for our situations

And the environments we are in.

That we'd turn to You in all things,

And turn away from sin.

We'd drop all our anxieties

And put our trust in You.

And experience this living One

Whose life is ever new.

4 Now the church life is so precious

With all the saints so dear.

Enjoying all Your riches,

Our vision is so clear,

That all would prophesy

Of Christ from what they've seen,

According to Your scripture

In First Corinthians fourteen.

< 1905 >

1 Lord, how long, dear Bridegroom,

'Til You come, Lord, how soon?

Don't delay for that coming day, coming day.

Grant me, Lord, to be filled

With You, Lord, ev'ry day.

Dearest Lord, take me all the way.

Come, Lord Jesus.

Please come, dear Bridegroom.

Precious One, come soon, come soon.

Lord, consume me!

Oh Lord, don't let me stray,

Faithful to You all the way.

2 Lord, make home in all my heart,

In my secret, deepest parts,

Hidden, Lord, and reserved for You, for You.

You would be preeminent

In all things and all events,

Possessed by Thee to this extent.

3 In my prayer and deepest plea,

In my spirit always be,

Saturated and soaked with Thee, with Thee.

This would be my life daily,

Every hour expecting Thee,

This I pray, Lord, desperately.

4 The universe, in it we see,

In the sweetest touch of Thee,

You're my choice and my destiny, destiny.

Lord, whate'er the price may be,

Lord, Amen, let it be,

Oh, my love, please come back quickly!

5 In Your love I am constrained.

What's within, I can't contain.

Lord I can't anymore restrain, restrain.

In Your love, I'll pour on Thee,

And the church, Your Bride to be.

This my choice voluntarily.

< 2102 >

1 Life is God the Father

In Christ Jesus as the Spirit

Flowing out and coming into us.

He's not just a teaching,

Or a creed or a dead doctrine,

But the processed Triune God, glorious!

2 Life is not created

As man's body, soul, and spirit-

That's man's life that's weak and temporal.

Life is uncreated.

It's divine and it's eternal.

And this is the life that's indestructible.

3 And this life came in us

In our spirit through the Spirit;

This is where we were made alive!

Now this life is spreading,

Lord, don't stop-just keep invading.

For this, Lord, we must be daily revived.

4 Life needs our maintaining,

Otherwise we're suffocating.

Calling on His name we breathe Him in.

Everywhere we breathe Him,

Makes us fresh and makes us living.

O, this life is full of hope and meaning.

5 In our daily living

It's this life that we are sensing.

Are we in the flesh or in the Lord?

If you're dead and empty

And the troubles you have plenty.

Saints, get out of there and flee back to the Lord!

6 Then you'll sense life flowing.

It's this life that's overcoming

Satan, flesh, and the world, and sin.

What a life we're having.

Lord, Your virtues manifesting.

Thus, we're branches bearing fruit in John 15.

< 2300 >

1 The Son with the Father by the Spirit-

O what a mystery!

The fullness of all the Godhead dwells

In Him bodily.

Wonderful One, Son with the Father,

Wonderful One, Son by the Spirit,

Wonderful Jesus Christ,

Wonderful Triune, Wonderful Triune God!

2 The Son with the Father by the Spirit,

Conceived in a virgin's womb

The issue: a God-man, a wonderful Person,

Jesus, divine and human.

(Repeat the first chorus)

3 This man in perfection chose God as His living;

He lived the life of God.

The sin, world, and Satan could not penetrate Him

Jesus had sinless blood.

Humanity, His blood has cleansed me.

Divinity, my guarantee.

His sinless blood cleansed me.

God's now my guaran-, God's now my guarantee.

4 His flesh without sin joined man's flesh full of sin

And this trapped Satan.

Man's flesh, sin and Satan were hanging upon Him

O what a termination!

Terminating, the old creation,

Nullifying, flesh, sin and Satan.

O what a promised seed!

He crushed the Devil's,

He crushed the Devil's head.

5 And in resurrection, this wonderful Person-

The Spirit He became.

The Spirit right now is the Son with the Father

To be the consummation.

Wonderful One, life-giving Spirit!

Son has become, the consummation.

Son with the Father, He

As Spirit dwells in, as Spirit dwells in me.

6 And in His ascension, this wonderful Person,

This man is on God's throne.

The highest position, to Him it was given,

He's ruling and reigning.

As Lord of lords, and King of kings,

The highest name, to Jesus given.

This man is on God's throne.

Most wonderful, most wonderful Person!

7 And in His enthronement as Head over all things

The processed God is He,

Dispensing Himself as the life-giving Spirit,

Producing His Body.

The Triune God, is not for doctrine;

The Trinity, is for dispensing.

He's now dispensing!

And we're enjoying, and we're enjoying,

And we're enjoying Him.

< 2302 >

1 The Triune God: a mystery-

God is one and He's three.

Oh, Triune God, You're wonderful!

You're wonder-wonderful!

2 The Triune God: a mystery-

God is one and He's three.

Oh, Triune God, You're marvelous!

You're marvel-marvelous!

Brothers: A child is born to us,

Sisters: The mighty God is He,

Brothers: A son is given to us,

Sisters: Eternal Father, He,

Brother: The child the mighty God,

Sisters: His name is wonderful,

Brothers: The Son and Father one.

All: A wonderful Person.

3 The Lord is now the Spirit,

A wondrous mystery!

Christ, the life-giving Spirit,

Has entered into me!

4 The Lord is now the Spirit,

Oh this is glorious!

Christ, the life-giving Spirit,

Has entered into us!

Brothers: The last Adam became

Sisters: The life-giving Spirit!

Brothers: The Lord is the Spirit,

Sisters: The all-inclusive Christ.

Brothers: The last Adam became

Sisters: The life-giving Spirit!

Brothers: Christ is the Lord Spirit.

All: He's now indwelling us!

5 Our Father God, the source;

God, the Son, has reached me.

God as the Spirit's flowing free.

He flowed God into me!

6 Our Father God, the source;

God, the Son, is the course.

God as the Spirit enters me.

'Tis the greatest mystery!

Brothers: The Triune God in me:

Sisters: The greatest mystery!

Brothers: Oh this is glorious!

Sisters: The Triune God in us!

Brothers: The Triune God in me:

Sisters: The greatest mystery!

Brothers: Oh this is marvelous!

All: The Triune God in us!

< 2310 >

1 There are three kinds of life in our existence today:

There is Bios, the physical, and soul-life, Psuche;

Now the third life is God's life and its called Zoe;

And we all have to choose what life we'll live by today.

Oh, it's God in Christ Jesus, through the Spirit today,

Who is flowing within us, flowing through us this way.

We don't care for the Bios; we don't want Psuche;

All we want is God's Zoe life to fill us today.

2 We don't care for the Bios, we don't care for the soul.

We don't care for the cares of life,

world's pleasure and show.

We don't care for the pride of life, the flesh and sin-

We say, "No!" to the soul life,

we'll take God's life within.

3 Do you know what God's life is? Well, just listen to this:

It is God in Christ Jesus through the Spirit-no less!

He is flowing within us, He is flowing through-

Hallelujah! He's moving to make everything new.

4 We have this Life within us, in our spirit today;

To our spirit we turn, O Lord, and take you this way.

We can overcome Bios and the Psuche too;

Hallelujah, the Spirit of the Lord takes us through.

< 2400 >

1 Man's Creator has a purpose

For our being here on earth.

In His image we're created,

To express His rule on earth.

But man fell to Satan's tempting;

Thus God's goal was hid from view.

Still our God will have His Kingdom,

For His Son will see it through.

Jesus Christ will get His Kingdom

Inspite of Satan and his plans.

He's getting something real and solid

By growing in the hearts of man.

It's nothing like religion teaches,

"You have to wait until you die."

For the Kingdom Christ is building,

Is here on earth before our eyes.

2 His Son, Jesus, is our Savior.

Once in human form He came.

Now as the Spirit He can enter

As the breath of life to man.

As a seed within our spirit

Christ takes root and starts to grow,

Spreading in our inmost being

Till His life we come to know.

3 Time is short, oh brothers hear it.

Christ is longing for His Bride.

We can hasten His returning,

Simply by the growth in life.

No more struggling, no more striving,

Simply turn to Christ within.

See the seed begin to blossom,

Growing fully into Him.

Jesus Christ will get His Kingdom

By growing in a normal way.

It's not an instant transformation.

This growth goes on from day to day.

The seed of life is all-inclusive.

It's got everything we'll ever need.

Yes, our God's eternal purpose

Is all within this precious seed.

< 2404 >

1 God has called us for His purpose,

His economy so glorious,

For which He was fully processed;

Consummated now is He.

As the Spirit He indwells us

As our God-allotted portion.

Working out His full salvation,

Making us the same as He is.

Oh, may a clear controlling vision of

The Lord's economy direct my heart

And burn in me until my spirit's wholly set afire.

With spirit strong and active we'll press on

To consummate God's goal-

New Jerusalem! Hallelujah!

2 Jesus lived the God-man pattern,

Set the way for us to follow.

He denied His natural man and

Was obedient unto death.

Once He was the only God-man;

Now we are His duplication.

As the many grains we're blended

As His corporate reproduction.

3 Living out His resurrection

Dying to the flesh and soul-life,

Living by the mingled spirit,

Natural man we will deny.

Now we're living in the Body,

Every day we're overcoming,

Striving for the peak of Zion,

Watching for our Lord's appearing.

4 God and men will have one living

Always in the mingled spirit;

We two are incorporated-

One organic entity!

This, the vision of the ages,

Will control our daily living,

That the Lord may have His body,

Shining as the holy city.

< 2406 >

1 The Bible is a romance

In the most holy sense:

God and His chosen people

In love it so presents.

This Universal Couple

Throughout it is displayed;

God in Christ is the Bridegroom,

His saints, the Bride, portrayed.

2 Through shadows, types, and figures,

God's deepest thought is known;

As typified by Adam,

The Husband, Christ, is shown.

A rib brought forth from Adam

Reveals the source of life

By which God built a woman:

Eve, as the church, His wife.

3 To be His people's Husband,

To take them as His wife:

This is what God desires

To live in marriage life.

Their sacrifice and worship

Alone could not content;

But with them to be married

Was God's foremost intent.

4 This romance is the finest

As seen in the Song of Songs;

For her beloved's kisses

His seeking lover longs.

Love's work in her produces

No person of her own,

But she becomes the City,

Her Person, Christ alone.

5 Christ is our coming Bridegroom;

We are the Church His Bride,

Redeemed, regenerated,

The issue of His side,

In source, in life, in nature

And person fully one,

His counterpart forever,

The New Jerusalem.

< 2700 >

1 Where's the answer?

There must be more for me.

Is this all to life-an empty vanity?

Day by day and year by year go by.

Am I just a man, a man just born to die?

Where's the answer? Oh I'm so empty

And plagued by this vanity.

Deep inside me, my conscience tells me:

I need another destiny.

2 I convince my friends

that everything's alright,

That my life and future

and everything's so bright.

But a sense inside me,

my friends, I can't deny,

Warning deep inside me

that I was living a lie.

3 The world and its glitter left me anxious,

dark and bitter,

Always yearning, my friends

is there something better?

And religion, my friends,

is just a Sunday game-

Dead teachings and doctrines

will leave you just the same.

4 Oh God, where are You?

I need You desperately!

Oh God, who are You?

Why don't You answer me?

The heavens declare You and the earth

shows Your beauty.

But I'm a man. Oh God, I'm so empty!

Lord, have mercy! I'm crying for You!

Please hear! Are You really true?

I'm dark and lonely. You're far,

far from me.

Oh Lord, I need You desperately!

5 One day a friend told me

that Jesus is the Lord.

To my great surprise,

it's written in the Word.

They asked me to believe You.

Your name I once blasphemed.

Dear Lord, You saved me

just by calling on Your name.

Oh, Lord Jesus, dear Son, so glorious,

I'm cleansed and You enter into me.

Oh, Lord Jesus, Your name most precious!

Your Person, dear Lord, I now possess.

< 2706 >

1 Lord, You were in the temple, teaching all the people

Of Yourself as the life.

Meanwhile I was elsewhere, committing

The biggest sin of my life.

The Pharisees they found me, dragged me through the street

There midst the people I sat.

Teacher, we found this woman committing adultery

We found her there in the act.

Great I Am, stooping down.

To the ground so low where I was found.

Where are they who say that you must die today?

Woman, go and sin no more.

2 Down from the mountain You came;

I approached You in shame.

I'm a leper, You see.

Sin and rebellion's in me and I long to be free;

If You're willing, cleanse me.

My destiny is to die; can You help me survive?

Lord, I know that You can.

All others, Lord, run away, when they come see my face,

Helpless hopeless I am.

Stretching out Your hand unto me,

How my heart was warmed when You touched me

With compassion; moved with love I never knew.

By Your touch to me I'm healed.

3 I down to Jericho went,

Met my robbers who stripped me and left me half dead.

The priests and Levites 'cause they also traveled my way,

Couldn't help me a bit.

But, Lord, You came to the earth, despised and slandered,

A Samaritan low.

With divinity there and humanity's care,

Tender and merciful.

Bound my wounds and poured in oil and wine.

Gave Your Spirit to me and life divine.

To the church brought me where care I could receive,

Jesus, You're my Savior true!

< 2708 >

1 I always knew deep down in me

There was a longing to be free,

A kind of hunger deep inside-

To fill it up, I tried and tried.

There were a lot of things I had;

Some things were good,

Some things were bad.

But all those things of mine before

Don't satisfy me anymore.

Now life affords a real reward

Whenever I just call "O Lord!"

The Triune God the Spirit is,

And He can fill mine up with His.

2 Thank You, Lord Jesus, for the wine

That I enjoy as life divine.

I thank You, Lord, for mercy all

That opened me to heed Your call.

O Lord, now make Your home my heart

And fully saturate each part.

O Lord, my words just can't express

The way You've filled my emptiness!

O Lord, I know that You will grow

And from my spirit overflow.

Lord, saturate me through and through-

O Lord Jesus, I love You.

3 I always knew deep down in me

There was a longing to be free.

A kind of hunger deep inside-

But now it can be satisfied...

Christ in my heart-the only way

To spread within me day by day.

Lord Jesus! Lord, I have to say

You're home in me and home to stay!

O Lord, I know now You will grow

And from my spirit overflow!

Now saturate me through and through!

O Lord Jesus, I love You!

O Lord Jesus, I love You!

O Lord Jesus, I love You!

< 2712 >

1 There's a gospel of today

That says believe and you'll be saved, and then

You can go to heaven and see the pearly gates

And walk the golden streets.

Words like these fail to treat

All the vanity that is hidden in me.

2 But the gospel is to me

The Triune God within humanity

As the Spirit reaching me to be in me

The one reality.

Love untold-Gospel Thee

Never getting old-story told eternally.

3 Left the ninety-nine behind-

You searched until the lost sheep You did find.

Laid me on Your shoulders there, You bore me in

Your tender loving care.

Rejoicing-You found me,

Though a small lost sheep-You gave all to come find me.

4 Sweeping in my deepest parts,

You lit a lamp and searched my inward heart,

Sanctifying deep within You shined in me,

Exposed me of my sin.

Repenting-now I see

Lord, You're sprinkling me with the blood You shed for me.

5 Eagerly awaiting me

That I the slightest turn to Thee would make.

Though my life had been a wreck, You ran to me

And fell upon my neck.

Kissing me affectionately,

Killed the calf for me-"Let us eat and be merry."

< 2713 >

1 Do you know what you were made for;

Do you ever wonder why?

What's the purpose for your being;

What's the reason you're alive?

Do you know God wants to your life?

He wants to be your life, He wants to be your life.

You were made with something deep within,

A vessel to contain just Him.

2 Deep within you is your spirit,

Even deeper than your "heart";

Many other things can fill you-

Only Jesus can fill this part.

You have been so empty all these years;

In spite of all you've tried, you're still not satisfied.

Don't you feel a longing deep within

To open up and take Christ in?

3 Doesn't matter how you see things,

For in God's eyes "all have sinned";

Jesus shed His blood to cleanse you

For the purpose of getting in.

He's done everything there is to do,

And He's the Spirit now so He can get in you.

Makes no difference what your past has been;

The living Christ will still come in.

4 Just as you are in your body,

Perfectly contained therein,

God wants you for His container,

All you need to do is let Him in.

Would you open up from deep within

To let the Lord come in and fill you to the brim.

Why not open up from deep within

And call upon the name of Him.